<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Censorship on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title>
    <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/tags/censorship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Censorship on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ooni.torproject.org/tags/censorship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Internet Censorship in Cuba&#39;s ParkNets</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/cuba-internet-censorship-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/cuba-internet-censorship-2017/</guid>
      <description>Image by Arturo Filastò (CC-BY-SA-3.0)  A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI)
View the pdf version of the report here.
Table of contents
 Key Findings
 Introduction
 Background
 Network landscape and internet penetration
 ETECSA
 ParkNets
 Joven Club
 StreetNets
 El Paquete
 Summary
  Measuring Internet Censorship in Cuba
 Methodology
 Collection and analysis of ooniprobe network measurements</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#EgyptCensors: Evidence of recent censorship events in Egypt</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/egypt-censors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/egypt-censors/</guid>
      <description>Country: Egypt
OONI tests: Web Connectivity, HTTP Header Field Manipulation, HTTP Invalid Request Line, HTTP Host, Vanilla Tor.
Probed ISPs: Link Egypt (AS24863), Vodafone Egypt (AS36935), Telecom Egypt (AS8452).
Analysis period: 23rd May 2017 to 17th June 2017.
Censorship method: Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) used to RESET connections.
Starting on May 24th, the Egyptian government ordered ISPs to block at least 21 news websites on the grounds of “supporting terrorism and spreading lies”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Internet Censorship in Indonesia</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/indonesia-internet-censorship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/indonesia-internet-censorship/</guid>
      <description>Image: Block page in Indonesia
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Sinar Project.
Table of contents
 Key Findings
 Introduction
 Background
 Network landscape and internet penetration
 Legal environment
 Freedom of expression
 Press freedom
 Access to information
 Privacy
 Censorship and surveillance
  Reported cases of internet censorship and surveillance
 Examining internet censorship in Indonesia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Internet Censorship in Myanmar</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/myanmar-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 13:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/myanmar-report/</guid>
      <description>A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI), Sinar Project, and the Myanmar ICT for Development Organization (MIDO).
Table of contents
 Key Findings
 Introduction
 Background
 Network landscape and internet penetration
 Legal environment
 Freedom of expression
 Press freedom
 Access to information
 Privacy
 Censorship and surveillance
  Reported cases of internet censorship and surveillance
 Examining internet censorship in Myanmar</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Internet Censorship in Thailand</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/thailand-internet-censorship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/thailand-internet-censorship/</guid>
      <description>Image: Block page in Thailand
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI), Sinar Project, and the Thai Netizen Network.
Table of contents
 Key Findings
 Introduction
 Background
 Network landscape and internet penetration
 Legal environment
 Freedom of expression
 Press freedom
 Access to information
 Privacy
 Censorship and surveillance
  Reported cases of internet censorship and surveillance
 Examining internet censorship in Thailand</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New ooniprobe Mobile App: Measure Internet Censorship &amp; Performance</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ooni-mobile-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ooni-mobile-app/</guid>
      <description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project is thrilled to announce the release of a new mobile app (“ooniprobe - Measure Internet Censorship &amp;amp; Performance”) that can now be installed on Android and iOS for testing Internet censorship and network performance.
     By running the tests included in OONI’s mobile app, you can monitor:
 Blocking of websites; Presence of systems that could be responsible for censorship or surveillance; Speed and performance of your network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kenya: Censorship-free internet?</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/kenya-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/kenya-study/</guid>
      <description>Over the last five months we ran OONI tests in Kenya almost every day to examine whether internet censorship events were occurring in the country. Hundreds of thousands of network measurements were collected and analyzed. 1,357 URLs were tested for censorship, including both international websites and sites that are more relevant to Kenya (e.g. local news outlets). Yet, after five months of intensive testing from four local vantage points in Kenya, we found almost no signs of internet censorship in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Internet Censorship in Malaysia</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/malaysia-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/malaysia-report/</guid>
      <description>Block page in Malaysia
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Sinar Project.
Table of contents
 Key Findings
 Introduction
 Background
 Network landscape and internet penetration
 Legal environment
 Freedom of expression
 Press freedom
 Access to information
 Privacy
 Censorship and surveillance
  Previous cases of internet censorship and surveillance
 Examining internet censorship in Malaysia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New OONI tests examine the blocking of WhatsApp and Facebook Messenger</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/whatsapp-and-facebook-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/whatsapp-and-facebook-tests/</guid>
      <description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project is excited to announce the release of two new software tests which are designed to examine the blocking of WhatsApp and Facebook Messenger. You can now run these tests to monitor the accessibility of these apps across time, and to collect data that can serve as evidence when/if they are blocked.
WhatsApp test Many of our users have asked us to develop a test to examine the accessibility of WhatsApp, especially in light of it being blocked by various governments around the world during elections, protests, and other political events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethiopia: Evidence of social media blocking and internet censorship</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ethiopia-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ethiopia-report/</guid>
      <description>Youth in Addis trying to get Wi-Fi Connection. Credit Addis Fortune Newspaper
Recently we published a post about what appeared to be a possible internet shutdown in Ethiopia during a wave of ongoing protests by ethnic groups. Today, in collaboration with Amnesty International we are releasing a report that includes evidence of recent censorship events during Ethiopia’s political upheaval.
View the pdf version of the report here.
Country: Ethiopia</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>