<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title>
    <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/tags/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ooni.torproject.org/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OONI at the CryptoRave 2017</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ooni-cryptorave-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ooni-cryptorave-2017/</guid>
      <description>CryptoRave is a free, non-commercial and collectively funded 48 hour event featuring talks, workshops and activities related to security, privacy, anonymity, hacking and freedom of expression that attracts more that 2,500 people mainly from South America. The event took place in São Paulo, Brazil on 5th and 6th May 2017.
A number of people attended the OONI presentation and workshop (&amp;ldquo;Listatona&amp;rdquo;) that was co-organized with Coding Rights. During the workshop participants were able to better understand OONI&amp;rsquo;s testing methodology, and how ooniprobe performs network measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OONI at the Internet Freedom Festival &amp; RightsCon 2017</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ooni-iff-rightscon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ooni-iff-rightscon/</guid>
      <description>Over the last month the OONI team joined the internet freedom community at the following events:
 Vietnam Cyber Dialogue (VCD)
 Internet Freedom Festival (IFF)
 Iran Cyber Dialogue (ICD)
 RightsCon 2017
 International Journalism Festival (IJF)
  These events provided us with the opportunity to engage with community members, create new friendships, learn about new projects, and to share skills and knowledge. We also had the opportunity to facilitate sessions that allowed us to collect feedback for the improvement of our software and research methodologies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>