<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dpi on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title>
    <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/tags/dpi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dpi on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ooni.torproject.org/tags/dpi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethiopia: Evidence of social media blocking and internet censorship</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ethiopia-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ethiopia-report/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ethiopia-report/et-05.png&#34; alt=&#34;Ethiopia image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Youth in Addis trying to get Wi-Fi Connection. Credit Addis Fortune Newspaper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently we published a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ethiopia-internet-shutdown-amidst-recent-protests/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; about what appeared to be a possible internet
shutdown in Ethiopia during a wave of ongoing protests by ethnic groups. Today,
in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amnesty.org/&#34;&gt;Amnesty International&lt;/a&gt; we are releasing a report that
includes evidence of recent censorship events during Ethiopia’s political
upheaval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View the &lt;strong&gt;pdf&lt;/strong&gt; version of the report &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/documents/Ethiopia-Offline-evidence-of.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Country:&lt;/strong&gt; Ethiopia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Probed ISP:&lt;/strong&gt; EthioNet-AS, ET ( AS24757 )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Censorship method:&lt;/strong&gt; Deep Packet Inspection (DPI), HTTP response failures, DNS
tampering, TCP injections&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OONI tests:&lt;/strong&gt; Web Connectivity, Vanilla Tor, WhatsApp test, HTTP invalid request
line, HTTP header field manipulation, HTTP Host&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measurement period:&lt;/strong&gt; 2016-06-15 - 2016-10-07&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#key-findings&#34;&gt;Key Findings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#methodology&#34;&gt;Methodology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#part-1-evidence-of-internet-censorship&#34;&gt;Part 1: Evidence of internet censorship&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#background-sustained-protests&#34;&gt;Background: Sustained protests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#internet-censorship-during-protests&#34;&gt;Internet censorship during protests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#state-of-emergency&#34;&gt;State of emergency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#findings-of-the-network-measurement-study&#34;&gt;Findings of the network measurement study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#whatsapp-blocked&#34;&gt;WhatsApp blocked&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#deep-packet-inspection-detected&#34;&gt;Deep Packet Inspection detected&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#websites-blocked&#34;&gt;Websites blocked&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#media-outlets&#34;&gt;Media outlets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#political-opposition-and-armed-groups&#34;&gt;Political opposition and armed groups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#lgbti-websites&#34;&gt;LGBTI websites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#human-rights-websites&#34;&gt;Human rights websites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#censorship-circumvention-tool-websites&#34;&gt;Censorship circumvention tool websites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#circumventing-censorship&#34;&gt;Circumventing censorship&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#internet-shutdown&#34;&gt;Internet shutdown?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#international-human-rights-law&#34;&gt;International Human Rights Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#recommendations&#34;&gt;Recommendations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#part-2-methodology&#34;&gt;Part 2: Methodology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#test-lists&#34;&gt;Test lists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ooni-network-measurements&#34;&gt;OONI network measurements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#web-connectivity&#34;&gt;Web Connectivity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#http-invalid-request-line&#34;&gt;HTTP invalid request line&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#http-header-field-manipulation&#34;&gt;HTTP header field manipulation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#http-host&#34;&gt;HTTP Host&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#data-analysis&#34;&gt;Data analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#acknowledgement-of-limitations&#34;&gt;Acknowledgement of limitations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;key-findings:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Key Findings&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/country/ET&#34;&gt;OONI data&lt;/a&gt; published in this report reveals the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WhatsApp&lt;/strong&gt; was found to be &lt;strong&gt;blocked&lt;/strong&gt; inside Ethiopia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) technology&lt;/strong&gt; was detected. DPI is technology that
can be bought and deployed on any network, enabling monitoring and filtering of
Internet traffic. This can be useful as part of network management, but it can
also be used for mass surveillance and internet censorship. This finding
suggests that Ethiopia has DPI technology in its possession and is deploying it
for censorship purposes inside the country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Out of &lt;strong&gt;1,403&lt;/strong&gt; different types of URLs that were tested, the types of sites that
consistently presented network anomalies and which were more likely to be
blocked include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;News outlets and online forums&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Armed groups and political opposition websites&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;LGBTI websites&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Websites advocating free expression&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Circumvention tool websites (including Tor and Psiphon)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above types of websites mostly presented HTTP response failures, indicating
that they were likely blocked by DPI equipment. Overall, 16 different Ethiopian
news outlets presented signs of censorship, many of which showed evidence of
being blocked prior to the state of emergency declaration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the course of this investigation, OONI also sought to verify reports from
Ethiopia of a mobile internet shutdown in October 2016. OONI software tests are
designed to examine the blocking of sites and services, but do not monitor
internet shutdowns as a whole. As such, the organisation referred to third party
data such as Network Diagnostic Test (NDT) measurements and Google transparency
reports, in an attempt to examine whether the reported internet shutdown could
be confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The below graph from Google’s transparency reports illustrates the total volume
of Google Search traffic originating from Ethiopia between July and November
2016. As published in an earlier report by OONI and Strathmore University Centre
for Intellectual Property and Information Technology Law (CIPIT), the data shows
a complete drop in Internet traffic in early August, suggesting that a full
Internet block took place following the call by political activists for region-
wide protests on the weekend of 5 and 6 August. While the data shows a decrease
in internet traffic during October, there is no strong indication of an internet
shutdown along the lines of that observed in early August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ethiopia-report/et-01.png&#34; alt=&#34;Google data&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google Transparency Report, Ethiopia, Google Search traffic between July and November 2016.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The findings suggest that if an internet shutdown did occur in October, it only
occurred in some networks in certain locations, rather than nationwide.
Furthermore, the decrease in overall traffic during October could be attributed
to temporary mobile internet shutdowns in certain local networks, or to an
increase of censorship events (for example, targeted blocking of certain
websites and instant messaging services). An examination of data from the
circumvention software Tor, shows a spike in traffic from Ethiopia in October,
suggesting that more people were seeking ways around censorship. This indicates
that there might have been an increase in censorship events following the
declaration of Ethiopia’s state of emergency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI was unable to confirm the reported mobile internet shutdown in October,
partly due to limitations in NDT measurements and Google transparency reports.
We therefore strongly encourage Internet companies including Facebook,
Microsoft, Yahoo and Twitter, to increase transparency around internet traffic
data so that internet shutdowns and other censorship events can be investigated
and verified quickly, and more accurately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of these acts of censorship took place before a state of emergency was
announced, raising questions about whether these measures had any basis in
Ethiopian law, as required by international human rights law. While the State of
Emergency may have subsequently provided a legal framework under Ethiopian law
for some of these measures, the State of Emergency itself is so broadly drafted
that it violates Ethiopia&amp;rsquo;s international legal obligations and permits
violations of numerous human rights. Amnesty International and OONI are
concerned that unnecessary and disproportionate censorship of the internet will
not only continue during the state of emergency, but become institutionalized
and entrenched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI has unearthed evidence of systematic interference with access to numerous
websites belonging to independent news organizations and political opposition
groups, as well as sites supporting freedom of expression and LGBTI rights. Such
widespread interference and blocking is a violation of people’s freedom of
expression, and specifically, people’s right to hold opinions without
interference, and their right to receive and impart information of all kinds as
guaranteed under article 19 (1) and (2) of the International Covenant on Civil
and Political Rights (ICCPR), which Ethiopia has ratified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethiopia’s position on the use of social media indicates that the authorities
are invoking their obligations to restrict freedom of expression where such
freedom is abused, as articulated in article 19 (3) of the ICCPR. However, the
acts of censorship uncovered by OONI’s study are inconsistent with the
requirements laid out in the ICCPR to restrict these rights. Specifically, that
any restrictions will be provided by law and are necessary to respect the rights
or reputations of others; or for the protection of national security or of
public order, public health or morals. Any restrictions to freedom of expression
is subject to a three part test: that they are legal; necessary and
proportional. The acts of censorship evidenced in OONI’s study fail to meet the
test. They are arbitrary, being carried out in the absence of clear and precise
law in the country which governs access to internet and social media,
restrictions/blockade of websites and social media, and clear legal procedures
governing restrictions, including administrative and judicial procedures to
challenge such restrictions and blockades. The acts of censorship also fail the
test of proportionality. The censorship acts uncovered by OONI were not
restricted to specific content; rather the censorship was happening at a large
scale, with dozens of websites and popular communications platforms like
WhatsApp affected over the space of several months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decision to restrict people’s ability to receive and impart information by
censoring internet access during the protests, only served to sweep the
underlying issues fuelling the protests under the carpet. To fully address the
situation that led up to the state of emergency, the government must genuinely
commit to addressing the underlying human rights violations that triggered the
protests in the first place; and respect its human rights obligations. This
includes refraining from blocking access to the internet and ensuring that all
its people can enjoy their right to express their opinions; even those who
criticise government policy and action; and guarantee their right to expression
and association online and offline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media companies should make available publicly verifiable data on network
traffic originating from countries around the world, to ensure transparency when
social media restrictions or heavy network disruptions occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;executive-summary:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waves of protests against the government have taken place across various parts
of Ethiopia since November 2015. These protests have consistently been quashed
by Ethiopian security forces using excessive, sometimes lethal, force, which led
to scores of injuries and deaths. The crackdown on protests was accompanied by
increasingly severe restrictions on access to information and communications in
large parts of the country by cutting off internet access, slowing down
connections and blocking social media websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The protests began on 12 November 2015 in Ginchi, a town in West Shewa Zone of
Oromia Region, against the Addis Ababa Masterplan, a government plan to extend
the capital Addis Ababa’s administrative control into parts of the Oromia. The
protests continued even after the Government announced in January that they had
cancelled the plans, and later expanded into the Amhara region with demands for
an end to arbitrary arrests and ethnic marginalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amnesty International’s research since the protests began revealed that security
forces responded with excessive and lethal force in their efforts to quell the
protests. Amnesty International interviewed at least fifty victims and witnesses
of human rights abuses during the protests, twenty human rights monitors,
activists and legal practitioners within Ethiopia, and also reviewed relevant
other primary and secondary information on the protests and the government
response. Based on this research, the organisation estimates that at least 800
people have been killed since the protests began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tensions in Oromia escalated at the beginning of October, following a stampede
during a religious festival which killed at least 55 people. Fresh protests,
some of which turned violent, broke out amidst contestations over who was
responsible for the stampede. Oromo activists blamed security forces for firing
live ammunition and tear gas into the crowds, while the government blamed anti-
peace protestors. The government of Ethiopia declared a state of emergency on 8
October. The state of emergency imposes broad restrictions on a range of human
rights, some of which are non-derogable rights, meaning that under international
law, they may never be restricted, even during a state of emergency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to using security forces to quash protests, the Ethiopian
authorities have restricted access to internet services during this time.
Amnesty International´s contacts inside Ethiopia reported that social media and
messaging mobile applications such as Facebook, WhatsApp and Twitter, have been
largely inaccessible since early March 2016, especially in the Oromia region
where the bulk of the protests were taking place. Internet services were also
completely blocked in Amhara, Addis Ababa and Oromia Regions following a call by
political activists for region-wide protests on the weekend of 6 and 7 August
2016. The protests went ahead during these two days. The government security
forces used excessive force against the protesters in Addis Ababa, Amhara and
Oromia Regions resulting in the death of at least 100 people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internet disruptions started again on 5 October 2016 after protesters in some
parts of Oromia targeted businesses, investments, government buildings and
security forces in the wake of the stampede during the Irrecha thanksgiving
festival in Oromo, which killed at least 55 people. Amnesty International´s
contacts have since reported that internet connections were very slow and social
media services have been inaccessible through browsers. Access to the mobile
internet connection in Addis Ababa improved for a couple of days in early
December, on 4th and 5th, before becoming inaccessible once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ethiopian government considers that social media has empowered populists and
extremists to exploit people’s genuine concerns and to spread bigotry and hate.
This position was made clear in the Prime Minister’s speech to the UN General
Assembly in September. Indeed, a number of political and other activists have
been arrested and charged under the Anti-Terrorism Proclamation on the basis of
their activities on social media platforms. Yonatan Tesfaye, formerly of the
Blue Party, was arrested and charged with terrorism crimes because of his
facebook posts criticizing government policy and action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the midst of these protests, and in response to the numerous reports from
Ethiopia that access to the internet was being blocked, the Open Observatory of
Network Interference (OONI) performed a study of internet censorship. OONI is a
free software project whose goal is to increase transparency about internet
censorship and traffic manipulation around the world. OONI undertook the study
in order to assess whether, and to what extent the censorship being reported
actually occurred during the protests. OONI sought evidence of websites and
instant messaging apps were being blocked; systems causing censorship and
traffic manipulation; and inaccessibility of censorship circumvention tools such
as Tor and Psiphon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI’s software tests were run from a computer inside the country (running on
the EthioNet network, the Ethiopia telecom monopoly). Tests were run on a total
of 1,403 different URLs, including both Ethiopian and global websites, in order
to determine website blocking. Additional OONI tests were run to examine whether
systems that could be responsible for censorship, surveillance, and traffic
manipulation were present in the tested network. OONI then processed and
analysed the network data collected based on a set of criteria for detecting
internet censorship and traffic manipulation. The testing period started on 15
June 2016 and concluded on 7 October 2016, immediately prior to the announcement
of the state of emergency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This report, presents the findings of the OONI study, and Amnesty
International’s human rights analysis of these findings. This report also
provides details of the technical methodology OONI used to verify the blockade
on Whatsapp and the restrictions on websites with political and other content in
a second, distinct section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;methodology:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Methodology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This report has two distinct sections. Part 1 of the report presents Amnesty
International and OONI´s joint findings related to Internet censorship during
the protests that have rocked Ethiopia since November 2015. Part 2 of the report
provides a detailed overview of OONI´s technical study, including the full range
of tests performed on Ethiopia´s network and acknowledged limitations in the
methodology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amnesty International has been documenting the protests since they began, as
well as the state response to the same. Primarily, Amnesty International has
conducted this research remotely, relying on victim and eyewitness testimony,
which has been taken through at least 50 phone and email interviews. Amnesty
International researchers have also used a variety of other primary and
secondary information to corroborate and verify witness accounts of specific
incidents including at least 20 phone and email interviews with human rights
monitors in Ethiopia; members of Ethiopian political opposition parties
including spokespersons; media reports; reports and images posted on social
media; and Ethiopian government communications. Amnesty International has tried
unsuccessfully to engage with the Ethiopian authorities on the protests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The information gathered by Amnesty International and used in this report, is to
provide the background, and context within which the OONI network measurement
study was carried out. It is not intended to provide comprehensive information
on the human rights violations that have occurred in the context of the
protests. For more information and analysis on the protests, please visit
Amnesty International’s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) is a free software project
that aims to increase transparency about internet censorship and traffic
manipulation around the world. OONI undertook a network measurement study, which
run from 15 June to 7 October 2016. OONI used multiple free and open source
software tests it had designed to examine the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blocking of websites and instant messaging apps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detection of systems responsible for censorship and traffic manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reachability of circumvention tools (such as Tor, Psiphon, and Lantern) and
sensitive domains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that the technical findings are subject to limitations,
and do not necessarily reflect a comprehensive view of internet censorship in
Ethiopia. The methodology, and its limitations, are discussed in detail in part
2 of the report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;part-1-evidence-of-internet-censorship:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Part 1: Evidence of internet censorship&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-sustained-protests:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Background: Sustained protests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the lack of confirmed data about casualties, an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amnesty.org/en/documents/afr25/5003/2016/en/&#34;&gt;estimated 800 people&lt;/a&gt;
have been killed due to excessive or otherwise unlawful use of force by the
security forces - some of which may amount to extrajudicial executions - since
the beginning of the protests in November 2015. The United Nations High
Commissioner for Human Rights has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/aug/11/un-ethiopia-observers-reports-dozens-dead-protests&#34;&gt;described&lt;/a&gt; the situation as “extremely
alarming” and urged Ethiopia to allow international human rights observers into
the country. The Ethiopian government, however, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aljazeera.com/news/2016/08/ethiopia-observers-needed-protests-rage-160811105846673.html&#34;&gt;rejected&lt;/a&gt; this UN request,
arguing that it alone is responsible for the security of its citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been almost continuous protests in parts of Ethiopia since November
2015. The protests in Oromia region were initially triggered by plans to extend
the capital, Addis Ababa, into Oromia, but continued even after the Addis Ababa
Masterplan was scrapped in January, evolving into demands for accountability for
human rights violations, ethnic equality and the release of political prisoners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In August 2016, people in the Amhara Region joined protests against arbitrary
detention of members of the Wolkait Amhara Identity and Self-determination
Committee. The Ethiopian security forces have &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amnesty.org/en/documents/afr25/5003/2016/en/&#34;&gt;consistently used excessive, including lethal, force&lt;/a&gt; to disperse the protesters. Over 600 protesters in
Oromia and 200 in Amhara have been killed as a result. Hundreds of political
activists, human rights defenders, journalists and protesters have been
arrested. Since the start of the protests in November last year, the police have
charged at least 200 people, including journalists, bloggers and opposition
political party leaders, under the Anti-Terrorism Proclamation. Their trials
were ongoing as of November 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tensions in Oromia escalated again following a stampede during the Irrecha
religious festival on 2 October that resulted in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aljazeera.com/news/2016/10/ethiopia-unrest-continues-day-deadly-stampede-161003130002688.html&#34;&gt;death of at least 52 people&lt;/a&gt;. The cause of the stampede, and the number of casualties, is contested.
The government has &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aljazeera.com/news/2016/10/ethiopia-protests-resurge-stampede-deaths-161006044616074.html&#34;&gt;claimed&lt;/a&gt; that protesters triggered the stampede, while Oromo
activists claim that the government security forces caused the stampede when
they fired tear gas canisters and shot live ammunition into the crowds.
Following the stampede, fresh protests broke out in Oromia with a number of them
turning violent. Protesters &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aljazeera.com/news/2016/09/firms-attacked-ethiopia-protests-continue-160902064459286.html&#34;&gt;attacked&lt;/a&gt; foreign and local businesses, farms, and
vehicles, especially those near Addis Ababa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response to the wave of protests, the government of Ethiopia severely
restricted internet access and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amnesty.org/en/documents/afr25/5003/2016/en/&#34;&gt;declared a state of emergency&lt;/a&gt; on 8 October 2016.
The state of emergency &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hrw.org/news/2016/10/30/legal-analysis-ethiopias-state-emergency&#34;&gt;imposes broad restrictions&lt;/a&gt; on a variety of human rights,
some of which are non-derogable rights, meaning that under international law,
they may never be restricted, even during a state of emergency. The arrest and
detention of protesters and politically-outspoken individuals critical of
government action continues, including Zone-9 bloggers &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.defenddefenders.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/ACHPR-report-October-2016.pdf&#34;&gt;Natnael Feleke&lt;/a&gt; on 4
October and &lt;a href=&#34;https://advox.globalvoices.org/2016/11/15/ethiopian-authorities-arrest-zone9-blogger-befeqadu-hailu-citing-state-of-emergency/&#34;&gt;Befeqadu Hailu&lt;/a&gt; on 11 November. The government forces also arrested
Anania Sorri and Daniel Shibeshi (members of former Unity Party) and Elias Gebru
(journalist) on 18 November 2016. The three of them had &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/2gwZTfQ&#34;&gt;posted their picture&lt;/a&gt;
showing the protest sign on 28 October 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Government of Ethiopia continues to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-37607751&#34;&gt;accuse&lt;/a&gt; the Ethiopian diaspora based
opposition political parties, Egypt and Eritrea for supporting and fostering the
protests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;internet-censorship-during-protests:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Internet censorship during protests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testimonies gathered by Amnesty International from different parts of the Oromia
region indicate that social media mobile applications such as Facebook,
WhatsApp, and Twitter, were largely inaccessible since early March 2016,
especially in the Oromia region, where residents were waging protests against
the government since November 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;you can&amp;rsquo;t use social media apps across Oromia for the last 6 weeks[since Mid-
March]. I personally checked it in Ambo town in West Shawa Zone and In
Batu/Ziway in East Shawa Zone and all [along] the road to there. The blackout is
directed to the apps [both Android and IOS] but, the whole Internet is too slow
and not working at all in some parts of the Region.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the witnesses Amnesty International spoke to in the Oromia region and
neighbouring cities, such as Hawassa, said that not only are the popular social
media applications largely inaccessible, but that the internet has also been
rendered unusually slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“All the way to Hawassa from Addis Ababa, I was not able to access skype and
facebook. Even after I reached Hawassa, the connection was too slow that I was
not able to have decent skype conversation during the night.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Government blocked access to Facebook, Instagram, Twitter and Viber during
the National University Exam week “&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-36763572&#34;&gt;to prevent students being distracted from studying during the exam period and to prevent the spread of false rumours&lt;/a&gt;”.
Accordingly, those social media outlets were reportedly inaccessible throughout
the country from 9-14 July 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internet services were also &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-36940906&#34;&gt;reportedly&lt;/a&gt; not available in Amhara, Addis Ababa and
Oromia Regions following the call for region-wide protests on the weekend of 6
and 7 August 2016. During these two days, the government used excessive,
including lethal force against protesters in Addis Ababa, Amhara and Oromia
Regions resulting in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2016/08/ethiopia-dozens-killed-as-police-use-excessive-force-against-peaceful-protesters/&#34;&gt;death of at least 100 people&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media and mobile internet was also &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.africanews.com/2016/10/05/ethiopia-partially-lifts-internet-shutdown-amid-protest-tension/&#34;&gt;reportedly&lt;/a&gt; unavailable from 5 October
2016 after protests in some parts of Oromia targeted businesses, investments,
government buildings and security forces, during a proclaimed “week of rage”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the government employed legislative and judicial tools to
discourage the use of internet and social media for expression of dissenting
views. The government passed a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ebc.et/web/ennews/-/parliament-approves-cyber-crime-proclamation&#34;&gt;new computer crimes law&lt;/a&gt; in June 2016 that among
other things penalises distribution of “violent messages, audio, or video”. The
law also authorizes the Ministry of Justice to issue a warrant for interception
or surveillance, and people suspected of computer crimes can be held in pre-
trial detention for up to four months. The law has had a chilling effect on the
flow of information about human rights violations perpetrated by the security
forces against protesters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ethiopian government has relied on the Anti-terrorism Proclamation (ATP) to
charge and convict people who have criticized government policy and action on
social media platforms. The Ethiopian Government arrested and charged Yonatan
Tesfaye, a political activist and former public relation head of the Blue Party,
with terrorism crimes under the ATP because of the content of his posts on
Facebook. The Zone-9 bloggers and Zelalem Workalemahu et el were also tried
because of their online activities. The Prosecutor charged the Zone-9 bloggers
with terrorism crimes for using encrypted software to ensure the security of
their communications. In Zelalem Workalemahu et al the Court &lt;a href=&#34;https://freedomhouse.org/report/freedom-net/2016/ethiopia&#34;&gt;convicted&lt;/a&gt; the first
defendant, Zelalem Workalemahu, for provision of training on online encryption
methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ethiopian Prime Minister´s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.un.org/apps/news/story.asp?NewsID=55022#.WBrYUC197IV&#34;&gt;speech&lt;/a&gt; at the United Nations General Assembly in
September 2016, gave an indication of the government’s views around the use of
social media: &lt;em&gt;“social media has certainly empowered populists and other
extremists to exploit people&amp;rsquo;s genuine concerns and spread their message of hate
and bigotry without any inhibition.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is unlikely that social media played a crucial role in mobilizing the
protests, given that internet penetration in the country remains very low at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://freedomhouse.org/report/freedom-net/2015/ethiopia&#34;&gt;2.9%&lt;/a&gt;. However, it has aided protesters in uncovering acts of violence committed
by the security forces. Previous protests in the country, such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amnesty.org/en/documents/afr25/006/2014/en/&#34;&gt;April 2014 Oromo Protest&lt;/a&gt; against the Addis Ababa Master Plan and the Muslim protest against
government interference in religious affairs since 2012 did not attract
international media coverage. However, the current protests in Oromia and Amhara
Regional States have gained a relatively greater media coverage due to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/oromoprotests?lang=en&#34;&gt;use of social media&lt;/a&gt;, even in very small towns, where witnesses have reported on
events and the violence committed by the security forces, sometimes in real-
time. For instance, the footage from the Irrecha tragedy on 2 October 2016 was
available on social media platforms almost in real time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google traffic data depicts an acute decline of traffic on 6 and 7 August 2016,
when there was a call by political activists for protests in Addis Ababa,
Oromia, and Amhara. The internet shutdown tallied with the heavy-handed response
of the security forces to the protests on these dates. Since social media was
not accessible on those days in Amhara, Oromia and Addis Ababa there were very
little reports at the time of the violence by the security forces. It was only
after 8 August 2016 that pictures, footage, and reports of excessive force by
security forces started to emerge on social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;state-of-emergency:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;State of emergency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethiopia is currently in a state of emergency for six months, as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/oct/10/ethiopia-declares-state-of-emergency-as-deadly-protests-continue&#34;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; by
the government on 8 October 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Government has &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fanabc.com/english/index.php/news/item/7370-inquiry-board-says-11,-607-people-arrested-under-emergency-law&#34;&gt;arrested more than 11,000 people&lt;/a&gt; for “violence and property
damage&amp;rdquo;. Amongst &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amnesty.org/en/documents/afr25/4984/2016/en/&#34;&gt;those in detention&lt;/a&gt; are bloggers, journalists, and members of the
political opposition, for publicly criticizing the government, the state of
emergency declaration or for posting the protest sign on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the state of emergency, all unauthorized protests and assemblies are
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-37679165&#34;&gt;banned&lt;/a&gt;. Sharing information about protests through social media platforms, such
as Facebook and Twitter, is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/africa/ethiopia-state-of-emergency-facebook-social-media-internet-blackout-rules-oromo-protests-latest-a7366956.html&#34;&gt;prohibited&lt;/a&gt;, while two TV stations run for the
Ethiopian diaspora, ESAT and the Oromia Media Network, are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ictpolicy.org/blog/ethiopian-state-of-emergency-details-released-english-translation/&#34;&gt;banned&lt;/a&gt; due to their
coverage of the protests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The state of emergency declaration imposes broad derogations on a variety of
human rights, some of which &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amnesty.org/en/documents/afr25/5003/2016/en/&#34;&gt;affect non-derogable rights&lt;/a&gt; according to Article 4
(3) of the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights (ICCPR). The
state of emergency declaration established a Command Post chaired by the Prime
Minister with the power to determine the specific restrictions, measures, and
geographic scope in the implementation of the state of emergency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Command Post has broad powers, including to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prohibit any overt or covert incitement for violence or ethnic conflict, in
whatever form of expression;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stop or suspend any media;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prohibit any assembly, association and demonstration;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Arrest anyone suspected of using violence in the areas the Command Post
identifies. Those arrested will be educated and released and, if necessary, they
will be punished under relevant law;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Search and seize any person or place and confiscate where necessary;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Impose curfew;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Block any road or public place or evacuate and move people from certain places;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evacuate people vulnerable to threats and keep them in safe places for a limited
period of time;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use proportionate force necessary for the implementation of the state of
emergency;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accordingly, the Command Post issued a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fanabc.com/index.php/component/k2/item/19458&#34;&gt;Directive&lt;/a&gt; on 15th October, which further
enumerated the acts prohibited, the state of emergency measures, and the
obligations to keep and communicate records. The directive conferred the
security forces with the powers to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Arrest without warrant;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detain those arrested at places designated by the Command Post until the end of
the state of emergency;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Search without warrant anytime and anywhere;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monitor and control any messages through radio, TV, articles, pictures,
photographs, theatre and movies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources told Amnesty International that the security forces have demolished a
number of private satellite frequency receivers in the Oromia and Amhara
regions, barring access to the broadcasts of the Ethiopian Satellite Television
and Oromia Media Network. Several witnesses have also told Amnesty International
that they were unable to access mobile internet service in Oromia, Addis Ababa,
and Amhara Regional States resulting in information blackout on the human rights
situation in those regions. However, it is not clear why the mobile internet was
unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;findings-of-the-network-measurement-study:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Findings of the network measurement study&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI)&lt;/a&gt; performed a study of
internet censorship in Ethiopia in the midst of tensions and ongoing public
protests in Oromia region, and prior to the announcement of the country’s state
of emergency. The aim of this study was to understand whether and to what extent
the censorship being reported actually occurred during the protests, and to
provide evidence in relation to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blocking of websites and instant messaging apps&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detection of systems responsible for censorship and traffic manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reachability of common circumvention tools used to get around censorship (such
as Tor and Psiphon).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-probe&#34;&gt;software tests&lt;/a&gt; were run from a computer inside
the country (running on the EthioNet network, the Ethiopia telecom monopoly).
Tests were run on a total of 1,403 different URLs, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/blob/master/lists/et.csv&#34;&gt;Ethiopian websites&lt;/a&gt;
as well as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/blob/master/lists/global.csv&#34;&gt;URLs&lt;/a&gt; that are commonly accessed around the world. All URLs were
tested for blocking. Other OONI tests were run to examine whether systems that
could be responsible for censorship, surveillance, and traffic manipulation were
present in the tested network. OONI processed and analysed the network
measurement data collected from these tests based on a set of heuristics for
detecting internet censorship and traffic manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The testing period started on 15 June 2016 and concluded on 7 October,
immediately prior to the announcement of the state of emergency. The testing was
also limited due to security risks to people involved in conducting the testing.
Even though Ethio Telecom is government owned and Ethiopia’s main ISP, it is
likely that censorship was implemented differently across locations, and that
the findings of this study do not necessarily represent nationwide censorship. A
detailed explanation of the methodology, including limitations, can be found in
part 2 of this report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;whatsapp-blocked:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;WhatsApp blocked&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;OONI&lt;/a&gt; has designed a new software &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-spec/blob/master/test-specs/ts-018-whatsapp.md&#34;&gt;test&lt;/a&gt; for examining the reachability of
WhatsApp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This test attempts to perform an HTTP GET request, TCP connection and DNS lookup
to WhatsApp’s endpoints, registration service and web version over the vantage
point of the user. Based on this methodology, WhatsApp’s app is likely blocked
if TCP/IP connections to its endpoints and/or registration service fail, if the
DNS lookup illustrates that different IP addresses have been allocated to its
endpoints, and/or if HTTP requests do not send back a response to OONI’s
servers. Similarly, WhatsApp’s website is likely blocked if any of the above
apply to web.whatsapp.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An anonymous researcher ran this test in October from a local vantage point in
Ethiopia (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ethionet.et/&#34;&gt;Ethio Telecom&lt;/a&gt;) in an attempt to examine whether and how WhatsApp was
censored. The collected measurement &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20160912T112212Z_AS24757_q79IWOW8fmyKllSOWewx6URNKqoFp5aAyHmy3UjZsTTl5fPbrV&#34;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt; illustrates that while both HTTP and
HTTPS requests to web.whatsapp.com succeeded, HTTPS requests to WhatsApp’s
registration service failed, and so did TCP connections to WhatsApp’s endpoints.
This indicates that WhatsApp’s website was accessible, but its &lt;em&gt;app&lt;/em&gt; was blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;web.whatsapp.com&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;WhatsApp endpoints&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;WhatsApp registration service&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HTTP request&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Success&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HTTPS request&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Success&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Failed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TCP connection&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Failed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DNS lookup&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Consistent&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Consistent&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Consistent&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Result&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Accessible&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Blocked&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Blocked&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;deep-packet-inspection-detected:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Deep Packet Inspection detected&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An Ethiopian news website (ecadforum.com) was &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20160912T111210Z_AS24757_4un8r03S6zIMpfJ7IuJqxxFGRaSfXlLOgUxshT9Ja5ep7hpQkS?input=ecadforum.com&#34;&gt;found&lt;/a&gt; to be blocked last month
based on the use of Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) technology. DPI enables its
users to analyze data packets and protocols. This can be useful as part of
network management, but it can also be used for data mining and internet
censorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blocking of ecadforum.com by DPI equipment was uncovered through &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-spec/blob/master/test-specs/ts-004-http-host.md&#34;&gt;OONI’s HTTP host test&lt;/a&gt; which was run from a local vantage point in Ethiopia. This test
attempts to examine whether the domain names of websites are blocked, and to
detect the presence of “middle boxes” (software that could potentially be used
for censorship and/or traffic manipulation) in tested networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of our testing, we performed HTTP requests towards one of OONI’s control
servers. This server is responsive for just sending back any data it receives.
In absence of censorship equipment, we would be able to view ooniprobe’s
request. But when we sent the HTTP Host header containing the domain
“ecadforum.com” to our control server, we noticed that the connections would get
reset. We were only able to receive the control response when requesting a
subdomain of “ecadforum.com” and when we prefixed the request method (GET) with
the newline character. This is summarized in the table below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;ecadforum.com&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Normal GET request&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Blocked&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Modified GET request&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Not blocked&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GET request to subdomain&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Not blocked&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GET request to domain + \t (tab character)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Not blocked&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Get request to XYZecadforum.comZYX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Not blocked&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leads us to conclude that the devices implementing this type of
interception were in fact “smart” enough to understand the HTTP protocol and
could only implement blocking when they found the request to match what they
expected to be “valid” HTTP. Therefore, DPI equipment was most likely present in
the tested network and used to implement censorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s worth pointing out that technology with a similar pattern was previously
found in Turkmenistan in 2013, as &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/tab-tab-come-in/&#34;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; by OONI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;websites-blocked:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Websites blocked&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;media-outlets:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Media outlets&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today Ethiopia’s state of emergency imposes &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ictpolicy.org/blog/ethiopian-state-of-emergency-details-released-english-translation/&#34;&gt;restrictions&lt;/a&gt; on media. Yet, as part
of our study numerous Ethiopian news outlets &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/country/ET&#34;&gt;presented signs of DNS, HTTP, and TCP/IP blocking&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;prior&lt;/em&gt; to the state of emergency declaration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The table below illustrates the amount and types of network anomalies detected
when testing such sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Tested websites&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;DNS&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;HTTP-diff&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;HTTP-failure&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;TCP/IP&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Anomalies&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ecadforum.com/&#34;&gt;http://ecadforum.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mereja.com&#34;&gt;https://mereja.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mereja.com&#34;&gt;http://mereja.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zehabesha.com/&#34;&gt;http://zehabesha.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ethiomedia.com&#34;&gt;http://ethiomedia.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ethsat.com&#34;&gt;http://ethsat.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ethiopianreview.com&#34;&gt;http://ethiopianreview.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ethiopianreview.com&#34;&gt;http://www.ethiopianreview.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ethiomedia.com/index.html&#34;&gt;http://www.ethiomedia.com/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ethioforum.org&#34;&gt;http://www.ethioforum.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quatero.net&#34;&gt;http://www.quatero.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goolgule.com&#34;&gt;http://www.goolgule.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ogaden.com&#34;&gt;http://www.ogaden.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://oromiamedia.org/&#34;&gt;http://oromiamedia.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.debteraw.com&#34;&gt;http://www.debteraw.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nazret.com&#34;&gt;http://www.nazret.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tzta.ca/tzta/english.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.tzta.ca/tzta/english.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tzta.ca&#34;&gt;http://www.tzta.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oromiamedia.org/&#34;&gt;https://www.oromiamedia.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.satenaw.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.satenaw.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oromiamedia.org/&#34;&gt;https://oromiamedia.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.satenaw.com/amharic/&#34;&gt;http://www.satenaw.com/amharic/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nazret.com&#34;&gt;http://nazret.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ethiopianreporter.com&#34;&gt;http://www.ethiopianreporter.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some cases, we tested different versions of the same sites to examine whether
censorship could potentially be circumvented. Earlier this year, for example, we
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/uganda-social-media-blocked/&#34;&gt;found&lt;/a&gt; Ugandan ISPs only blocking the HTTP versions of social media sites,
enabling users to access these sites over HTTPS. In this study we therefore
tested various versions of certain sites, such as both the HTTP and HTTPS
versions of oromiamedia.org. In all such cases however, access to these sites
presented signs of network interference, as illustrated in the table above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, 16 different Ethiopian news outlets presented signs of censorship. As
no block pages were detected, we cannot confirm any censorship events with
absolute certainty. However, the sites that presented the highest amount of
network anomalies are more likely to have actually been blocked, while those
with fewer network anomalies are less likely to have been tampered with. As
such, ecadforum.com - with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20160912T112136Z_AS24757_b8C5V1dP3DlBSVTWBFZ3HEZ4RyzJzyyBEmhx1k5jiVTnITtcIr?input=https:%2F%2Fecadforum.com%2F&#34;&gt;highest amount of network anomalies&lt;/a&gt; - was most
likely blocked by DPI equipment (as explained previously), while access to it
might have also been interfered with based on DNS tampering. On the other hand,
sites which presented fewer cases of network anomalies (such as satenaw.com) are
less likely to have been blocked, though this remains a possibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, it’s interesting to see that out of the &lt;strong&gt;1,403 different URLs&lt;/strong&gt; (1,217
URLs in the “&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/blob/master/lists/global.csv&#34;&gt;global list&lt;/a&gt;” and 186 URLs in the “&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/blob/master/lists/et.csv&#34;&gt;Ethiopian list&lt;/a&gt;”) that were tested
for censorship as part of this study, access to these 16 Ethiopian news outlets
presented the highest levels of network anomalies, indicating that they were
most likely tampered with. These sites include oromiamedia.org, which is an
independent, nonpartisan, and nonprofit news enterprise that reports on Oromia,
one of the main regions that has been at the heart of the recent wave of
protests and political unrest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, access to &lt;strong&gt;ethsat.com&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ictpolicy.org/blog/ethiopian-state-of-emergency-details-released-english-translation/&#34;&gt;banned&lt;/a&gt; in Ethiopia under the
country’s new state of emergency restrictions. This website is run by the
Ethiopian diaspora, &lt;a href=&#34;http://ethsat.com/about-us/&#34;&gt;aims&lt;/a&gt; to “promote free press, democracy, respect for human
rights and the rule of law in Ethiopia” and also &lt;a href=&#34;http://amharic.ethsat.com/&#34;&gt;publishes in Amharic&lt;/a&gt;. However,
we tested access to this site prior to Ethiopia’s state of emergency declaration
and our findings show that it &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20161007T101106Z_AS24757_C2SUvTfp4dbK5vzLrYHpHspYaCaW4oR3XEZBwhtBPYwSD7uTcS?input=http:%2F%2Fethsat.com&#34;&gt;presented&lt;/a&gt; many network anomalies. Similarly to
ecadforum.com, access to ethsat.com presented high levels of HTTP interference,
indicating that it might have also been blocked by DPI equipment before it was
even officially banned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An Amharic online forum (&lt;strong&gt;mereja.com&lt;/strong&gt;) also &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20160912T112136Z_AS24757_b8C5V1dP3DlBSVTWBFZ3HEZ4RyzJzyyBEmhx1k5jiVTnITtcIr?input=https:%2F%2Fmereja.com&#34;&gt;presented&lt;/a&gt; high levels of HTTP
interference, and was possibly blocked by DPI as well. While the motivation
behind the blocking of news sites could potentially be attributed to the
dissemination of information around the protests, the potential blocking of an
Amharic forum might be attributed to intentions to block communication,
coordination and information dissemination amongst Amharic protesters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;political-opposition-and-armed-groups:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Political opposition and armed groups&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of our study we &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/country/ET&#34;&gt;found&lt;/a&gt; the websites of Ethiopian armed groups and
political opposition groups to be tampered with. In the case of those related to
armed groups espousing violent opposition to the Ethiopian government,
censorship may fall within the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.ohchr.org/english/issues/opinion/articles1920_iccpr/docs/CRP7Callamard.pdf&#34;&gt;permissible restrictions&lt;/a&gt; to freedom of expression
under international human rights law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The table below summarizes our findings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Tested websites&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;DNS&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;HTTP-diff&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;HTTP-failure&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;TCP/IP&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Anomalies&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ginbot7.org/&#34;&gt;http://ginbot7.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eprp.com&#34;&gt;http://www.eprp.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eppf.net&#34;&gt;http://www.eppf.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onlf.org&#34;&gt;http://www.onlf.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oromoliberationfront.org&#34;&gt;http://www.oromoliberationfront.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://patriotg7.org/&#34;&gt;http://patriotg7.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ginbot7.org/&#34;&gt;Ginbot 7&lt;/a&gt; is a national political party and part of Ethiopia’s political
opposition. In 2009 the Ethiopian government &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20160112163042/http://www.ethiopianreview.com/index/9441&#34;&gt;accused&lt;/a&gt; Ginbot 7 of fostering a
coup attempt to overthrow the government, which Ginbot 7 &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20120418222418/http://www.ginbot7.org/Ginbot_7_PressRelease_25_April_2009.htm&#34;&gt;denied&lt;/a&gt;. Ginbot 7 is one
of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://freedomhouse.org/report/freedom-world/2012/ethiopia&#34;&gt;proscribed organizations&lt;/a&gt; under the Anti-Terrorism Proclamation, which is
potentially why ginbot7.org was blocked. Through our testing we &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20160912T112136Z_AS24757_b8C5V1dP3DlBSVTWBFZ3HEZ4RyzJzyyBEmhx1k5jiVTnITtcIr?input=http:%2F%2Fginbot7.org%2F&#34;&gt;found&lt;/a&gt; that
access to this website presented a high amount of network anomalies. In
September 2016 we tested ginbot7.org by sending multiple HTTP GET requests to
access the site. In all cases however, we &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20160912T112136Z_AS24757_b8C5V1dP3DlBSVTWBFZ3HEZ4RyzJzyyBEmhx1k5jiVTnITtcIr?input=http:%2F%2Fginbot7.org%2F&#34;&gt;never received a response&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eprp.com&#34;&gt;Ethiopian People’s Revolutionary Party&lt;/a&gt; (EPRP) is a national political party
which was founded by the Ethiopian diaspora and which is currently headquartered
in the United States. During the 1970s Ethiopia’s then military government
declared open war (“&lt;a href=&#34;http://study.com/academy/lesson/red-terror-in-ethiopia.html&#34;&gt;Red Terror&lt;/a&gt;” campaign) against the EPRP and other political
opponents, resulting in the death of around 250,000 Ethiopians. Similar to
ginbot7.org, we found eprp.com inaccessible due to HTTP response failures as
part of our testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oromoliberationfront.org&#34;&gt;Oromo Liberation Front&lt;/a&gt; (OLF) is a regional political party that was
established by Oromo nationalists in the early 1970s to promote self-
determination, and which was &lt;a href=&#34;http://nazret.com/blog/index.php/2012/08/01/ethiopia-2011-u-s-terrorism-report-ethiopia&#34;&gt;designated&lt;/a&gt; as a “terrorist organization” by
Ethiopia’s government. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eppf.net&#34;&gt;Ethiopian People’s Patriotic Front&lt;/a&gt; (EPPF) is an armed
opposition group in north western Ethiopia that was originally founded to
overthrow the EPRDF regime. As part of our testing, the websites of both groups
appeared to be inaccessible due to HTTP response failures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the websites of two armed opposition groups, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onlf.org&#34;&gt;Ogaden National Liberation Front&lt;/a&gt; (ONLF) and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://patriotg7.org/&#34;&gt;Patriotic Ginbot 7 Movement for Unity and Democracy&lt;/a&gt;, also presented HTTP response failures as part of our testing. The
ONLF is an separatist armed group that is fighting for the independence of the
Ogaden region in eastern Ethiopia, bordering with Somalia. An &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ogaden.com&#34;&gt;Ogaden news website&lt;/a&gt; was also found to be inaccessible, as illustrated in the table of the
previous section of this report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lgbti-websites:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;LGBTI websites&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of OONI’s testing, access to sites supporting LGBTI rights appeared to
be tampered with since we did not receive HTTP responses when querying them.
These sites, and our research findings, are included in the table below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Tested websites&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;DNS&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;HTTP-diff&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;HTTP-failure&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;TCP/IP&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Anomalies&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.queernet.org&#34;&gt;http://www.queernet.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.samesexmarriage.ca&#34;&gt;http://www.samesexmarriage.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ifge.org&#34;&gt;http://www.ifge.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ifge.org/&#34;&gt;International Foundation for Gender Education (IFGE)&lt;/a&gt; is a US-based
educational organization that promotes acceptance for transgender people, while
samesexmarriage.ca is a Canadian site that promotes same-sex marriage. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.queernet.org/&#34;&gt;QueerNet&lt;/a&gt;
is a project of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onlinepolicy.org/&#34;&gt;Online Policy Group&lt;/a&gt; (a non-profit dedicated to online policy
research around digital rights issues) which provides free online services (such
as email hosting, websites, and mailing lists) for LGBTI communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Same-sex sexual activity is prohibited in Ethiopia under Article 629 of the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wipo.int/wipolex/en/text.jsp?file_id=248268&#34;&gt;Criminal Code&lt;/a&gt; punishable up to fifteen years imprisonment. All three websites
appeared to be inaccessible in September 2016, but appeared to be accessible
when tested again in early October 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;human-rights-websites:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Human rights websites&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two sites promoting freedom of speech and expression also presented signs of
network anomalies as part of our study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Tested websites&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;DNS&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;HTTP-diff&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;HTTP-failure&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;TCP/IP&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Anomalies&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cyberethiopia.com&#34;&gt;http://www.cyberethiopia.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cyberethiopia.com/warka4/&#34;&gt;http://www.cyberethiopia.com/warka4/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fepproject.org&#34;&gt;http://www.fepproject.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cyberethiopia.com&#34;&gt;Cyber Ethiopia&lt;/a&gt; is a Swiss-based non-profit organization that aims to promote
human rights in Ethiopia through programs and policy recommendations that uphold
freedom of speech and expression online. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fepproject.org&#34;&gt;Free Expression Policy Project&lt;/a&gt; is a
think tank on artistic and intellectual freedom. It provides research and
advocacy on free speech, copyright, and media democracy issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When querying cyberethiopia.com, we did not receive an HTTP response, indicating
that access to the site was blocked. Our results regarding fepproject.org are
different. When testing the site in &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20160615T064622Z_AS24757_WkSufX2lde14cj3IrIx6vG1JZUbQfS8eoFU9BOq4tbgAq3b8Co?input=http:%2F%2Fwww.fepproject.org&#34;&gt;June&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20161007T103227Z_AS24757_2L3k891LkzJ6lTGT4TYB4L1sjbaNQq5uvLSAk0vNZ8WIKsz4Jb?input=http:%2F%2Fwww.fepproject.org&#34;&gt;October&lt;/a&gt; 2016, we were able to
successfully connect to it. However, all attempts to establish TCP connections
to the site during &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20160817T193553Z_AS24757_Gl82pwV6hJaIIoPjJ5uVSNNtQd78S7A1LBl7HIO08gkaPQg0Ri?input=http:%2F%2Fwww.fepproject.org&#34;&gt;August&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20160912T074657Z_AS24757_36rWpt4et8egebrQAJAb2mgXfiR8fyBCJVxbvsHgXehPXPYGML?input=http:%2F%2Fwww.fepproject.org&#34;&gt;September&lt;/a&gt; 2016 failed and presented timeout
errors. It remains unclear if fepproject.org was intentionally blocked
throughout August and September 2016 based on TCP/IP blocking, or if connections
to the site failed due to transient network failures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;censorship-circumvention-tool-websites:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Censorship circumvention tool websites&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amongst the many sites that presented HTTP response failures are the sites of
major censorship circumvention tools: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://psiphon.ca/&#34;&gt;Psiphon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Tested websites&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;DNS&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;HTTP-diff&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;HTTP-failure&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;TCP/IP&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Anomalies&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.psiphon.ca&#34;&gt;http://www.psiphon.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ultrasurf.us&#34;&gt;http://www.ultrasurf.us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.torproject.org&#34;&gt;http://www.torproject.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ultrasurf.us&#34;&gt;https://ultrasurf.us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ultrasurf.us&#34;&gt;http://ultrasurf.us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://psiphon.ca&#34;&gt;http://psiphon.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tor is a free and open source network designed to provide anonymity to its users
by bouncing their communications across a distributed network of relays, thus
masking their real IP addresses and enabling them to circumvent censorship.
Psiphon is free and open source software that utilizes SSH, VPN, and HTTP proxy
technology to enable its users to circumvent censorship. Ultrasurf is freeware
that utilizes an HTTP proxy server to enable its users to bypass censorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both torproject.org and ultrasurf.us appeared to be inaccessible between June
and October 2016 due to HTTP response failures, while psiphon.ca presented the
same failures from August 2016 onwards. The fact that all three sites presented
HTTP response failures and that &lt;a href=&#34;http://ultrasurf.us&#34;&gt;http://ultrasurf.us&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ultrasurf.us&#34;&gt;https://ultrasurf.us&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://psiphon.ca&#34;&gt;http://psiphon.ca&lt;/a&gt; appeared to be slightly more accessible than
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ultrasurf.us&#34;&gt;http://www.ultrasurf.us&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.psiphon.ca&#34;&gt;http://www.psiphon.ca&lt;/a&gt; indicate the presence of Deep
Packet Inspection (DPI) equipment in the tested network (as explained in the DPI
section of this report).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While toproject.org was &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20161007T101106Z_AS24757_C2SUvTfp4dbK5vzLrYHpHspYaCaW4oR3XEZBwhtBPYwSD7uTcS?input=http:%2F%2Fwww.torproject.org&#34;&gt;found to be inaccessible&lt;/a&gt;, we did &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20160909T172805Z_AS24757_O6q1HLEWGZyuNxa9aJq921iwhokHWzmOUANVtz5l7fXccJMes0&#34;&gt;not find tor software itself being blocked&lt;/a&gt; in Ethiopia during the testing period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;circumventing-censorship:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Circumventing censorship&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations and companies hosting websites that may be blocked in Ethiopia can
consider hosting their websites on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/docs/tor-hidden-service.html.en&#34;&gt;Tor hidden service&lt;/a&gt; to hide its IP address
and prevent blocking. It is also recommended to add HTTPS to your site through
&lt;a href=&#34;https://letsencrypt.org/&#34;&gt;Let’s Encrypt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individuals seeking to access blocked websites may consider using the below
circumvention tools and services to get around blocks. &lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Under Anti-
terrorism Proclamation, use of digital security tools have been used in the past
to prosecute bloggers and activists, even if there is no provision of law that
outlaws use of internet security tools, including tor. Yet It is vital that you
understand the security risks in accessing such tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser.html.en&#34;&gt;Tor Browser&lt;/a&gt; (or other circumvention tools) to circumvent censorship and
access blocked sites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If torproject.org is blocked, download Tor Browser &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/gettor&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt; network is blocked, get &lt;a href=&#34;https://bridges.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor bridges&lt;/a&gt; to circumvent the blocking and
connect to it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/docs/android.html.en&#34;&gt;VPN mode of Orbot&lt;/a&gt; to access WhatsApp (and other IM apps) on Android over
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt; network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;internet-shutdown:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Internet shutdown?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numerous &lt;a href=&#34;https://advox.globalvoices.org/2016/10/12/ethiopian-authorities-shut-down-mobile-internet-and-major-social-media-sites/&#34;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; surfaced in October regarding a mobile internet shutdown in
Ethiopia, and this was also reported to Amnesty International by contacts on
the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/&#34;&gt;OONI software tests&lt;/a&gt; are designed to examine the blocking of sites and services,
but do not monitor internet shutdowns as a whole. As such, we referred to third
party data such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.measurementlab.net/tools/ndt/&#34;&gt;NDT measurements&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/transparencyreport/traffic/explorer/?r=ET&amp;amp;l=WEBSEARCH&amp;amp;csd=1468958400000&amp;amp;ced=1478352600000&#34;&gt;Google transparency reports&lt;/a&gt; in order to
assess whether we could confirm the reported internet shutdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The below graph from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/transparencyreport/traffic/explorer/?r=ET&amp;amp;l=WEBSEARCH&amp;amp;csd=1468958400000&amp;amp;ced=1478352600000&#34;&gt;Google’s transparency reports&lt;/a&gt; illustrates the total volume
of Google Search traffic originating from Ethiopia between July and November
2016. As published in an &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ethiopia-internet-shutdown-amidst-recent-protests/&#34;&gt;earlier report&lt;/a&gt; by OONI, the data shows a complete drop
in Internet traffic in early August, suggesting that a full Internet block took
place following the call for region-wide protests on the weekend of 5 and 6
August. While the data shows a decrease in internet traffic during October,
there is no strong indication of an internet shutdown along the lines of that
observed in early August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ethiopia-report/et-01.png&#34; alt=&#34;Google data&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google Transparency Report, Ethiopia, Google Search traffic between July and November 2016.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Google Maps is another Google service that is commonly used via mobile
phones, we also looked at Google Maps traffic originating from Ethiopia between
July and November 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ethiopia-report/et-02.png&#34; alt=&#34;Google data&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google Transparency Report, Ethiopia, Google Maps traffic between July and November 2016.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to Google Search traffic, Google Maps traffic appears to be disrupted in
August but not in October. The above graphs indicate that if an internet
shutdown did occur in October, it only occurred in some networks in certain
locations, rather than nationwide. Furthermore, the decrease in overall traffic
during October could be attributed to temporary mobile internet shutdowns in
certain local networks, or to an increase of censorship events (for example,
targeted blocking of certain websites and instant messaging services).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, there appears to be a spike in the usage of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor circumvention software&lt;/a&gt; in Ethiopia during October, indicating that internet services might
have been less accessible. This is illustrated via &lt;a href=&#34;https://metrics.torproject.org/userstats-relay-country.html?start=2016-08-06&amp;amp;end=2016-11-04&amp;amp;country=et&amp;amp;events=off&#34;&gt;Tor Metrics data&lt;/a&gt; below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ethiopia-report/et-03.png&#34; alt=&#34;Tor metrics&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The graph below shows an increase in Tor usage from 8th October, when Ethiopia’s
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ictpolicy.org/blog/ethiopian-state-of-emergency-details-released-english-translation/&#34;&gt;state of emergency&lt;/a&gt; was declared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ethiopia-report/et-04.png&#34; alt=&#34;Tor metrics&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://metrics.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor Metrics data&lt;/a&gt;, combined with third party internet traffic data, indicates a
possible increase in censorship events following the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ictpolicy.org/blog/ethiopian-state-of-emergency-details-released-english-translation/&#34;&gt;declaration of Ethiopia’s state of emergency&lt;/a&gt;. While there is no strong indication of an internet shutdown,
it is possible that certain mobile data service might have temporarily been shut
down in certain locations in Ethiopia at specific points in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is worth noting that OONI’s inability to confirm the reported mobile internet
shutdown might also in part be due to limitations in the data sources that we
referred to. We therefore encourage companies (like Facebook) to increase
transparency around internet traffic data so that internet shutdowns and other
censorship events can be studied and evaluated more accurately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;international-human-rights-law:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;International Human Rights Law&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights (ICCPR), to which
Ethiopia is a state party, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achpr.org/instruments/achpr/&#34;&gt;guarantees freedom of expression&lt;/a&gt;. This includes the “freedom
to seek, receive and impart information and ideas of all kinds, regardless of
frontiers, either orally, in writing or in print, in the form of art, or through
any other media of his choice.” This right is also protected under Article 9 of
the African Charter on Human and Peoples’ Rights, to which Ethiopia is a state
party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding restrictions on access to internet resources, the United Nations Human
Rights Committee has stressed that any restrictions “generally should be
content-specific; generic bans on the operation of certain sites and systems are
not compatible with paragraph 3 of Article 19 of the ICCPR. It is also
inconsistent with paragraph 3 to prohibit a site or an information dissemination
system from publishing material solely on the basis that it may be critical of
the government or the political social system espoused by the government.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UN Human Rights Council resolution on the promotion, protection and
enjoyment of human rights on the Internet which was passed on 1 July 2016,
“condemns unequivocally measures to intentionally prevent or disrupt access to
or dissemination of information online in violation of international human
rights law and calls on all States to refrain from and cease such measures.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The abuse of freedom of expression in the form of propaganda for war, advocacy
of national, racial or religious hatred that constitutes incitement to
discrimination, hostility or violence may be subject to restrictions under the
ICCPR,  but these restrictions must meet three requirements laid out in the
covenant. The first requirement is that restrictions must be provided by law,
which is “formulated with sufficient precision to enable an individual to
regulate his or her conduct accordingly”. Additionally, “a law may not confer
unfettered discretion for the restriction of freedom of expression on those
charged with its execution.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second requirement is that restrictions must be “necessary” to achieve one
of the enumerated legitimate aims under the ICCPR. The third requirement
provides, among other things, that “restrictive measures must conform to the
principle of proportionality… they must be the least intrusive instrument
amongst those which might achieve their protective function.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/country/ET&#34;&gt;OONI’s findings&lt;/a&gt; provide evidence of systematic interference with access to
numerous websites belonging to independent news organizations and political
opposition groups, as well as sites supporting freedom of expression and LGBTI
rights. Such widespread interference and blocking is a violation of Ethiopia’s
obligations under article 19 of the ICCPR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The restrictions on access to information as per the findings of this report
fail to meet the legality test, which is the first requirement under article
19(3). Ethiopia lacks clear and precise law that governs access to internet and
social media, restrictions/blockade of websites and social media, and the legal
procedures. The inventory of Ethiopian relevant telecommunications, cybercrimes,
security, and intelligence laws reveals the absence of provisions that govern
content control and access to internet in the Country. The laws that established
the Information Network Security Agency and the National Intelligence and
Security Service1 authorize neither of the institutions to restrict access to
internet and social media, censor websites for any reason. The Telecom Fraud
Offences Proclamation does not authorize any of the Government agencies to
control and restrict access to internet, websites, or social media application
in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, the blocking of WhatsApp and restrictions of certain websites are
arbitrary, being conducted without any specific national law. Moreover, in the
absence of such law, the country also lacks the administrative and judicial
procedures for challenging such restrictions and blockades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet restrictions also fail the proportionality test, because the
interference is not limited to specific content; rather interference is
happening at a very large scale, with dozens of websites affected over the space
of several months. Similarly, blocking access to WhatsApp, a popular
communications platform in Ethiopia is not a justifiable restriction on freedom
of expression and access to information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethiopia’s practices of restricting access to large numbers of websites, as well
as services such as WhatsApp is therefore a clear violation of the rights to
freedom of expression and access to information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ICCPR permits derogation from certain rights during emergencies. However,
such derogations must meet several criteria in order to be lawful. Most
importantly, “the situation must amount to a public emergency which threatens
the life of the nation, and the State party must have officially proclaimed a
state of emergency.” Measures taken subject to a derogation must be “limited to
the extent strictly required by the exigencies of the situation.” The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achpr.org/press/2016/10/d321/&#34;&gt;African Charter on Human and Peoples’ Rights&lt;/a&gt; does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have a provision that provides for
derogation during emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ictpolicy.org/blog/ethiopian-state-of-emergency-details-released-english-translation/&#34;&gt;State of Emergency Declaration&lt;/a&gt; allows the Command Post to “stop or suspend
any mass media and communications” throughout the country. The geographic
coverage of this measure violates the requirement that derogations under state
of emergency must be limited to exigencies of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ethiopian Government has repeatedly alleged that the violence after the
Irrecha tragedy prompted the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ictpolicy.org/blog/ethiopian-state-of-emergency-details-released-english-translation/&#34;&gt;declaration of the state of emergency&lt;/a&gt;. While the
violence occurred primarily in some districts of Oromia and Amhara, it is
unclear how the exigencies of the situation would strictly require the
imposition of such measures with a geographic scope that covers the whole of the
country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the midst of ongoing protests in Ethiopia, access to &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20160912T112212Z_AS24757_q79IWOW8fmyKllSOWewx6URNKqoFp5aAyHmy3UjZsTTl5fPbrV&#34;&gt;WhatsApp was found to be blocked&lt;/a&gt;, and the covert presence of &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20160912T111210Z_AS24757_4un8r03S6zIMpfJ7IuJqxxFGRaSfXlLOgUxshT9Ja5ep7hpQkS?input=ecadforum.com&#34;&gt;Deep Packet Inspection (DPI)&lt;/a&gt; equipment was
not only unveiled, but it was also found to be filtering access to an
independent Ethiopian media website (ecadforum.com).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research conducted by OONI between June and October 2016 shows that access to
WhatsApp as well as at least 16 news outlets were blocked prior to the state of
emergency. Also targeted were websites supporting Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual,
Transgender and Intersex (LGBTI) rights, organizations advocating freedom of
expression, sites run by opposition groups and armed movements, as well as
websites that offer censorship circumvention tools, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://psiphon.ca/&#34;&gt;Psiphon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, all of these sites consistently presented HTTP response failures
when queried, while the testing of different versions of the same sites appeared
to bypass the filter in certain cases. This pattern is identical to that of
ecadforum.com, indicating that most (if not all) of the above types of sites
were likely filtered by DPI equipment as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Amnesty International research findings during the same period corroborate
OONI’s findings, indicating that other social media applications were very slow,
not working properly or inaccessible, particularly in regions affected by the
protests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evidence suggesting that the government is deploying Deep Packet Inspection
(DPI) technology to filter access to internet traffic is concerning. Though it
has many legitimate functions, DPI enables effective surveillance and filtering
of internet traffic, increasing the States’ ability to restrict access to the
internet, fully or partially, on command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the acts of censorship identified by OONI took place before a state of
emergency was announced, and violated Ethiopia’s obligation to respect, protect
and fulfill its people’s right to receive and impact information. The acts of
censorship, conducted outside a clear legal framework, over several months and
affecting dozens of websites and social media platforms failed to meet the
criteria set out under the ICCPR for restrictions on freedom of expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the State of Emergency may have subsequently provided a legal framework
under Ethiopian law for some of these measures, the State of Emergency itself is
so broadly drafted that it violates Ethiopia&amp;rsquo;s international legal obligations
and permits violations of numerous human rights. The power the state of
emergency bestows upon the Command post to monitor and suspend all
communications and media throughout Ethiopia is unnecessarily expansive. The
protests and the violence following the protest have been limited to Oromia,
Amhara, Konso District in Southern Nations Nationalities and Peoples Region
(SNNPR) and Addis Ababa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amnesty International and OONI are concerned that unnecessary and
disproportionate censorship of the internet will not only continue during the
state of emergency, but become institutionalized and entrenched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommendations:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Recommendations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To Ethiopian authorities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amnesty International and OONI request the Ethiopian government to respect and
protect and fulfill freedom of expression on the internet. Specifically, they
request the Ethiopian Authorities to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Refrain from blocking access to the internet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Refrain from unlawful censorship of the internet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ensure that limitations on the right to seek or impart information on the
internet fully adhere to the requirements of article 19(3) of the ICCPR.
Specifically, that the restrictions comply with the three-tier test of legality,
necessity and proportionality, and that they are subject to judicial review.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To social media companies (e.g. Facebook, Twitter)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make available publicly verifiable data on network traffic originating from
countries around the world, to ensure transparency when social media
restrictions or heavy network disruption occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;part-2-methodology:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Part 2: Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The methodology of this study, in an attempt to identify potential censorship
events in Ethiopia, included the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Test lists&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;OONI network measurements&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data analysis&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-probe&#34;&gt;OONI’s free software tests&lt;/a&gt; were run from a local vantage point (EthioNet) in
Ethiopia. Some tests examined two lists of URLs: the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/blob/master/lists/et.csv&#34;&gt;one being relevant to Ethiopia&lt;/a&gt;, while the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/blob/master/lists/global.csv&#34;&gt;other&lt;/a&gt; including URLs that are commonly accessed around the
world. All URLs included in these two lists were tested in terms of blocking.
Other OONI tests were run to examine whether systems that could be responsible
for censorship, surveillance, and traffic manipulation were present in the
tested network. Once network measurement data was collected from these tests,
the data was subsequently processed and analyzed based on a set of heuristics
for detecting internet censorship and traffic manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The testing period started on 15th June 2016 and concluded on 7th October 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;test-lists:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Test lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important part of identifying censorship is determining &lt;em&gt;which&lt;/em&gt; websites to
examine for blocking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-probe&#34;&gt;software&lt;/a&gt; (called ooniprobe) is designed to examine URLs contained in
specific lists (“test lists”) for censorship. By default, ooniprobe examines the
“&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/blob/master/lists/global.csv&#34;&gt;global test list&lt;/a&gt;”, which includes a wide range of internationally relevant
websites, most of which are in English. These websites fall under &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/blob/master/lists/00-proposed-category_codes.csv&#34;&gt;30 categories&lt;/a&gt;,
ranging from news media, file sharing and culture, to provocative or
objectionable categories, like pornography, political criticism, and hate
speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These categories help ensure that a wide range of different types of websites
are tested, and they enable the examination of the impact of censorship events
(for example, if the majority of the websites found to be blocked in a country
fall under the “human rights” category, that may have a bigger impact than other
types of websites being blocked elsewhere). The main reason why objectionable
categories (such as “pornography” and “hate speech”) are included for testing is
because they are more likely to be blocked due to their nature, enabling the
development of heuristics for detecting censorship elsewhere within a country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to testing the URLs included in the global test list, ooniprobe is
also designed to examine a test list which is specifically created for the
country that the user is running ooniprobe from, if such a list exists. Unlike
the global test list, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/tree/master/lists&#34;&gt;country-specific test lists&lt;/a&gt; include websites that are
relevant and commonly accessed within specific countries, and such websites are
often in local languages. Similarly to the global test list, country-specific
test lists include websites that fall under the same set of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/blob/master/lists/00-proposed-category_codes.csv&#34;&gt;30 categories&lt;/a&gt;, as
explained previously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All test lists are hosted by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://citizenlab.org/&#34;&gt;Citizen Lab&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, supporting OONI and
other network measurement projects in the creation and maintenance of lists of
URLs to test for censorship. Some criteria for adding URLs to test lists include
the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The URLs cover topics of socio-political interest within the country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The URLs are likely to be blocked because they include sensitive content (i.e.
they touch upon sensitive issues or express political criticism).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The URLs have been blocked in the past.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Users have faced difficulty connecting to those URLs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above criteria indicate that such URLs are more likely to be blocked,
enabling the development of heuristics for detecting censorship within a
country. Furthermore, other criteria for adding URLs are reflected in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/blob/master/lists/00-proposed-category_codes.csv&#34;&gt;30 categories&lt;/a&gt; that URLs can fall under. Such categories, for example, can include
file-sharing, human rights, and news media, under which the websites of file-
sharing projects, human rights NGOs and media organizations can be added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of this study, the URLs included in &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; the Citizen Lab’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/blob/master/lists/et.csv&#34;&gt;test list for Ethiopia&lt;/a&gt; and its &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/blob/master/lists/global.csv&#34;&gt;global list&lt;/a&gt; were tested for blocking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A core limitation to the study is the bias in terms of the URLs that were
selected for testing. The URL selection criteria, for example, included the
following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Websites that were more likely to be blocked because their content expressed
political criticism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Websites of organizations that were known to have previously been blocked and
were thus likely to be blocked again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Websites reporting on human rights restrictions and violations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above criteria reflect bias in terms of which URLs were selected for
testing, as one of the core aims of this study was to examine whether and to
what extent websites reflecting criticism were blocked, limiting open dialogue
and access to information across the country. As a result of this bias, it is
important to acknowledge that the findings of this study are only limited to the
websites that were tested, and do not provide a complete view of other
censorship events that may have taken place before and after the testing period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ooni-network-measurements:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;OONI network measurements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI)&lt;/a&gt; is a free software project
that aims to increase transparency about internet censorship and traffic
manipulation around the world. Since 2011, OONI has developed multiple &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-probe&#34;&gt;free and open source software tests&lt;/a&gt; designed to examine the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blocking of websites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blocking of instant messaging apps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detection of systems responsible for censorship and traffic manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reachability of circumvention tools (such as Tor, Psiphon, and Lantern) and
sensitive domains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of this study, the following OONI software tests were run from a local
vantage point in Ethiopia:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/web-connectivity/&#34;&gt;Web connectivity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/http-invalid-request-line/&#34;&gt;HTTP invalid request line&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/http-header-field-manipulation/&#34;&gt;HTTP header field manipulation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/http-host/&#34;&gt;HTTP host&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web connectivity test was run with the aim of examining whether a set of
URLs (included in both the “&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/blob/master/lists/global.csv&#34;&gt;global test list&lt;/a&gt;” and the “&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/blob/master/lists/et.csv&#34;&gt;Ethiopian test list&lt;/a&gt;”)
were blocked during the testing period and if so, how. The HTTP invalid request
line and HTTP header field manipulation tests were run with the aim of examining
whether systems (that could potentially be responsible for censorship and/or
surveillance) were present in the tested network. The HTTP host test was run to
not only examine if tested URLs were blocked, but to also examine whether
specific systems were used in the tested network to implement such blocking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sections below document how each of these tests are designed for the purpose
of detecting cases of internet censorship and traffic manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;web-connectivity:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Web Connectivity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/web-connectivity/&#34;&gt;test&lt;/a&gt; examines whether websites are reachable and if they are not, it
attempts to determine whether access to them is blocked through DNS tampering,
TCP connection RST/IP blocking or by a transparent HTTP proxy. Specifically,
this test is designed to perform the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Resolver identification&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;DNS lookup&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;TCP connect&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;HTTP GET request&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, this test performs the above (excluding the first step, which is
performed only over the network of the user) both over a control server and over
the network of the user. If the results from both networks match, then there is
no clear sign of network interference; but if the results are different, the
websites that the user is testing are likely censored. Further information is
provided below, explaining how each step performed under the web connectivity
test works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Resolver identification&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The domain name system (DNS) is what is responsible for transforming a host name
(e.g. torproject.org) into an IP address (e.g. 38.229.72.16). Internet Service
Providers (ISPs), amongst others, run DNS resolvers which map IP addresses to
hostnames. In some circumstances though, ISPs map the requested host names to
the wrong IP addresses, which is a form of tampering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a first step, the web connectivity test attempts to identify which DNS
resolver is being used by the user. It does so by performing a DNS query to
special domains (such as whoami.akamai.com) which will disclose the IP address
of the resolver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. DNS lookup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the web connectivity test has identified the DNS resolver of the user, it
then attempts to identify which addresses are mapped to the tested host names by
the resolver. It does so by performing a DNS lookup, which asks the resolver to
disclose which IP addresses are mapped to the tested host names, as well as
which other host names are linked to the tested host names under DNS queries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. TCP connect&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web connectivity test will then try to connect to the tested websites by
attempting to establish a TCP session on port 80 (or port 443 for URLs that
begin with HTTPS) for the list of IP addresses that were identified in the
previous step (DNS lookup).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. HTTP GET request&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the web connectivity test connects to tested websites (through the previous
step), it sends requests through the HTTP protocol to the servers which are
hosting those websites. A server normally responds to an HTTP GET request with
the content of the webpage that is requested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comparison of results: Identifying censorship&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the above steps of the web connectivity test are performed both over a
control server and over the network of the user, the collected results are then
compared with the aim of identifying whether and how tested websites are
tampered with. If the compared results do not match, then there is a sign of
network interference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are the conditions under which the following types of blocking are
identified:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DNS blocking:&lt;/strong&gt; If the DNS responses (such as the IP addresses mapped to host names) do not
match.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TCP/IP blocking:&lt;/strong&gt; If a TCP session to connect to websites was not established
over the network of the user.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HTTP blocking:&lt;/strong&gt; If the HTTP request over the user’s network failed, or the HTTP
status codes don’t match, or all of the following apply:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The body length of compared websites (over the control server and the
network of the user) differs by some percentage&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The HTTP headers names do not match&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The HTML title tags do not match&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note, however, that DNS resolvers, such as Google or a local
ISP, often provide users with IP addresses that are closest to them
geographically. Often this is not done with the intent of network tampering, but
merely for the purpose of providing users with localized content or faster
access to websites. As a result, some false positives might arise in OONI
measurements. Other false positives might occur when tested websites serve
different content depending on the country that the user is connecting from, or
in the cases when websites return failures even though they are not tampered
with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;http-invalid-request-line:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;HTTP invalid request line&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/http-invalid-request-line/&#34;&gt;test&lt;/a&gt; tries to detect the presence of network components (“middle box”)
which could be responsible for censorship and/or traffic manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of sending a normal HTTP request, this test sends an invalid HTTP
request line - containing an invalid HTTP version number, an invalid field count
and a huge request method – to an echo service listening on the standard HTTP
port. An echo service is a very useful debugging and measurement tool, which
simply sends back to the originating source any data it receives. If a middle
box is not present in the network between the user and an echo service, then the
echo service will send the invalid HTTP request line back to the user, exactly
as it received it. In such cases, there is no visible traffic manipulation in
the tested network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, however, a middle box is present in the tested network, the invalid HTTP
request line will be intercepted by the middle box and this may trigger an error
and that will subsequently be sent back to OONI’s server. Such errors indicate
that software for traffic manipulation is likely placed in the tested network,
though it’s not always clear what that software is. In some cases though,
censorship and/or surveillance vendors can be identified through the error
messages in the received HTTP response. Based on this technique, OONI has
previously &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/highlights/&#34;&gt;detected&lt;/a&gt; the use of BlueCoat, Squid and Privoxy proxy technologies in
networks across multiple countries around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important though to note that a false negative could potentially occur in
the hypothetical instance that ISPs are using highly sophisticated censorship
and/or surveillance software that is specifically designed to not trigger errors
when receiving invalid HTTP request lines like the ones of this test.
Furthermore, the presence of a middle box is not necessarily indicative of
traffic manipulation, as they are often used in networks for caching purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;http-header-field-manipulation:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;HTTP header field manipulation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/http-header-field-manipulation/&#34;&gt;test&lt;/a&gt; also tries to detect the presence of network components (“middle box”)
which could be responsible for censorship and/or traffic manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTTP is a protocol which transfers or exchanges data across the internet. It
does so by handling a client’s request to connect to a server, and a server’s
response to a client’s request. Every time a user connects to a server, the user
(client) sends a request through the HTTP protocol to that server. Such requests
include “HTTP headers”, which transmit various types of information, including
the user’s device operating system and the type of browser that is being used.
If Firefox is used on Windows, for example, the “user agent header” in the HTTP
request will tell the server that a Firefox browser is being used on a Windows
operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This test emulates an HTTP request towards a server, but sends HTTP headers that
have variations in capitalization. In other words, this test sends HTTP requests
which include valid, but non-canonical HTTP headers. Such requests are sent to a
backend control server which sends back any data it receives. If OONI receives
the HTTP headers exactly as they were sent, then there is no visible presence of
a “middle box” in the network that could be responsible for censorship,
surveillance and/or traffic manipulation. If, however, such software is present
in the tested network, it will likely normalize the invalid headers that are
sent or add extra headers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on whether the HTTP headers that are sent and received from a backend
control server are the same or not, OONI is able to evaluate whether software –
which could be responsible for traffic manipulation – is present in the tested
network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;False negatives, however, could potentially occur in the hypothetical instance
that ISPs are using highly sophisticated software that is specifically designed
to not interfere with HTTP headers when it receives them. Furthermore, the
presence of a middle box is not necessarily indicative of traffic manipulation,
as they are often used in networks for caching purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;http-host:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;HTTP Host&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/http-host/&#34;&gt;test&lt;/a&gt; is designed to examine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether the domain names of websites are blocked;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The presence of “middle boxes” (software that could be responsible for
censorship and/or surveillance) in tested networks;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether censorship circumvention techniques are capable of bypassing the
censorship implemented by the “middle box”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI’s HTTP Host test implements a series of techniques which help it evade
getting detected from censors and then uses a list of domain names (such as
bbc.co.uk) to connect to an OONI backend control server, which sends the host
headers of those domain names back to OONI. If a “middle box” is detected
between the network path of the probe and the OONI backend control server, its
fingerprint might be included in the JSON data that OONI receives from the
backend control server. Such data also informs OONI if the tested domain names
are blocked or not, as well as how the censor tried to fingerprint the
censorship of those domains. This can sometimes lead to the identification of
the type of infrastructure being used to implement censorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-analysis:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Data analysis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through its &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-pipeline&#34;&gt;data pipeline&lt;/a&gt;, OONI processes all network measurements that it
collects, including the following types of data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Country code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI by default collects the code which corresponds to the country from which
the user is running ooniprobe tests from, by automatically searching for it
based on the user’s IP address through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.maxmind.com/en/home&#34;&gt;MaxMind GeoIP database&lt;/a&gt;. The
collection of country codes is an important part of OONI’s research, as it
enables OONI to map out global network measurements and to identify where
network interferences take place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autonomous System Number (ASN)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI by default collects the Autonomous System Number (ASN) which corresponds to
the network that a user is running ooniprobe tests from. The collection of the
ASN is useful to OONI’s research because it reveals the specific network
provider (such as Vodafone) of a user. Such information can increase
transparency in regards to which network providers are implementing censorship
or other forms of network interference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date and time of measurements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI by default collects the time and date of when tests were run. This
information helps OONI evaluate when network interferences occur and to compare
them across time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IP addresses and other information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI does not deliberately collect or store users’ IP addresses. In fact, OONI
takes measures to remove users’ IP addresses from the collected measurements, to
protect its users from &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/about/risks/&#34;&gt;potential risks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, OONI might &lt;em&gt;unintentionally&lt;/em&gt; collect users’ IP addresses and other
potentially personally-identifiable information, if such information is included
in the HTTP headers or other metadata of measurements. This, for example, can
occur if the tested websites include tracking technologies or custom content
based on a user’s network location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network measurements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The types of network measurements that OONI collects depend on the types of
tests that are run. Specifications about each OONI test can be viewed through
its &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-spec/tree/master/test-specs&#34;&gt;git repository&lt;/a&gt;, and details about what collected network measurements entail
can be viewed through &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/world/&#34;&gt;OONI Explorer&lt;/a&gt; or through OONI’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;list of measurements&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI processes the above types of data with the aim of deriving meaning from the
collected measurements and, specifically, in an attempt to answer the following
types of questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which types of OONI tests were run?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In which countries were those tests run?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In which networks were those tests run?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When were tests run?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What types of network interference occurred?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In which countries did network interference occur?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In which networks did network interference occur?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When did network interference occur?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did network interference occur?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer such questions, OONI’s pipeline is designed to process data which is
automatically sent to OONI’s measurement collector by default. The initial
processing of network measurements enables the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attributing measurements to a specific country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attributing measurements to a specific network within a country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Distinguishing measurements based on the specific tests that were run for their
collection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Distinguishing between “normal” and “anomalous” measurements (the latter
indicating that a form of network tampering is  likely present).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Identifying the type of network interference based on a set of heuristics for
DNS tampering, TCP/IP blocking, and HTTP blocking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Identifying block pages based on a set of heuristics for HTTP blocking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Identifying the presence of “middle boxes” within tested networks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, false positives and false negatives emerge within the processed data
due to a number of reasons. As explained previously (section on “OONI network
measurements”), DNS resolvers (operated by Google or a local ISP) often provide
users with IP addresses that are closest to them geographically. While this may
appear to be a case of DNS tampering, it is actually done with the intention of
providing users with faster access to websites. Similarly, false positives may
emerge when tested websites serve different content depending on the country
that the user is connecting from, or in the cases when websites return failures
even though they are not tampered with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, measurements indicating HTTP or TCP/IP blocking might actually be
due to temporary HTTP or TCP/IP failures, and may not conclusively be a sign of
network interference. It is therefore important to test the same sets of
websites across time and to cross-correlate data, prior to reaching a conclusion
on whether websites are in fact being blocked. Since block pages differ from
country to country and sometimes even from network to network, it is quite
challenging to accurately identify them. OONI uses a series of heuristics to try
to guess if the page in question differs from the expected control, but these
heuristics can often result in false positives. Due to this, OONI only confirms
an instance of blocking when a known block page has manually been added to the
list of block pages that OONI supports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this means that when a block page is not presented by the censor OONI
cannot confirm with absolute certainty that blocking is occurring. For the
purpose of this study we have extended our methodology to also take into account
unusual failures that could be triggered by the censor. In particular, we have
looked at sites that appear to fail consistently (that is in the same way) and
constantly over the testing period, therefore most likely not due to transient
networking errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI’s methodology for detecting the presence of “middle boxes” - systems that
could be responsible for censorship, surveillance and traffic manipulation - can
also present false negatives if ISPs are using highly sophisticated software
that is specifically designed to not interfere with HTTP headers when it
receives them, or to not trigger error messages when receiving invalid HTTP
request lines. It remains unclear though if such software is being used.
Moreover, it’s important to note that the presence of a middle box is not
necessarily indicative of censorship or traffic manipulation, as such systems
are often used in networks for caching purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon collection of more network measurements, OONI continues to develop its data
analysis heuristics, based on which it attempts to accurately identify
censorship events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;acknowledgement-of-limitations:20a1d265084b89cbc4dcb05bd7ab9a38&#34;&gt;Acknowledgement of limitations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The findings of this study present various limitations, and do not necessarily
reflect a comprehensive view of internet censorship in Ethiopia on a nationwide
level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first limitation is associated with the testing period, which started on
15th June 2016 and concluded on 7th October 2016, prior to the declaration of
Ethiopia’s state of emergency. Therefore, censorship events which may have
occurred before and/or after the testing period (such as the reported mobile
internet shutdown in October 2016) were not examined as part of this study.
Furthermore, security challenges for people conducting OONI tests in Ethiopia
limited our ability to perform daily measurements and tests were inevitably run
quite sporadically across the testing period. As such, censorship events that
may have occurred on days that tests were not run might not be included as part
of this study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though measurements were collected from Ethio Telecom, which is Ethiopia’s
main telecommunications service provider, the findings of this study do not
necessarily apply on a nationwide level. Ethio Telecom might have applied
censorship in some locations of Ethiopia, while not in others. Given that OONI
software tests were run from the same location across the testing period, we
cannot know with certainty whether the censorship events found through this
study apply on a nationwide level or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another limitation is associated to the types of URLs that were tested as part
of this study. As mentioned in the methodology section of this report (“Test
lists”), the criteria for selecting URLs that are relevant to Ethiopia presented
bias. While a total of 1,403 different URLs were tested for censorship as part
of this study, not all the URLs on the internet were tested, indicating the
possibility that other websites not included in test lists might have been
blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the data analysis heuristics as part of this study also present
limitations. This is due to the fact that many false positives almost inevitably
emerge within the collected measurement data, limiting our ability to confirm
censorship events with confidence, especially when block pages are not present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warm thanks to Girma Walabuma who took considerable security risks to perform
OONI network measurement tests in Ethiopia for this study, and to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opentech.fund/&#34;&gt;Open Technology Fund&lt;/a&gt; for funding OONI&amp;rsquo;s work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Egypt: Media censorship, Tor interference, HTTPS throttling and ads injections?</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/egypt-network-interference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/egypt-network-interference/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Country:&lt;/strong&gt; Egypt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Probed ISPs:&lt;/strong&gt; Noor (AS 20928), TE Data (AS 8452), Vodafone (AS 24835)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Censorship method:&lt;/strong&gt; DPI, network throttling, TCP injections&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OONI tests:&lt;/strong&gt; HTTP Requests, Web Connectivity, Vanilla Tor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measurement period:&lt;/strong&gt; 2016-08-27 - 2016-10-26&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently noticed network anomalies in Egypt and performed a study in an
attempt to understand the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our findings indicate that the Tor anonymity network appeared to be interfered
with in Egypt, while HTTPS connections to DigitalOcean&amp;rsquo;s Frankfurt data centre
were throttled. We also found that access to porn sites appeared to be
interfered with via in-band TCP packet injections of advertisement and malware
content, and that the blocking of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alaraby.co.uk&#34;&gt;The New Arab&lt;/a&gt;
website led to the blocking of specific content (such as images) of other sites
that are hosted on the same Content Distribution Network (CDN).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below we present our findings based on network measurement tests performed over
the last two months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#media-censorship&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Media censorship&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#collateral-damage&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Collateral damage&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#https-throttling&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;HTTPS throttling&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#inaccessible-urls&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inaccessible URLs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#attempts-to-block-tor&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Attempts to block Tor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#advertisement-and-malware-injection&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Advertisement and malware injection&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#third-party-tools-curl-showing-injected-content&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Third party tools (curl) showing injected content&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#circumventing-censorship&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Circumventing censorship&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#acknowledgements&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#appendix&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Appendix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-name-media-censorship-a-media-censorship:01dc84c43bf59cf55367261531ee7ada&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;media-censorship&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Media censorship&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The New Arab website &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20161025T230118Z_AS36935_N4hRIq4Ya5raRq0yRrW7dRu9yxeg8m7fgbyNrOd9ugt07uQGK0?input=http:%2F%2Fwww.alaraby.co.uk&#34;&gt;www.alaraby.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;
and its mirror website &lt;code&gt;www.alarabyaljadeed.co.uk&lt;/code&gt;
has been blocked in Egypt since 2016-01-05 according to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/media/2016/jan/05/saudi-arabia-uae-egypt-block-access-qatari-news-website&#34;&gt;Guardian&lt;/a&gt;
news outlet. Similarly, the domain
&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20161025T231508Z_AS36935_Cvza90GziUHIFTeK7F5rBLFVIa5nkFKi3X9i3gZ2dpNymzbn69?input=http:%2F%2Fwww.alarabyaljadeed.co.uk&#34;&gt;www.alarabyaljadeed.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;
pointing to the same website (&lt;code&gt;www.alaraby.co.uk&lt;/code&gt;) has also been blocked. The
ISPs have not redirected the visitors to any block page or any resource that
explains the reason of the block. Instead, they appear to have used Deep
Packet Inspection (DPI) equipment to censor the content of the website. When
requesting the HTTP version of the websites &lt;code&gt;http://www.alaraby.co.uk&lt;/code&gt; and
&lt;code&gt;http://www.alarabyaljadeed.co.uk&lt;/code&gt; a response from the middlebox is triggered
containing a blank webpage as is shown by the following two OONI measurements
collected on 25th of October 2016:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20161025T220457Z_AS36935_PqOJazEa6I8BzYZ3NrFVEILGKUaVq6fQ4pM9asTMWaQ3MWzqSz?input=http:%2F%2Fwww.alaraby.co.uk&#34;&gt;Blocking of www.alaraby.co.uk via
HTTP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20161025T231508Z_AS36935_Cvza90GziUHIFTeK7F5rBLFVIa5nkFKi3X9i3gZ2dpNymzbn69?input=http:%2F%2Fwww.alarabyaljadeed.co.uk&#34;&gt;Blocking of www.alarabyaljadeed.co.uk via
HTTP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The request for the HTTPS version of the websites (&lt;code&gt;https://www.alaraby.co.uk&lt;/code&gt;,
&lt;code&gt;https://www.alarabyaljadeed.co.uk&lt;/code&gt;) times out and no response is received, as
shown in the following measurement:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20161025T225008Z_AS36935_3RV6eZcQFuo4GncFinLXtrb1jlMfTSXZPG8xpWOCgWCPf9DreU?input=https:%2F%2Fwww.alaraby.co.uk&#34;&gt;Timing out of requests to www.alaraby.co.uk via
HTTPS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-name-collateral-damage-a-collateral-damage:01dc84c43bf59cf55367261531ee7ada&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;collateral-damage&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Collateral damage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the censorship of the media website The New Arab, this blocking
has caused some collateral damage to other websites hosted on the same Content
Delivery Network (CDN).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The screenshots below illustrate how these websites appeared from an Egyptian
vantage point (right-side) and when accessed via Tor Browser (left-side):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/egypt-network-interference/viagogo-2016-10-21.png&#34; alt=&#34;http://www.viagogo.com&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/egypt-network-interference/megapixl-2016-10-21.png&#34; alt=&#34;https://www.megapixl.com&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/egypt-network-interference/adiglobal-2016-10-21.png&#34; alt=&#34;https://uk-eshop.adiglobal.com/Pages/default.aspx&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-name-https-throttling-a-https-throttling:01dc84c43bf59cf55367261531ee7ada&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;https-throttling&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; HTTPS throttling&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout August 2016 we noticed that HTTPS connections to a number of
services using DigitalOcean&amp;rsquo;s Frankfurt data centre appeared to be presenting
network connectivity issues from two Egyptian vantage points: Noor ADSL
(&lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.ripe.net/AS20928&#34;&gt;AS20928&lt;/a&gt;) and Vodafone Egypt (ex-RAYA
Telecom, &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.ripe.net/AS24835&#34;&gt;AS24835&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of our research we found that one way to consistently reproduce a
network interference is by sending HTTPS requests to the network sub-nets
belonging to DigitalOcean&amp;rsquo;s Frankfurt data center (including, but not limited
to &lt;code&gt;46.101.128.0/24&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;46.101.172.0/24&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;46.101.179.0/24&lt;/code&gt; —
&lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.ripe.net/AS201229&#34;&gt;AS201229&lt;/a&gt;). Our experiment showed consistent
and heavy throttling of HTTPS services located in the network: only 3% of TCP
connection attempts succeeded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our latency analysis suggests that all the packets that the client was
receiving were &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transmission_Control_Protocol#Timeout_based_retransmission&#34;&gt;timeout-based TCP
re-transmissions&lt;/a&gt;
and that a network device was consistently dropping the first occurrence of
each TCP packet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non-encrypted protocols on the other hand, like plain HTTP, which hosted
services in the same sub-nets were not affected. This indicates that only HTTPS
connections were throttled, while insecure HTTP connections to DigitalOcean&amp;rsquo;s
Frankfurt data centre were successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on our tests, the last sample of throttling that we observed occurred on
2016-09-01 12:30 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The complete and detailed technical analysis can be found
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/notebooks/eg-vs-digitalocean.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-name-inaccessible-urls-a-inaccessible-urls:01dc84c43bf59cf55367261531ee7ada&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;inaccessible-urls&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Inaccessible URLs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The HTTPS throttling of services hosted by DigitalOcean&amp;rsquo;s Frankfurt data centre
led to the inaccessibility of various URLs. These include the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20160829T135335Z_AS20928_j3cqNiI8kwkJxby5R3LyH2PnTPgnBJ0rZ3Qx2RClxkQWc9WmOg?input=https:%2F%2F050media.nl&#34;&gt;Blocking of
https://050media.nl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20160829T134302Z_AS20928_I5cYSYTKoHbYLyKtnogYNPLNcdF7T5PkcmxVs4cfR46ifNiq7z?input=https:%2F%2F33-km.ru&#34;&gt;Blocking of
https://33-km.ru&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20160821T211424Z_AS8452_cZllOWSUFhF2WYmiz0KSH54J1mzkeDIqC5hrClLQ593FGGE3M1?input=https:%2F%2Flaracasts.com&#34;&gt;Blocking of
https://laracasts.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as the following URLs: &lt;code&gt;https://antoniomarques.eu&lt;/code&gt;,
&lt;code&gt;https://akombakom.net&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;https://anadoluefessk.org&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;https://alexmerkel.com&lt;/code&gt;,
&lt;code&gt;https://alexmerkel.me&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;https://alexmerkel.xyz&lt;/code&gt;. The raw JSON OONI
measurements file (25Mb size) of these URLs can be found
&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/2016-08-31/20160830T125839Z-EG-AS20928-web_connectivity-no_report_id-0.2.0-probe.json&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above lists however are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; exhaustive and more websites may have been
affected which are not listed here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-name-attempts-to-block-tor-a-attempts-to-block-tor:01dc84c43bf59cf55367261531ee7ada&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;attempts-to-block-tor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Attempts to block Tor&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two days ago, tests were run to examine the reachability of the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt; anonymity network. The collected measurement
data indicates that the Tor process bootstrap was
&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20161026T162218Z_AS36935_kTY80ArJx4baKS9FIss3oPEYfqpzEp0bubESO1T0aEc3Njl3QU&#34;&gt;disrupted&lt;/a&gt;
by blocking requests to directory authorities, which are designed to help Tor
clients learn the list of relays that make up the Tor network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the requests that were found to be blocked is a request to download a
&amp;ldquo;consensus&amp;rdquo; document from Tor directory authorities. That request is a plain
HTTP request to the URL:
&lt;code&gt;http://154.35.175.225/tor/status-vote/current/consensus.z&lt;/code&gt; from a networking
point of view. Connections to directory authorities are intercepted and
blocking is performed by injecting a packet that terminates the connection
abruptly (a TCP RST packet). This happens right after the server acknowledges
the request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The injected RST packets share the same static &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPv4#Identification&#34;&gt;IP identification (IP ID)&lt;/a&gt; value of &lt;code&gt;0x3412&lt;/code&gt; as the
injected RST packets used to block aforementioned websites that we have found to be
blocked. Usage of the same IP ID implies that the blocking infrastructure used
to censor Tor is the same (or similar) to that used to block other websites
(see the in depth &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/notebooks/eg-serving-malware.html&#34;&gt;technical analysis&lt;/a&gt; of
in-band TCP content injections).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our testing we found &lt;strong&gt;7 out of 9 directory authority&lt;/strong&gt; consensus file requests
to be blocked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20161026T205703Z_AS36935_OyfZ1mzzY4xuh8S3abKAfvxcwWGh5JVHUCk55e8cInkOyRmw5U?input=http:%2F%2F128.31.0.39:9131%2Ftor%2Fstatus-vote%2Fcurrent%2Fconsensus.z&#34;&gt;Blocking of consensus document requests to the moria1 directory
authority&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20161026T210514Z_AS36935_3tNJySRXLDwSXijucIltcrFYoKt8KzfrYc2eYdSyO2cxTBs3k5?input=http:%2F%2F171.25.193.9:443%2Ftor%2Fstatus-vote%2Fcurrent%2Fconsensus.z&#34;&gt;Blocking of consensus document requests to the maatuska directory
authority&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20161026T210714Z_AS36935_w88LJ82yd0rKPiaEFJymNZt3kdusHPnMTuWHMHPWDlGxFQLPde?input=http:%2F%2F86.59.21.38:80%2Ftor%2Fstatus-vote%2Fcurrent%2Fconsensus.z&#34;&gt;Blocking of consensus document requests to the tor26 directory
authority&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20161026T210218Z_AS36935_L18ktGixOxdLtxr9LYxIO0jGwkKkLjvsLDZ1YPOJ2eQL7EhDx4?input=http:%2F%2F194.109.206.212:80%2Ftor%2Fstatus-vote%2Fcurrent%2Fconsensus.z&#34;&gt;Blocking of consensus document requests to the dizum directory
authority&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20161026T210811Z_AS36935_Co624cXxizzgIzXOEV1Cx44SCElOMjLHrGML838zycImudosLR?input=http:%2F%2F131.188.40.189:80%2Ftor%2Fstatus-vote%2Fcurrent%2Fconsensus.z&#34;&gt;Blocking of consensus document requests to the gabelmoo directory
authority&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20161026T210434Z_AS36935_so2ZaGOjUdgGNJM7gjyALCyycGDS3v3r5SWoVgPdna7GstFit5?input=http:%2F%2F193.23.244.244:80%2Ftor%2Fstatus-vote%2Fcurrent%2Fconsensus.z&#34;&gt;Blocking of consensus document requests to the dannenberg directory
authority&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20161026T210524Z_AS36935_OfwC8F4e16wN6RjbZCSl6dveF0XRL2UnsygTeXSMFlDBRwB3bw?input=http:%2F%2F154.35.175.225:80%2Ftor%2Fstatus-vote%2Fcurrent%2Fconsensus.z&#34;&gt;Blocking of consensus document requests to the Faravahar directory
authority&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also found access to the now discontinued Tor &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20161026T210826Z_AS36935_Y1ON5xUx0alU1OMrDIMwix8FpjyFs5OUXsbPZWaK6PrCqKpMpW?input=http:%2F%2F208.83.223.34:443%2Ftor%2Fstatus-vote%2Fcurrent%2Fconsensus.z&#34;&gt;directory authority urras to
be blocked&lt;/a&gt;
.We did not test the accessibility of the recently added &lt;code&gt;Bitfroest&lt;/code&gt; Tor
directory authority, nor do we have samples regarding the potential blocking of
&lt;code&gt;longclaw&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, it&amp;rsquo;s just the set of consensus URLs that are blocked, for example, the
request for &lt;code&gt;/tor/status-vote/current/lack-of-consensus.z&lt;/code&gt; produces ordinary
&lt;code&gt;404 Not found&lt;/code&gt; error. That implies that the blockage is explicitly targeting
Tor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another type of request that is blocked is the Onion Router handshake sent to
ORPort of the well-known Tor router. They appear to be blocked in the same way:
the TCP connection is interrupted by terminating the connection (with a TCP RST
packet) during the TLS handshake (after the first &lt;code&gt;Client Hello&lt;/code&gt; from the
client).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blocking appears to only be targeting Tor in a default configuration. This
means that it&amp;rsquo;s possible to easily circumvent such censorship by using any
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bridges.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor Bridge&lt;/a&gt;, including non-obfuscated ones.
Given the fact that the blocking of connections doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen all the time, a
client should be able to bootstrap a Tor connection successfully with enough
retries. This however can, in some cases, take up to a half an hour.
Moreover, OR connections are only blocked to some subset of the public Tor
network, meaning that if a client has already bootstrapped and has a cached
version of the consensus and descriptors it is likely to work properly. The
connection is not throttled as soon as it is established successfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sort of Tor blockage seems to &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; be active in the moment of the
publication of this report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is not the first time we noticed interference with the Tor network in
Egypt. Earlier this month, users reported that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t connect directly
to Tor from Egypt and had to use bridges to access it. Tor Metrics statistics
illustrate that &lt;a href=&#34;https://metrics.torproject.org/userstats-relay-country.html?start=2016-09-19&amp;amp;end=2016-10-26&amp;amp;country=eg&amp;amp;events=points&#34;&gt;direct
connections&lt;/a&gt;
to Tor were reduced on 2nd and 25th October 2016, while the use of
&lt;a href=&#34;https://metrics.torproject.org/userstats-bridge-country.html?start=2016-09-19&amp;amp;end=2016-10-26&amp;amp;country=eg&#34;&gt;bridges&lt;/a&gt;
increased, indicating that Tor might have been blocked. It&amp;rsquo;s probably worth
noting though that only around 30% of Tor users appear to have used bridges to
circumvent potential censorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following graphs below illustrate the estimated number of
directly-connecting clients and the estimated number of clients connecting via
bridges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/egypt-network-interference/userstats-relay-country-eg-2016-09-19-2016-10-26-points.png&#34; alt=&#34;Directly connecting users from Egypt&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/egypt-network-interference/userstats-bridge-country-eg-2016-09-19-2016-10-26.png&#34; alt=&#34;Bridge users from Egypt&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-name-advertisement-and-malware-injection-a-advertisement-and-malware-injection:01dc84c43bf59cf55367261531ee7ada&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;advertisement-and-malware-injection&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Advertisement and malware injection&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through our research we found false content deliberately injected by at least
one ISP in Egypt: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TE_Data&#34;&gt;TE Data&lt;/a&gt;. This ISP
accounts for 65% of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.igmena.org/Indicators-of-Internet-Penetration-in-Egypt&#34;&gt;market
share&lt;/a&gt; and
controls over 70% of the Egyptian internet bandwidth TE Data appears to be
using DPI or similar network equipment to conduct a man-in-the-middle attack
and transparently inject content for gaining profit (affiliate advertising) or
malicious purposes (serving malware).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our experiment showed that there was a 10% probability that mobile device users
connected via Wi-Fi to TE Data ADSL would get redirected when visiting some
porn websites. The redirection injected the URL
&lt;code&gt;http://marketing-sv.com/mads.html&lt;/code&gt;, which serves at least two different static
web-pages redirecting to &lt;code&gt;http://go.ad2upapp.com/afu.php?id=788146&lt;/code&gt; either
directly or via static pages from &lt;code&gt;utextads.com&lt;/code&gt; subdomains. This
PopUp/PopUnder advertisement network is known to be used by malware authors to
gain revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our October 2016 investigation the injector was mostly targeting mobile
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_agent&#34;&gt;User-Agents&lt;/a&gt;. It was not limited to
iPhone and Android platforms, but also targeted BlackBerry and Symbian devices.
In August 2016 ooniprobe also &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/measurement/20160827T153815Z_AS8452_gAU19jWom21aUc0hwieYQymbvcuTTTYULW8k1W1UXOlEYmhDPq?input=http:%2F%2Fxnxx.com&#34;&gt;captured a similar
injection&lt;/a&gt;
in the TE Data network. The injection was redirecting the user to
&lt;code&gt;http://go.ad2upapp.com/afu.php?id=723454&lt;/code&gt; that further redirects to
&lt;code&gt;http://go.deliverymodo.com/afu.php?id=723454&lt;/code&gt;, a different advertising website
but with the same affiliate ID (723454). We also received user complains about
similar injections in transit traffic of Vodafone 3G
(&lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.ripe.net/AS36935&#34;&gt;AS36935&lt;/a&gt;) and Noor ADSL
(&lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.ripe.net/AS20928&#34;&gt;AS20928&lt;/a&gt;) pointing to the
&lt;code&gt;http://adf.ly/1cqbTY&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;marketing-sv.com&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;infinitiads.com&lt;/code&gt; domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also discovered at least one &lt;a href=&#34;https://virustotal.com/en/file/988f3b1079b7badb27442bd1439f1b7b51c9f812a27fbab7e4d60a37c97f3d64/analysis/&#34;&gt;malware
sample&lt;/a&gt;
served by the chain of web redirects starting with the aforementioned link
during our research. Our IP TTL and network packet latency analysis confirms
that the injection is done in-band using a DPI or similar network equipment to
conduct a man-in-the-middle attack. The analysis refutes the hypothesis of an
&amp;ldquo;infected&amp;rdquo; website serving advertisements instead of content. The statistics
suggest that the injector is located within the TE Data network (not further
than that and not as close as end-user LAN) and transparently injects content
for gaining profit via affiliate advertising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Client &amp;lt;--(forged packet)-- ISP&#39;s middle box &amp;lt;--(valid packet)-- Web server&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-name-third-party-tools-curl-showing-injected-content-a-third-party-tools-curl-showing-injected-content:01dc84c43bf59cf55367261531ee7ada&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;third-party-tools-curl-showing-injected-content&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Third party tools (curl) showing injected content&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The curl output excerpts below illustrate how TE Data and Noor ISP redirected
users&amp;rsquo; connections to porn websites through the injection of ads. It&amp;rsquo;s
important though to note that the DNS query answers of the requested domains
are legitimate, and there appears to be no sign of DNS tampering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TE Data ISP redirected the user visiting &lt;code&gt;http://xnxx.com/&lt;/code&gt; (34th most visited
website in Egypt according to Alexa statistics) to
&lt;code&gt;http://go.ad2upapp.com/afu.php?id=723454&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTTP headers curl output &lt;code&gt;http://xnxx.com/&lt;/code&gt; in Noor ISP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;* Rebuilt URL to: http://xnxx.com/
* Hostname was NOT found in DNS cache
*   Trying 141.0.174.38...
* Connected to xnxx.com (141.0.174.38) port 80 (#0)
&amp;gt; HEAD / HTTP/1.1
&amp;gt; User-Agent: curl/7.35.0
&amp;gt; Host: xnxx.com
&amp;gt; Accept: */*
&amp;gt;
&amp;lt; HTTP/1.1 307 Temporary Redirect
&amp;lt; Location: http://go.ad2upapp.com/afu.php?id=723454
&amp;lt; Connection: close
&amp;lt;
* Closing connection 0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noor ISP redirected the user visiting &lt;code&gt;http://xhamster.com/&lt;/code&gt; (53th most visited
website in Egypt according to Alexa statistics) to &lt;code&gt;http://adf.ly/1cqbTY&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTTP headers curl output of &lt;code&gt;http://xhamster.com/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;*   Trying 88.208.18.30...
* Connected to xhamster.com (88.208.18.30) port 80 (#0)
&amp;gt; HEAD / HTTP/1.1
&amp;gt; Host: xhamster.com
&amp;gt; User-Agent: curl/7.47.0
&amp;gt; Accept: */*
&amp;gt;
&amp;lt; HTTP/1.1 307 Temporary Redirect
&amp;lt; Location: http://adf.ly/1cqbTY
&amp;lt; Connection: close
&amp;lt;
* Closing connection 0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The complete and detailed technical analysis of the injected malware and
advertisements in TCP connections can be found
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/notebooks/eg-serving-malware.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-name-circumventing-censorship-a-circumventing-censorship:01dc84c43bf59cf55367261531ee7ada&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;circumventing-censorship&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Circumventing censorship&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI findings in Egypt revealed the censorship of a media website, blocking of
services and malicious TCP injections of advertisements and malware content.
ISPs in Egypt appear to be using DPI, TCP injections and network throttling to
block resources, censor websites and serve advertisements and malware to
internet users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can bypass such censorship through the use of
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser.html.en&#34;&gt;Tor
Browser&lt;/a&gt;. Users in
mobile networks can use
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/docs/android.html.en&#34;&gt;Orbot&lt;/a&gt; (Tor on Android) to
access the web or other mobile applications by using the VPN mode of Orbot
which enables all apps on the device to run through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor
network&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-name-acknowledgements-a-acknowledgements:01dc84c43bf59cf55367261531ee7ada&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;acknowledgements&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Acknowledgements&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI would like to thank anonymous contributors that reported and shared
evidence to document these incidents including, but not limited to, the
cypherpunk who asked to be identified by the following hashsum:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;KCB3XJW2ZVGS2A6MQKIE4NQCMJNFKIXI4KGK6CW4J2OFXFZE6RB5VB35LTLJKMM6ZQ654W57C7JLFWJBHMFH6UNO4CXIK7APUD3H33Y=
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-name-appendix-a-appendix:01dc84c43bf59cf55367261531ee7ada&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;appendix&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Appendix&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Detailed technical analysis:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/notebooks/eg-vs-digitalocean.html&#34;&gt;Egypt vs DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/notebooks/eg-vs-digitalocean.ipynb&#34;&gt;download ipynb
notebook&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/notebooks/eg-serving-malware.html&#34;&gt;Egypt serving malware&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/notebooks/eg-serving-malware.ipynb&#34;&gt;download ipynb
notebook&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EEEP and Greek Internet censorship</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/eeep-greek-censorship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/eeep-greek-censorship/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Country:&lt;/strong&gt; Greece&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Probed ISPs:&lt;/strong&gt; Forthnet, Ote, Cyta, Wind, Vodafone, Cosmote, Wind mobile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blocking methods:&lt;/strong&gt; DPI, DNS Hijacking, HTTP proxy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measurement period:&lt;/strong&gt; June - July 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19:40 UTC Saturday, 17 June 2016&lt;/strong&gt; Update: Add AS numbers of the ISPs, update
raw measurement data URLs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The newly formed Independent Administrative Authority&amp;rsquo;s Hellenic Gaming
Commission acts as the public body responsible for the control and supervision
of gambling services in Greece and published a blacklist of websites that are
offering unlicensed gambling and betting services to Greek internet users.
According to article 52, law No. &lt;sup&gt;4002&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2011&lt;/sub&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://nomoi.info/%CE%A6%CE%95%CE%9A-%CE%91-180-2011-%CF%83%CE%B5%CE%BB-44.html&#34;&gt;A180&lt;/a&gt; unlicensed
gambling and betting websites without a license in Greece is a serious criminal
offense applying as well for users (players), companies and ISPs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most Greek ISPs have not issued any public report that notifies their
customers/users warning them about the content being blocked by the EEEP
blacklist.
Apart from that there is no documentation on how they have implemented the
block/censorship, if they keep track of people trying to access these blocked
websites, as the law orders, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this technical report we have used the blacklist issued by the Hellenic
Gaming Commission &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/images/Anakoinoseis/BlackList_EEEP_%2021022014.pdf&#34;&gt;EEEP&lt;/a&gt;, titled &amp;ldquo;List of sites providing
gaming and betting services without authorisation in Greece&amp;rdquo;. The collection of
the reports took place during June and July 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main test specifications used to probe the blacklist are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;http-requests-test:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitweb.torproject.org/ooni-probe.git/tree/ooni/nettests/blocking/http_requests.py&#34;&gt;HTTP Requests test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This test performs an HTTP GET request from a specified URL list of potential blocked
websites over the test network (censored network) and over Tor. It then compares
the response headers and checks if the two responses (the one over Tor and the one
over the censored network) match and if the proportion between the expected body
length matches. In our test cases we have used a proportion with a tolerance
factor of 80% between the two body lengths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default the HTTP User Agent is chosen at random and is different between the
control request and the experiment request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since version 0.2.3 the User Agent is chosen at random, but is the same between
the control request and the experiment request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user agent is chosen amongst this set of possible user agents:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; en-US; rv:1.9.1.7) Gecko/20091221 Firefox/3.5.7&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;Mozilla/5.0 (iPhone; U; CPU iPhone OS 3 1 2 like Mac OS X; en-us) AppleWebKit/528.18 (KHTML, like Gecko) Mobile/7D11&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 6.1; en-US; rv:1.9.2) Gecko/20100115 irefox/3.6&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; en-US; rv:1.9.2) Gecko/20100115 Firefox/3.6&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; en-US; rv:1.9.2) Gecko/20100115 Firefox/3.6&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; de; rv:1.9.2) Gecko/20100115 Firefox/3.6&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 6.1; de; rv:1.9.2) Gecko/20100115 Firefox/3.6&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; de; rv:1.9.2) Gecko/20100115 Firefox/3.6&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 6.1; en-US; rv:1.9.1.7) Gecko/20091221 Firefox/3.5.7&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; de; rv:1.9.1.7) Gecko/20091221 Firefox/3.5.7 (.NET CLR 3.5.30729)&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These user agents are taken from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://panopticlick.eff.org/browser-uniqueness.pdf&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;How Unique Is Your Web
Browser?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; paper as the
browser user agents with largest anonymity set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dns-consistency-test:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitweb.torproject.org/ooni-probe.git/tree/ooni/nettests/blocking/dns_consistency.py&#34;&gt;DNS consistency test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This test performs an A DNS query (via UDP) to the control resolver. The answer
to such query is called the control answer. For each DNS resolver to be tested
the test performs an A DNS query for the domain in question. This answer
(experiment answer) is compared with the control answer. If the two have a
common IPv4 address then the result for the given hostname and resolver
combination is considered consistent (or not tampered) with the control
resolver (tampering: False).
If they do not have commonalities the test does a reverse lookup of the first
IPv4 address in the control answer and the first IPv4 address in the experiment
answer. If the two reverse lookups match (the PTR record points to the same
hostname), then censorship is probably not happening (tampering:
&amp;ldquo;reverse_match&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any other case the result is marked as: &lt;code&gt;tampering: True&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;probed-isps:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Probed ISPs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probed ISPs: &lt;code&gt;Forthnet (AS 1241), Ote (AS 6799), Cyta (AS 6866), Wind (AS
25472), Vodafone (AS 12361), Cosmote (AS 29247), Wind mobile (AS 15617)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the tested ISPs employed &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DNS_hijacking&#34;&gt;DNS hijacking&lt;/a&gt; with the exception of Vodafone
that uses also &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_packet_inspection&#34;&gt;Deep Packet Inspection&lt;/a&gt; to block the resources of the blacklist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;per-isp-analysis:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Per ISP analysis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/eeep-greek-censorship/eeep_blocking_per_isp.png&#34; alt=&#34;Blocking per ISP&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;forthnet:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Forthnet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ISP has blocked 96 entries (21.91%) of the published &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/images/Anakoinoseis/BlackList_EEEP_%2021022014.pdf&#34;&gt;blacklist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from HTTP request test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;body_length_match: false
body_proportion: 0.0
control_failure: null
experiment_failure: null
factor: 0.8
headers_diff: !!set {Cache-Control: null, Content-Type: null, Date: null,
Expires: null,
  Location: null, Pragma: null, Set-Cookie: null, Vary: null}
headers_match: false
input: http://betguardian.me/
requests:
- request:
    body: null
    headers:
    - - User-Agent
      - [&#39;Mozilla/5.0 (iPhone; U; CPU iPhone OS 3 1 2 like Mac OS X; en-us)
        AppleWebKit/528.18
          (KHTML, like Gecko) Mobile/7D11&#39;]
    method: GET
    tor: {is_tor: false}
    url: http://betguardian.me/
  response:
    body: &#39;&#39;
    code: 302
    headers:
    - - Connection
      - [close]
    - - Location
      - [&#39;http://eeep.forthnetgroup.gr/&#39;]
    - - Content-Length
      - [&#39;0&#39;]
    - - Server
      - [BigIP]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from DNS Consistency test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;control_resolver: 64.9.225.221:57004
input: betguardian.me
queries:
- addrs: [109.68.33.64]
  answers:
  - [&amp;lt;RR name=betguardian.me type=A class=IN ttl=2407s auth=False&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;A
    address=109.68.33.64
      ttl=2407&amp;gt;]
  query: &#39;[Query(&#39;&#39;betguardian.me&#39;&#39;, 1, 1)]&#39;
  query_type: A
  resolver: &amp;amp;id002 [64.9.225.221, 57004]
- addrs: [62.1.46.55]
  answers:
  - [&amp;lt;RR name=betguardian.me type=A class=IN ttl=3600s auth=True&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;A
    address=62.1.46.55
      ttl=3600&amp;gt;]
  query: &#39;[Query(&#39;&#39;betguardian.me&#39;&#39;, 1, 1)]&#39;
  query_type: A
  resolver: &amp;amp;id001 [192.168.122.1, 53]
- addrs: [eeep.forthnet.gr]
  answers:
  - [&amp;lt;RR name=55.46.1.62.in-addr.arpa type=PTR class=IN ttl=86396s auth=False&amp;gt;,
    &amp;lt;PTR
      name=eeep.forthnet.gr ttl=86396&amp;gt;]
  query: &#39;[Query(&#39;&#39;55.46.1.62.in-addr.arpa&#39;&#39;, 12, 1)]&#39;
  query_type: PTR
  resolver: *id001
- query: &#39;[Query(&#39;&#39;64.33.68.109.in-addr.arpa&#39;&#39;, 12, 1)]&#39;
  query_type: PTR
  resolver: *id002
tampering: {192.168.122.1: true}
test_resolvers: [192.168.122.1]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A screenshot from the blocked website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/eeep-greek-censorship/eeep_forthnetgroup_gr.png&#34; alt=&#34;Forthnet EEEP Blocked website screenshot&#34; title=&#34;Forthnet EEEP Blocked website screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ote:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Ote&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from HTTP request test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;body_length_match: false
body_proportion: 0.13907389787503965
control_failure: null
experiment_failure: null
factor: 0.8
headers_diff: !!set {Accept-Ranges: null, Cache-Control: null, ETag: null,
Expires: null,
  Last-Modified: null, Pragma: null, Set-Cookie: null, Vary: null}
headers_match: false
input: http://betguardian.me/
requests:
- request:
    body: null
    headers:
    - - User-Agent
      - [&#39;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 6.1; de; rv:1.9.2) Gecko/20100115
        Firefox/3.6&#39;]
    method: GET
    tor: {is_tor: false}
    url: http://betguardian.me/
  response:
    body: &amp;quot;\uFEFF&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC \&amp;quot;-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0
Transitional//EN\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\
      \n&amp;lt;HTML&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;HEAD&amp;gt;\r\n &amp;lt;META content=\&amp;quot;IE=5.0000\&amp;quot;
http-equiv=\&amp;quot;X-UA-Compatible\&amp;quot;\
      &amp;gt;\r\n &amp;lt;TITLE&amp;gt;\u039C\u03AE
      &amp;gt;\u0395\u03C0\u03B9\u03C4\u03C1\u03B5\u03C0\u03C4\u03AE\
      \ \u03A0\u03C1\u03CC\u03C3\u03B2\u03B1\u03C3\u03B7&amp;lt;/TITLE&amp;gt; \r\n&amp;lt;META
http-equiv=\&amp;quot;\
      Content-Type\&amp;quot; content=\&amp;quot;text/html; charset=iso-8859-7\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;LINK
href=\&amp;quot;files/styles.css\&amp;quot;\
      \ rel=\&amp;quot;stylesheet\&amp;quot; type=\&amp;quot;text/css\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/HEAD&amp;gt; \r\n&amp;lt;BODY
text=\&amp;quot;#000000\&amp;quot;\
      \ topmargin=\&amp;quot;0\&amp;quot; leftmargin=\&amp;quot;0\&amp;quot; bgcolor=\&amp;quot;#eeeeee\&amp;quot; marginheight=&#39;0\&amp;quot;&#39;
marginwidth=\&amp;quot;\
      0\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;TABLE width=\&amp;quot;100%\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;100%\&amp;quot; border=\&amp;quot;0\&amp;quot;
cellspacing=\&amp;quot;0\&amp;quot;\
      \ cellpadding=\&amp;quot;0\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n  &amp;lt;TBODY&amp;gt;\r\n  &amp;lt;TR&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;TD align=\&amp;quot;center\&amp;quot;
valign=\&amp;quot;\
      top\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;\r\n      &amp;lt;TABLE width=\&amp;quot;700\&amp;quot; style=\&amp;quot;border: 2px solid
rgb(202,\
      \ 202, 202);\&amp;quot; \r\n      cellspacing=\&amp;quot;0\&amp;quot; cellpadding=\&amp;quot;0\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n
&amp;lt;TBODY&amp;gt;\r\
      \n        &amp;lt;TR&amp;gt;\r\n          &amp;lt;TD&amp;gt;\r\n            &amp;lt;TABLE width=\&amp;quot;100%\&amp;quot;
border=\&amp;quot;\
      0\&amp;quot; cellspacing=\&amp;quot;0\&amp;quot; cellpadding=\&amp;quot;0\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n              &amp;lt;TBODY&amp;gt;\r\n
\
      \        &amp;lt;TR&amp;gt;\r\n                &amp;lt;TD width=\&amp;quot;650\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;70\&amp;quot;
align=\&amp;quot;center\&amp;quot;\
      \ background=\&amp;quot;files/BackHeader.gif\&amp;quot; valign=\&amp;quot;middle\&amp;quot; colspan=3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;FONT
class=\&amp;quot;\
      blueTitle\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\u039C\u0397
\u0395\u03A0\u0399\u03A4\u03A1\u0395\u03A0\u03A4\u0397\
      \
\u03A0\u03A1\u039F\u03A3\u0392\u0391\u03A3\u0397&amp;lt;/FONT&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TD&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TR&amp;gt;\r\n\
      \              &amp;lt;TR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TR&amp;gt;\r\n              &amp;lt;TR&amp;gt;\r\n                &amp;lt;TD
align=\&amp;quot;\
      left\&amp;quot; background=\&amp;quot;files/BackLeft.jpg\&amp;quot; valign=\&amp;quot;bottom\&amp;quot;
style=\&amp;quot;background-position:\
      \ left bottom; background-repeat: no-repeat;\&amp;quot; bgcolor=\&amp;quot;#ffffff\&amp;quot;
colspan=\&amp;quot;\
      2\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n                  &amp;lt;CENTER&amp;gt;\r\n                  &amp;lt;TABLE&amp;gt;\r\n
\
      \            &amp;lt;TBODY&amp;gt;\r\n                    &amp;lt;TR&amp;gt;\r\n
&amp;lt;TD&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;lt;/TD&amp;gt;\r\
      \n                      &amp;lt;TD&amp;gt;&amp;lt;FONT
class=\&amp;quot;blue\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;\u039C\u03B5\
      \ \u03B2\u03AC\u03C3\u03B7 \u03B1\u03C0\u03CC\u03C6\u03B1\u03C3\u03B7
\u03C4\
      \u03B7\u03C2
\u03B1\u03BD\u03B5\u03BE\u03AC\u03C1\u03C4\u03B7\u03C4\u03B7\u03C2\
      \ \u03B4\u03B9\u03BF\u03B9\u03BA\u03B7\u03C4\u03B9\u03BA\u03AE\u03C2
\u03B1\u03C1\
      \u03C7\u03AE\u03C2 \&amp;quot;\u0395\u03C0\u03B9\u03C4\u03C1\u03BF\u03C0\u03AE
\u0395\
      \u03C0\u03BF\u03C0\u03C4\u03B5\u03AF\u03B1\u03C2 \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9
\u0395\u03BB\
      \u03AD\u03B3\u03C7\u03BF\u03C5
\u03A0\u03B1\u03B9\u03B3\u03BD\u03AF\u03C9\u03BD\
      \&amp;quot; (\u0395.\u0395.\u0395.\u03A0.), \u03BF
\u03B9\u03C3\u03C4\u03CC\u03C4\u03BF\
      \u03C0\u03BF\u03C2 \u03C0\u03BF\u03C5
\u03B5\u03C0\u03B9\u03C7\u03B5\u03B9\u03C1\
      \u03B5\u03AF\u03C4\u03B5 \u03BD\u03B1
\u03B5\u03C0\u03B9\u03C3\u03BA\u03B5\u03C6\
      \u03B8\u03B5\u03AF\u03C4\u03B5 \u03AD\u03C7\u03B5\u03B9
\u03B5\u03B3\u03B3\u03C1\
      \u03B1\u03C6\u03B5\u03AF \u03C3\u03C4\u03BF\u03BD
\u03BA\u03B1\u03C4\u03AC\u03BB\
      \u03BF\u03B3\u03BF \u03B5\u03BA\u03B5\u03AF\u03BD\u03C9\u03BD
\u03C0\u03BF\u03C5\
      \ \u03C0\u03C1\u03BF\u03C3\u03C6\u03AD\u03C1\u03BF\u03C5\u03BD
\u03C5\u03C0\u03B7\
      \u03C1\u03B5\u03C3\u03AF\u03B5\u03C2
\u03C4\u03C5\u03C7\u03B5\u03C1\u03CE\u03BD\
      \ \u03C0\u03B1\u03B9\u03B3\u03BD\u03AF\u03C9\u03BD \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9
\u03C3\
      \u03C4\u03BF\u03B9\u03C7\u03B7\u03BC\u03AC\u03C4\u03C9\u03BD
\u03C7\u03C9\u03C1\
      \u03AF\u03C2
\u03AC\u03B4\u03B5\u03B9\u03B1.\r\n\t\t\t&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;\u039A\u03B1\u03C4\
      \u03AC \u03C3\u03C5\u03BD\u03AD\u03C0\u03B5\u03B9\u03B1, \u03BC\u03B5
\u03B2\
      \u03AC\u03C3\u03B7 \u03C4\u03B7\u03BD
\u03BA\u03B5\u03AF\u03BC\u03B5\u03BD\u03B7\
      \ \u03BD\u03BF\u03BC\u03BF\u03B8\u03B5\u03C3\u03AF\u03B1, \u03B7
\u03C0\u03C1\
      \u03CC\u03C3\u03B2\u03B1\u03C3\u03B7 \u03C3\u03C4\u03BF\u03BD
\u03B9\u03C3\u03C4\
      \u03CC\u03C4\u03BF\u03C0\u03BF \u03B1\u03C5\u03C4\u03CC
\u03B4\u03B5\u03BD \u03B5\
      \u03C0\u03B9\u03C4\u03C1\u03AD\u03C0\u03B5\u03C4\u03B1\u03B9.\r\n\t\t\t&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;\u0393\
      \u03B9\u03B1
\u03C0\u03B5\u03C1\u03B9\u03C3\u03C3\u03CC\u03C4\u03B5\u03C1\u03B5\
  \u03C2 \u03C0\u03BB\u03B7\u03C1\u03BF\u03C6\u03BF\u03C1\u03AF\u03B5\u03C2:
&amp;lt;a\
      \
href=\&amp;quot;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/index.php/el/\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/index.php/el/&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;\r\
      \n\t\t\t&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/FONT&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TD&amp;gt;\r\n
&amp;lt;TD&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;lt;/TD&amp;gt;\r\
      \n
\t\t&amp;lt;/TR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TBODY&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TABLE&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/CENTER&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TBODY&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TABLE&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TD&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TBODY&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TABLE&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TD&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TBODY&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TABLE&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/BODY&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/HTML&amp;gt;\r\
      \n&amp;quot;
    code: 200
    headers:
    - - Content-Length
      - [&#39;2631&#39;]
    - - Accept-Ranges
      - [bytes]
    - - Server
      - [Apache/2.2.15 (CentOS)]
    - - Last-Modified
      - [&#39;Wed, 07 Aug 2013 11:24:33 GMT&#39;]
    - - Connection
      - [close]
    - - ETag
      - [&#39;&amp;quot;81b85-a47-4e359c92631e1&amp;quot;&#39;]
    - - Date
      - [&#39;Wed, 04 Jun 2014 18:24:16 GMT&#39;]
    - - Content-Type
      - [text/html; charset=UTF-8]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from DNS Consistency test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;input: www.betguardian.me
queries:
- addrs: [109.68.33.64]
  answers:
  - [&amp;lt;RR name=www.betguardian.me type=A class=IN ttl=14399s auth=False&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;A
    address=109.68.33.64
      ttl=14399&amp;gt;]
  query: &#39;[Query(&#39;&#39;www.betguardian.me&#39;&#39;, 1, 1)]&#39;
  query_type: A
  resolver: &amp;amp;id002 [64.9.225.221, 57004]
- addrs: [83.235.64.20]
  answers:
  - [&amp;lt;RR name=www.betguardian.me type=A class=IN ttl=1800s auth=True&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;A
    address=83.235.64.20
      ttl=1800&amp;gt;]
  query: &#39;[Query(&#39;&#39;www.betguardian.me&#39;&#39;, 1, 1)]&#39;
  query_type: A
  resolver: &amp;amp;id001 [192.168.1.1, 53]
- addrs: [eeep.otenet.gr]
  answers:
  - [&amp;lt;RR name=20.64.235.83.in-addr.arpa type=PTR class=IN ttl=86376s
    auth=False&amp;gt;,
    &amp;lt;PTR name=eeep.otenet.gr ttl=86376&amp;gt;]
  query: &#39;[Query(&#39;&#39;20.64.235.83.in-addr.arpa&#39;&#39;, 12, 1)]&#39;
  query_type: PTR
  resolver: *id001
- failure: deferred_timeout_error
  query: &#39;[Query(&#39;&#39;64.33.68.109.in-addr.arpa&#39;&#39;, 12, 1)]&#39;
  query_type: PTR
  resolver: *id002
- failure: deferred_timeout_error
  query: &#39;[Query(&#39;&#39;www.betguardian.me&#39;&#39;, 1, 1)]&#39;
  query_type: A
  resolver: *id002
- addrs: [109.68.33.64]
  answers:
  - [&amp;lt;RR name=www.betguardian.me type=A class=IN ttl=14395s auth=False&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;A
    address=109.68.33.64
      ttl=14395&amp;gt;]
  query: &#39;[Query(&#39;&#39;www.betguardian.me&#39;&#39;, 1, 1)]&#39;
  query_type: A
  resolver: *id002
- addrs: [83.235.64.20]
  answers:
  - [&amp;lt;RR name=www.betguardian.me type=A class=IN ttl=1793s auth=False&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;A
    address=83.235.64.20
      ttl=1793&amp;gt;]
  query: &#39;[Query(&#39;&#39;www.betguardian.me&#39;&#39;, 1, 1)]&#39;
  query_type: A
  resolver: &amp;amp;id003 [192.168.1.1, 53]
- addrs: [eeep.otenet.gr]
  answers:
  - [&amp;lt;RR name=20.64.235.83.in-addr.arpa type=PTR class=IN ttl=86368s
    auth=False&amp;gt;,
    &amp;lt;PTR name=eeep.otenet.gr ttl=86368&amp;gt;]
  query: &#39;[Query(&#39;&#39;20.64.235.83.in-addr.arpa&#39;&#39;, 12, 1)]&#39;
  query_type: PTR
  resolver: *id003
- query: &#39;[Query(&#39;&#39;64.33.68.109.in-addr.arpa&#39;&#39;, 12, 1)]&#39;
  query_type: PTR
  resolver: *id002
tampering: {192.168.1.1: true}
test_resolvers: [192.168.1.1]

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ISP has blocked 438 entries (100%) of the published &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/images/Anakoinoseis/BlackList_EEEP_%2021022014.pdf&#34;&gt;blacklist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A screenshot from the blocked website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/eeep-greek-censorship/eeep_otenet_gr.png&#34; alt=&#34;Ote EEEP Blocked website screenshot&#34; title=&#34;Ote EEEP Blocked website screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cyta:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Cyta&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from HTTP request test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;input: http://betguardian.me/
requests:
- request:
    body: null
    headers:
    - - User-Agent
      - [&#39;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; en-US; rv:1.9.1.7)
        Gecko/20091221
          Firefox/3.5.7&#39;]
    method: GET
    tor: {is_tor: false}
    url: http://betguardian.me/
  response:
    body: &amp;quot;\uFEFF&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC \&amp;quot;-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0
Transitional//EN\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\
      \n&amp;lt;!-- saved from url=(0037)http://www.cyta.gr/misc/eeep_noaccess
--&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE\
      \ html PUBLIC \&amp;quot;-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Strict//EN\&amp;quot;
\&amp;quot;http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd\&amp;quot;\
      &amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;html\r\nlang=\&amp;quot;el\&amp;quot; xmlns=\&amp;quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml\&amp;quot;
      &amp;gt;xmlns:fb=\&amp;quot;\
      http://ogp.me/ns/fb#\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;meta content=\&amp;quot;text/html;
charset=utf-8\&amp;quot;\
      \ http-equiv=\&amp;quot;content-type\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;meta content=\&amp;quot;IE=edge,chrome=1\&amp;quot;
http-equiv=\&amp;quot;\
      X-UA-Compatible\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;\u039C\u03B7
\u03B4\u03C5\u03BD\u03B1\u03C4\
      \u03AE \r\n\u03C0\u03C1\u03CC\u03C3\u03B2\u03B1\u03C3\u03B7&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;\r\n
&amp;lt;meta\
      \ scheme=\&amp;quot;\&amp;quot; name=\&amp;quot;DESCRIPTION\&amp;quot; content=\&amp;quot;cyta\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;meta
scheme=\&amp;quot;\&amp;quot;\
      \ name=\&amp;quot;KEYWORDS\&amp;quot; content=\&amp;quot;cyta\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;meta name=\&amp;quot;viewport\&amp;quot;
content=\&amp;quot;\
      width=device-width,initial-scale=1\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;meta name=\&amp;quot;CODE_LANGUAGE\&amp;quot;
content=\&amp;quot;\
      C#\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;meta name=\&amp;quot;vs_defaultClientScript\&amp;quot;
content=\&amp;quot;JavaScript\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\
      \n    &amp;lt;meta name=\&amp;quot;vs_targetSchema\&amp;quot;
content=\&amp;quot;http://schemas.microsoft.com/intellisense/ie5\&amp;quot;\
      &amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;!-- CSS --&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;link rel=\&amp;quot;stylesheet\&amp;quot; type=\&amp;quot;text/css\&amp;quot;
      &amp;gt;href=\&amp;quot;\
      index_files/style.css\&amp;quot; media=\&amp;quot;all\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;link rel=\&amp;quot;Stylesheet\&amp;quot;
type=\&amp;quot;\
      text/css\&amp;quot; href=\&amp;quot;index_files/forms.css\&amp;quot; media=\&amp;quot;all\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;link
rel=\&amp;quot;\
      stylesheet\&amp;quot; type=\&amp;quot;text/css\&amp;quot; href=\&amp;quot;index_files/print.css\&amp;quot;
media=\&amp;quot;print\&amp;quot;\
      &amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;!--[if lte IE 7]&amp;gt;&amp;lt;link rel=\&amp;quot;stylesheet\&amp;quot;
      &amp;gt;href=\&amp;quot;/css/cyta/ie7.css\&amp;quot;\
      \ type=\&amp;quot;text/css\&amp;quot; media=\&amp;quot;screen, projection\&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;![endif]--&amp;gt;\r\n
&amp;lt;!--\
      \ Icon --&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;link rel=\&amp;quot;shortcut icon\&amp;quot; type=\&amp;quot;image/x-icon\&amp;quot;
href=\&amp;quot;\
      /img/cyta/favicon.ico\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;!-- Js --&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;link
rel=\&amp;quot;stylesheet\&amp;quot;\
      \ type=\&amp;quot;text/css\&amp;quot; href=\&amp;quot;index_files/VisitorIdentification.css\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n
&amp;lt;meta\
      \ name=\&amp;quot;GENERATOR\&amp;quot; content=\&amp;quot;MSHTML
9.00.8112.16496\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;\r\
      \n    &amp;lt;form id=\&amp;quot;mainform\&amp;quot; method=\&amp;quot;post\&amp;quot; name=\&amp;quot;mainform\&amp;quot;
action=\&amp;quot;eeep_noaccess\&amp;quot;\
      &amp;gt;\r\n        &amp;lt;div class=\&amp;quot;wrapper\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n            &amp;lt;div style=\&amp;quot;padding:
      &amp;gt;20px\
      \ 0px 400px;\&amp;quot; class=\&amp;quot;errorpage\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n                &amp;lt;img
src=\&amp;quot;index_files/eeep_noaccess.png\&amp;quot;\
      &amp;gt;\r\n                &amp;lt;h3 style=\&amp;quot;margin-top: 50px;\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\u0394\u03B5\u03BD
      &amp;gt;\u03B5\
      \u03AF\u03BD\u03B1\u03B9 \u03B4\u03C5\u03BD\u03B1\u03C4\u03AE \u03B7
\u03C0\u03C1\
      \u03CC\u03C3\u03B2\u03B1\u03C3\u03B7 \u03C3\u03C4\u03BF\u03BD
\u03B9\u03C3\u03C4\
      \u03CC\u03C4\u03BF\u03C0\u03BF.&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;\r\n                &amp;lt;p
style=\&amp;quot;font-size:\
      \ 14px;\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n                    \u0397
\u03B1\u03C0\u03B1\u03B3\u03CC\u03C1\
      \u03B5\u03C5\u03C3\u03B7 \u03C4\u03B7\u03C2
\u03C0\u03C1\u03CC\u03C3\u03B2\u03B1\
      \u03C3\u03B7\u03C2
\u03B5\u03C0\u03B9\u03B2\u03AC\u03BB\u03BB\u03B5\u03C4\u03B1\
      \u03B9 \u03B1\u03C0\u03CC \u03C4\u03BF \u03BD\u03CC\u03BC\u03BF
\r\n4.002/2011\
      \ \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9 \u03C4\u03B9\u03C2
\u03B1\u03C0\u03BF\u03C6\u03AC\u03C3\
      \u03B5\u03B9\u03C2 \u03C4\u03B7\u03C2
\u0395\u03C0\u03B9\u03C4\u03C1\u03BF\u03C0\
      \u03AE\u03C2 \u0395\u03C0\u03BF\u03C0\u03C4\u03B5\u03AF\u03B1\u03C2
\u03BA\u03B1\
      \u03B9 \u0395\u03BB\u03AD\u03B3\u03C7\u03BF\u03C5
\u03A0\u03B1\u03B9\u03B3\u03BD\
      \u03AF\u03C9\u03BD \r\n(\u0395.\u0395.\u0395.\u03A0.),
\u03C4\u03C5\u03C7\u03CC\
      \u03BD \u03C0\u03B1\u03C1\u03B1\u03B2\u03AF\u03B1\u03C3\u03B7
\u03C4\u03C9\u03BD\
      \ \u03BF\u03C0\u03BF\u03AF\u03C9\u03BD
\u03B5\u03C0\u03B9\u03C3\u03CD\u03C1\u03B5\
      \u03B9 \u03B1\u03C5\u03C3\u03C4\u03B7\u03C1\u03AD\u03C2
\u03B4\u03B9\u03BF\u03B9\
      \u03BA\u03B7\u03C4\u03B9\u03BA\u03AD\u03C2 \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9
\r\n\u03C0\u03BF\
      \u03B9\u03BD\u03B9\u03BA\u03AD\u03C2
\u03BA\u03C5\u03C1\u03CE\u03C3\u03B5\u03B9\
      \u03C2.\r\n                &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;\r\n                &amp;lt;p style=\&amp;quot;font-size:
14px;\&amp;quot;\
      &amp;gt;\r\n                    \u0393\u03B9\u03B1
      &amp;gt;\u03C0\u03B5\u03C1\u03B9\u03C3\u03C3\
      \u03CC\u03C4\u03B5\u03C1\u03B5\u03C2
\u03C0\u03BB\u03B7\u03C1\u03BF\u03C6\u03BF\
      \u03C1\u03AF\u03B5\u03C2
\u03B1\u03C0\u03B5\u03C5\u03B8\u03C5\u03BD\u03B8\u03B5\
      \u03AF\u03C4\u03B5 \u03C3\u03C4\u03B7\u03BD
\r\n\u03B9\u03C3\u03C4\u03BF\u03C3\
      \u03B5\u03BB\u03AF\u03B4\u03B1 \u03C4\u03B7\u03C2
\u0395.\u0395.\u0395.\u03A0\
      .: &amp;lt;a href=\&amp;quot;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/index.php/el/\&amp;quot;
target=\&amp;quot;_blank\&amp;quot;\
      &amp;gt;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/index.php/el/&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;\r\n
      &amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;\r\
      \n            &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;\r\n        &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;/form&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;script&amp;gt;\r\n
\
      \      (function (i, s, o, g, r, a, m) {\r\n
i[&#39;GoogleAnalyticsObject&#39;]\
      \ = r; i[r] = i[r] || function () {\r\n                (i[r].q = i[r].q
|| []).push(arguments)\r\
      \n            }, i[r].l = 1 * new Date(); a = s.createElement(o),\r\n
\
      \      m = s.getElementsByTagName(o)[0]; a.async = 1; a.src = g;
m.parentNode.insertBefore(a,\
      \ m)\r\n        })(window, document, &#39;script&#39;,
&#39;//www.google-analytics.com/analytics.js&#39;,\
      \ &#39;ga&#39;);\r\n\r\n        ga(&#39;create&#39;, &#39;UA-43814796-1&#39;, &#39;cyta.gr&#39;);\r\n
\
\      m = s.getElementsByTagName(o)[0]; a.async = 1; a.src = g;
m.parentNode.insertBefore(a,\
      \ m)\r\n        })(window, document, &#39;script&#39;,
&#39;//www.google-analytics.com/analytics.js&#39;,\
      \ &#39;ga&#39;);\r\n\r\n        ga(&#39;create&#39;, &#39;UA-43814796-1&#39;, &#39;cyta.gr&#39;);\r\n
\
      \  ga(&#39;send&#39;, &#39;pageview&#39;);\r\n    &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&amp;quot;
    code: 200
    headers:
    - - Content-Length
      - [&#39;3429&#39;]
    - - Accept-Ranges
      - [bytes]
    - - Server
      - [Apache]
    - - Last-Modified
      - [&#39;Mon, 09 Sep 2013 12:44:47 GMT&#39;]
    - - Connection
      - [close]
    - - ETag
      - [&#39;&amp;quot;40e99-d65-4e5f2c0d6edc0&amp;quot;&#39;]
    - - Date
      - [&#39;Mon, 23 Jun 2014 16:47:46 GMT&#39;]
    - - Content-Type
      - [text/html; charset=UTF-8]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ISP has blocked 357 entries (81.5%) of the published &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/images/Anakoinoseis/BlackList_EEEP_%2021022014.pdf&#34;&gt;blacklist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A screenshot from the blocked website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/eeep-greek-censorship/eeep_cyta_gr.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cyta EEEP Blocked website screenshot&#34; title=&#34;Cyta EEEP Blocked website screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least 80 entries faulty responded with a 404 HTTP error&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example response of a URL that faulty responded with a 404 error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;agent: agent
body_length_match: false
body_proportion: 0.0
control_failure: null
experiment_failure: null
factor: 0.8
headers_diff: !!set {Content-Type: null, Location: null, Server: null}
headers_match: false
input: http://backgammon.betoto.com/backgammon.aspx
requests:
- request:
    body: null
    headers:
    - - User-Agent
      - [&#39;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; de; rv:1.9.2) Gecko/20100115
        Firefox/3.6&#39;]
    method: GET
    tor: {is_tor: false}
    url: http://backgammon.betoto.com/backgammon.aspx
  response:
    body: &#39;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC &amp;quot;-//IETF//DTD HTML 2.0//EN&amp;quot;&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;404 Not Found&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Not Found&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The requested URL /backgammon.aspx was not found on this server.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;

      &#39;
    code: 404
    headers:
    - - Date
      - [&#39;Mon, 23 Jun 2014 16:47:46 GMT&#39;]
    - - Content-Length
      - [&#39;213&#39;]
    - - Content-Type
      - [text/html; charset=iso-8859-1]
    - - Connection
      - [close]
    - - Server
      - [Apache]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyta introduces a Google Analytics user agent used to
track users that are being redirected on their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cyta.gr/misc/eeep_noaccess&#34;&gt;blocking
webpage&lt;/a&gt;. It is worth mentioning that
Cyta uses a different user agent (UA) tag for user tracking purposes than on
their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cyta.gr&#34;&gt;main website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;wind:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Wind&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from HTTP request test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;input: http://betguardian.me/
requests:
- request:
    body: null
    headers:
    - - User-Agent
      - [&#39;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; en-US; rv:1.9.2)
        Gecko/20100115
          Firefox/3.6&#39;]
    method: GET
    tor: {is_tor: false}
    url: http://betguardian.me/
  response:
    body: &amp;quot;\uFEFF&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC \&amp;quot;-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.01
Transitional//EN\&amp;quot;\r\
      \n\&amp;quot;http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/loose.dtd\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;.:\
      \ \u0391\u03C0\u03B1\u03B3\u03CC\u03C1\u03B5\u03C5\u03C3\u03B7
\u03A0\u03C1\u03CC\
      \u03C3\u03B2\u03B1\u03C3\u03B7\u03C2 :.&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;meta
http-equiv=\&amp;quot;Content-Type\&amp;quot;\
      \ content=\&amp;quot;text/html; charset=UTF-8\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;style
type=\&amp;quot;text/css\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;!--\r\
      \nbody
{\r\n\tpadding:0px;\r\n\tmargin:0px;\r\n\tfont-family:Tahoma;\r\n\tfont-size:11pt;\r\
      \n\tbackground-image:
url(/img/wind_new_bg.jpg);\r\n\tbackground-repeat:repeat-x;\r\
      \n\tbackground-position: center top; \r\n}\r\n\r\na
{\r\n\tcolor:#02578E;\r\n\
      \tcursor: pointer; cursor: hand;\r\n}\r\n\r\nTop
{\r\n\tmargin:0;\r\n\theight:125px;\r\
      \n\twidth:970px;\r\n\tmargin-bottom:20px;\r\n}\r\n\r\nLogo{\r\n\tfloat:left;\r\
      \n\twidth:188px;\r\n}\r\n\r\n.style1 {\r\n\tfont-size:
11pt;\r\n\tfont-weight:\
      \ bold;\r\n}\r\n\r\n.style2 {color: #02578E}\r\n\r\n.main {\r\n\tmargin:
30px\
      \ 10px 10px 20px;\r\n\tpadding:10pt auto;\r\n\tline-spacing:
110%;\r\n\tfont-size:\
      \ 11pt;\r\n\ttext-align:
justify;\r\n}\r\n\r\n.uline{\r\n\ttext-decoration:underline;\r\
      \n\tfont-weight: bold;\r\n}\r\n--&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/style&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;body
class=\&amp;quot;\
      body\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n\t&amp;lt;div class=\&amp;quot;Top\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t&amp;lt;div class=\&amp;quot;Logo\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img
src=\&amp;quot;/img/wind_logo.jpg\&amp;quot;\
      &amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;\r\n\t&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;\r\n\t&amp;lt;div class=\&amp;quot;main\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span
      &amp;gt;class=\&amp;quot;style1\&amp;quot;\
      &amp;gt;\u03A3\u03B7\u03BC\u03B1\u03BD\u03C4\u03B9\u03BA\u03AE
      &amp;gt;\u03B5\u03BD\u03B7\u03BC\
      \u03AD\u03C1\u03C9\u03C3\u03B7:&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;\u039C\u03B5
\u03B2\u03AC\
      \u03C3\u03B7 \u03C4\u03B7\u03BD 65/8/24.7.2013
\u03B1\u03C0\u03CC\u03C6\u03B1\
      \u03C3\u03B7 \u03C4\u03B7\u03C2
&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;\u0395\u03C0\u03B9\u03C4\u03C1\u03BF\
      \u03C0\u03AE\u03C2 \u0395\u03C0\u03BF\u03C0\u03C4\u03B5\u03AF\u03B1\u03C2
\u03BA\
      \u03B1\u03B9 \u0395\u03BB\u03AD\u03B3\u03C7\u03BF\u03C5
\u03A0\u03B1\u03B9\u03B3\
      \u03BD\u03AF\u03C9\u03BD (\u0395.\u0395.\u0395.\u03A0.)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;, \u03BF
\u03B9\
      \u03C3\u03C4\u03CC\u03C4\u03BF\u03C0\u03BF\u03C2 \u03C0\u03BF\u03C5
\u03B5\u03C0\
      \u03B9\u03C7\u03B5\u03B9\u03C1\u03B5\u03AF\u03C4\u03B5 \u03BD\u03B1
\u03B5\u03C0\
      \u03B9\u03C3\u03BA\u03B5\u03C6\u03B8\u03B5\u03AF\u03C4\u03B5
&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;\u03C0\u03C1\
      \u03BF\u03C3\u03C6\u03AD\u03C1\u03B5\u03B9
\u03C5\u03C0\u03B7\u03C1\u03B5\u03C3\
      \u03AF\u03B5\u03C2 \u03C4\u03C5\u03C7\u03B5\u03C1\u03CE\u03BD
\u03C0\u03B1\u03B9\
      \u03B3\u03BD\u03AF\u03C9\u03BD \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9
\u03C3\u03C4\u03BF\u03B9\u03C7\
      \u03B7\u03BC\u03AC\u03C4\u03C9\u03BD &amp;lt;span
class=&#39;uline&#39;&amp;gt;\u03C7\u03C9\u03C1\u03AF\
      \u03C2 \u03AC\u03B4\u03B5\u03B9\u03B1&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;
\u03C3\u03C4\u03B7\u03BD\
      \
\u0395\u03BB\u03BB\u03AC\u03B4\u03B1.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;\u039A\u03B1\u03C4\u03AC\
      \ \u03C3\u03C5\u03BD\u03AD\u03C0\u03B5\u03B9\u03B1, &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;\u03B7
\u03C0\u03C1\
      \u03CC\u03C3\u03B2\u03B1\u03C3\u03B7 \u03C3\u03C4\u03BF\u03BD
\u03B9\u03C3\u03C4\
      \u03CC\u03C4\u03BF\u03C0\u03BF \u03B1\u03C5\u03C4\u03CC
\u03B4\u03B5\u03BD \u03B5\
      \u03AF\u03BD\u03B1\u03B9
\u03B5\u03C0\u03B9\u03C4\u03C1\u03B5\u03C0\u03C4\u03AE\
      &amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;, \u03CC\u03C0\u03C9\u03C2 \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9 \u03C3\u03B5
\u03BA\u03AC\
      \u03B8\u03B5 \u03B9\u03C3\u03C4\u03CC\u03C4\u03BF\u03C0\u03BF
\u03C0\u03BF\u03C5\
      \
\u03C0\u03B5\u03C1\u03B9\u03BB\u03B1\u03BC\u03B2\u03AC\u03BD\u03B5\u03C4\u03B1\
      \u03B9 \u03C3\u03C4\u03BF\u03BD
\u03C3\u03C7\u03B5\u03C4\u03B9\u03BA\u03CC \u03BA\
      \u03B1\u03C4\u03AC\u03BB\u03BF\u03B3\u03BF \u03C4\u03B7\u03C2
\u0395.\u0395\
      .\u0395.\u03A0.
\u03A0\u03B5\u03C1\u03B9\u03C3\u03C3\u03CC\u03C4\u03B5\u03C1\
      \u03B5\u03C2
\u03BB\u03B5\u03C0\u03C4\u03BF\u03BC\u03AD\u03C1\u03B5\u03B9\u03B5\
      \u03C2 \u03C3\u03C7\u03B5\u03C4\u03B9\u03BA\u03AC \u03BC\u03B5
\u03C4\u03B1\
      \ \u03C0\u03B1\u03C1\u03B1\u03C0\u03AC\u03BD\u03C9
\u03BA\u03B1\u03B8\u03CE\u03C2\
      \ \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9 \u03C4\u03BF\u03BD \u03C0\u03BB\u03AE\u03C1\u03B7
\u03BA\
      \u03B1\u03C4\u03AC\u03BB\u03BF\u03B3\u03BF \u03C4\u03C9\u03BD
\u03B1\u03C0\u03B1\
      \u03B3\u03BF\u03C1\u03B5\u03C5\u03BC\u03AD\u03BD\u03C9\u03BD
\u03B1\u03C0\u03CC\
      \ \u03C4\u03B7\u03BD \u0395.\u0395.\u0395.\u03A0.
\u03B9\u03C3\u03C4\u03BF\u03C4\
      \u03CC\u03C0\u03C9\u03BD \u03BC\u03C0\u03BF\u03C1\u03B5\u03AF\u03C4\u03B5
\u03BD\
      \u03B1 \u03B2\u03C1\u03B5\u03AF\u03C4\u03B5 \u03B5\u03B4\u03CE:  &amp;lt;a
href=&#39;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/index.php/el&#39;\
      \
target=&#39;_new&#39;&amp;gt;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/index.php/el/&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;\r\n\
      \t\t\t&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;\u039C\u03B5
\u03B5\u03BA\u03C4\u03AF\u03BC\u03B7\u03C3\u03B7,&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;\r\
      \n\t\t\tWIND
\u0395\u03BB\u03BB\u03AC\u03C2\r\n\t\t\t&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;\r\n\t&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;\r\
      \n&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;quot;
    code: 200
    headers:
    - - Content-Length
      - [&#39;2395&#39;]
    - - Accept-Ranges
      - [bytes]
    - - Server
      - [Tellas HTTP Server]
    - - Last-Modified
      - [&#39;Wed, 04 Sep 2013 06:55:41 GMT&#39;]
    - - Connection
      - [close]
    - - ETag
      - [&#39;&amp;quot;1cf689-95b-4b277540&amp;quot;&#39;]
    - - Date
      - [&#39;Mon, 25 Aug 2014 11:42:53 GMT&#39;]
    - - Content-Type
      - [text/html]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ISP has blocked 325 entries (74.2%) of the published &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/images/Anakoinoseis/BlackList_EEEP_%2021022014.pdf&#34;&gt;blacklist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A screenshot from the blocked website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/eeep-greek-censorship/eeep_wind_gr.png&#34; alt=&#34;Wind EEEP Blocked website screenshot&#34; title=&#34;Wind EEEP Blocked website screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least 65 entries falsely responded with a 404 HTTP error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;agent: agent
body_length_match: false
body_proportion: 0.0
control_failure: null
experiment_failure: null
factor: 0.8
headers_diff: !!set {Content-Type: null, Date: null, Location: null}
headers_match: false
input: http://tatts.com/goldencasket
requests:
- request:
    body: null
    headers:
    - - User-Agent
      - [&#39;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; en-US; rv:1.9.2)
        Gecko/20100115
          Firefox/3.6&#39;]
    method: GET
    tor: {is_tor: false}
    url: http://tatts.com/goldencasket
  response:
    body: &#39;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC &amp;quot;-//IETF//DTD HTML 2.0//EN&amp;quot;&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;404 Not Found&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Not Found&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The requested URL /goldencasket was not found on this server.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Additionally, a 404 Not Found

      error was encountered while trying to use an ErrorDocument to handle the
request.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;

      &#39;
    code: 404
    headers:
    - - Date
      - [&#39;Mon, 25 Aug 2014 11:43:09 GMT&#39;]
    - - Content-Length
      - [&#39;329&#39;]
    - - Content-Type
      - [text/html; charset=iso-8859-1]
    - - Connection
      - [close]
    - - Server
      - [Tellas HTTP Server]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ISP uses Etag for tracking users which try to visit the blocked content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;hol:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;HOL&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ISP has blocked 438 entries (100%) of the published &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/images/Anakoinoseis/BlackList_EEEP_%2021022014.pdf&#34;&gt;blacklist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from HTTP request test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;input: http://betguardian.me/
requests:
- request:
    body: null
    headers:
    - - User-Agent
      - [&#39;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; en-US; rv:1.9.1.7)
        Gecko/20091221
          Firefox/3.5.7&#39;]
    method: GET
    tor: {is_tor: false}
    url: http://betguardian.me/
  response:
    body: &#39;&#39;
    code: 301
    headers:
    - - Date
      - [&#39;Thu, 24 Jul 2014 15:58:11 GMT&#39;]
    - - Connection
      - [close]
    - - Content-Length
      - [&#39;0&#39;]
    - - Location
      - [&#39;http://eeepnotice.hol.gr/&#39;]
    - - Server
      - [lighttpd/1.4.31]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from DNS Consistency test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;input: betguardian.me
queries:
- addrs: [186.5.161.199]
  answers:
  - [&amp;lt;RR name=betguardian.me type=A class=IN ttl=14399s auth=False&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;A
    address=186.5.161.199
      ttl=14399&amp;gt;]
  query: &#39;[Query(&#39;&#39;betguardian.me&#39;&#39;, 1, 1)]&#39;
  query_type: A
  resolver: &amp;amp;id002 [64.9.225.221, 57004]
- addrs: [194.30.227.163]
  answers:
  - [&amp;lt;RR name=betguardian.me type=A class=IN ttl=3138s auth=False&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;A
    address=194.30.227.163
      ttl=3138&amp;gt;]
  query: &#39;[Query(&#39;&#39;betguardian.me&#39;&#39;, 1, 1)]&#39;
  query_type: A
  resolver: &amp;amp;id001 [192.168.122.1, 53]
- query: &#39;[Query(&#39;&#39;163.227.30.194.in-addr.arpa&#39;&#39;, 12, 1)]&#39;
  query_type: PTR
  resolver: *id001
- query: &#39;[Query(&#39;&#39;199.161.5.186.in-addr.arpa&#39;&#39;, 12, 1)]&#39;
  query_type: PTR
  resolver: *id002
tampering: {192.168.122.1: reverse_match}
test_resolvers: [192.168.122.1]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A screenshot from the blocked website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/eeep-greek-censorship/eeepnotice_hol_gr.png&#34; alt=&#34;HOL EEEP Blocked website screenshot&#34; title=&#34;HOL EEEP Blocked website screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cosmote:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Cosmote&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from HTTP request test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;input: http://betguardian.me/
requests:
- request:
    body: null
    headers:
    - - User-Agent
      - [&#39;Mozilla/5.0 (iPhone; U; CPU iPhone OS 3 1 2 like Mac OS X; en-us)
        AppleWebKit/528.18
          (KHTML, like Gecko) Mobile/7D11&#39;]
    method: GET
    tor: {is_tor: false}
    url: http://betguardian.me/
  response:
    body: &amp;quot;\uFEFF&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC \&amp;quot;-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0
Transitional//EN\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\
      \n&amp;lt;HTML&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;HEAD&amp;gt;\r\n &amp;lt;META content=\&amp;quot;IE=5.0000\&amp;quot;
http-equiv=\&amp;quot;X-UA-Compatible\&amp;quot;\
      &amp;gt;\r\n &amp;lt;TITLE&amp;gt;\u039C\u03AE
      &amp;gt;\u0395\u03C0\u03B9\u03C4\u03C1\u03B5\u03C0\u03C4\u03AE\
      \ \u03A0\u03C1\u03CC\u03C3\u03B2\u03B1\u03C3\u03B7&amp;lt;/TITLE&amp;gt; \r\n&amp;lt;META
http-equiv=\&amp;quot;\
      Content-Type\&amp;quot; content=\&amp;quot;text/html; charset=iso-8859-7\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;LINK
href=\&amp;quot;files/styles.css\&amp;quot;\
      \ rel=\&amp;quot;stylesheet\&amp;quot; type=\&amp;quot;text/css\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/HEAD&amp;gt; \r\n&amp;lt;BODY
text=\&amp;quot;#000000\&amp;quot;\
      \ topmargin=\&amp;quot;0\&amp;quot; leftmargin=\&amp;quot;0\&amp;quot; bgcolor=\&amp;quot;#eeeeee\&amp;quot; marginheight=&#39;0\&amp;quot;&#39;
marginwidth=\&amp;quot;\
      0\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;TABLE width=\&amp;quot;100%\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;100%\&amp;quot; border=\&amp;quot;0\&amp;quot;
cellspacing=\&amp;quot;0\&amp;quot;\
      \ cellpadding=\&amp;quot;0\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n  &amp;lt;TBODY&amp;gt;\r\n  &amp;lt;TR&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;TD align=\&amp;quot;center\&amp;quot;
valign=\&amp;quot;\
      top\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;\r\n      &amp;lt;TABLE width=\&amp;quot;700\&amp;quot; style=\&amp;quot;border: 2px solid
rgb(202,\
      \ 202, 202);\&amp;quot; \r\n      cellspacing=\&amp;quot;0\&amp;quot; cellpadding=\&amp;quot;0\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n
&amp;lt;TBODY&amp;gt;\r\
      \n        &amp;lt;TR&amp;gt;\r\n          &amp;lt;TD&amp;gt;\r\n            &amp;lt;TABLE width=\&amp;quot;100%\&amp;quot;
border=\&amp;quot;\
      0\&amp;quot; cellspacing=\&amp;quot;0\&amp;quot; cellpadding=\&amp;quot;0\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n              &amp;lt;TBODY&amp;gt;\r\n
\
      \        &amp;lt;TR&amp;gt;\r\n                &amp;lt;TD width=\&amp;quot;650\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;70\&amp;quot;
align=\&amp;quot;center\&amp;quot;\
      \ background=\&amp;quot;files/BackHeader.gif\&amp;quot; valign=\&amp;quot;middle\&amp;quot; colspan=3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;FONT
class=\&amp;quot;\
      blueTitle\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\u039C\u0397
\u0395\u03A0\u0399\u03A4\u03A1\u0395\u03A0\u03A4\u0397\
      \
\u03A0\u03A1\u039F\u03A3\u0392\u0391\u03A3\u0397&amp;lt;/FONT&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TD&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TR&amp;gt;\r\n\
      \              &amp;lt;TR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TR&amp;gt;\r\n              &amp;lt;TR&amp;gt;\r\n                &amp;lt;TD
align=\&amp;quot;\
      left\&amp;quot; background=\&amp;quot;files/BackLeft.jpg\&amp;quot; valign=\&amp;quot;bottom\&amp;quot;
style=\&amp;quot;background-position:\
      \ left bottom; background-repeat: no-repeat;\&amp;quot; bgcolor=\&amp;quot;#ffffff\&amp;quot;
colspan=\&amp;quot;\
      2\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n                  &amp;lt;CENTER&amp;gt;\r\n                  &amp;lt;TABLE&amp;gt;\r\n
\
      \            &amp;lt;TBODY&amp;gt;\r\n                    &amp;lt;TR&amp;gt;\r\n
&amp;lt;TD&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;lt;/TD&amp;gt;\r\
      \n                      &amp;lt;TD&amp;gt;&amp;lt;FONT
class=\&amp;quot;blue\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;\u039C\u03B5\
      \ \u03B2\u03AC\u03C3\u03B7 \u03B1\u03C0\u03CC\u03C6\u03B1\u03C3\u03B7
\u03C4\
      \u03B7\u03C2
\u03B1\u03BD\u03B5\u03BE\u03AC\u03C1\u03C4\u03B7\u03C4\u03B7\u03C2\
      \ \u03B4\u03B9\u03BF\u03B9\u03BA\u03B7\u03C4\u03B9\u03BA\u03AE\u03C2
\u03B1\u03C1\
      \u03C7\u03AE\u03C2 \&amp;quot;\u0395\u03C0\u03B9\u03C4\u03C1\u03BF\u03C0\u03AE
\u0395\
      \u03C0\u03BF\u03C0\u03C4\u03B5\u03AF\u03B1\u03C2 \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9
\u0395\u03BB\
      \u03AD\u03B3\u03C7\u03BF\u03C5
\u03A0\u03B1\u03B9\u03B3\u03BD\u03AF\u03C9\u03BD\
      \&amp;quot; (\u0395.\u0395.\u0395.\u03A0.), \u03BF
\u03B9\u03C3\u03C4\u03CC\u03C4\u03BF\
      \u03C0\u03BF\u03C2 \u03C0\u03BF\u03C5
\u03B5\u03C0\u03B9\u03C7\u03B5\u03B9\u03C1\
      \u03B5\u03AF\u03C4\u03B5 \u03BD\u03B1
\u03B5\u03C0\u03B9\u03C3\u03BA\u03B5\u03C6\
      \u03B8\u03B5\u03AF\u03C4\u03B5 \u03AD\u03C7\u03B5\u03B9
\u03B5\u03B3\u03B3\u03C1\
      \u03B1\u03C6\u03B5\u03AF \u03C3\u03C4\u03BF\u03BD
\u03BA\u03B1\u03C4\u03AC\u03BB\
      \u03BF\u03B3\u03BF \u03B5\u03BA\u03B5\u03AF\u03BD\u03C9\u03BD
\u03C0\u03BF\u03C5\
      \ \u03C0\u03C1\u03BF\u03C3\u03C6\u03AD\u03C1\u03BF\u03C5\u03BD
\u03C5\u03C0\u03B7\
      \u03C1\u03B5\u03C3\u03AF\u03B5\u03C2
\u03C4\u03C5\u03C7\u03B5\u03C1\u03CE\u03BD\
      \ \u03C0\u03B1\u03B9\u03B3\u03BD\u03AF\u03C9\u03BD \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9
\u03C3\
      \u03C4\u03BF\u03B9\u03C7\u03B7\u03BC\u03AC\u03C4\u03C9\u03BD
\u03C7\u03C9\u03C1\
      \u03AF\u03C2
\u03AC\u03B4\u03B5\u03B9\u03B1.\r\n\t\t\t&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;\u039A\u03B1\u03C4\
      \u03AC \u03C3\u03C5\u03BD\u03AD\u03C0\u03B5\u03B9\u03B1, \u03BC\u03B5
\u03B2\
      \u03AC\u03C3\u03B7 \u03C4\u03B7\u03BD
\u03BA\u03B5\u03AF\u03BC\u03B5\u03BD\u03B7\
      \ \u03BD\u03BF\u03BC\u03BF\u03B8\u03B5\u03C3\u03AF\u03B1, \u03B7
\u03C0\u03C1\
      \u03CC\u03C3\u03B2\u03B1\u03C3\u03B7 \u03C3\u03C4\u03BF\u03BD
\u03B9\u03C3\u03C4\
      \u03CC\u03C4\u03BF\u03C0\u03BF \u03B1\u03C5\u03C4\u03CC
\u03B4\u03B5\u03BD \u03B5\
      \u03C0\u03B9\u03C4\u03C1\u03AD\u03C0\u03B5\u03C4\u03B1\u03B9.\r\n\t\t\t&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;\u0393\
      \u03B9\u03B1
\u03C0\u03B5\u03C1\u03B9\u03C3\u03C3\u03CC\u03C4\u03B5\u03C1\u03B5\
      \u03C2
\u03C0\u03BB\u03B7\u03C1\u03BF\u03C6\u03BF\u03C1\u03AF\u03B5\u03C2: &amp;lt;a\
      \
href=\&amp;quot;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/index.php/el/\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/index.php/el/&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;\r\
      \n\t\t\t&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/FONT&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TD&amp;gt;\r\n
&amp;lt;TD&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;amp;nbsp&amp;lt;/TD&amp;gt;\r\
      \n
\t\t&amp;lt;/TR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TBODY&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TABLE&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/CENTER&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TBODY&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TABLE&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TD&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TBODY&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TABLE&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TD&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TBODY&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TABLE&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/BODY&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/HTML&amp;gt;\r\
      \n&amp;quot;
    code: 200
    headers:
    - - Content-Length
      - [&#39;2631&#39;]
    - - Accept-Ranges
      - [bytes]
    - - Server
      - [Apache/2.2.15 (CentOS)]
    - - Last-Modified
      - [&#39;Wed, 07 Aug 2013 11:24:33 GMT&#39;]
    - - Connection
      - [close]
    - - ETag
      - [&#39;&amp;quot;81b85-a47-4e359c92631e1&amp;quot;&#39;]
    - - Date
      - [&#39;Thu, 03 Jul 2014 16:16:06 GMT&#39;]
    - - Content-Type
      - [text/html; charset=UTF-8]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ISP has blocked 438 entries (100%) of the published &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/images/Anakoinoseis/BlackList_EEEP_%2021022014.pdf&#34;&gt;blacklist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A screenshot from the blocked website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/eeep-greek-censorship/eeep_cosmote_gr.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cosmote EEEP Blocked website screenshot&#34; title=&#34;Cosmote EEEP Blocked website screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;vodafone:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Vodafone&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ISP has blocked 425 entries (97.03%) of the published &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/images/Anakoinoseis/BlackList_EEEP_%2021022014.pdf&#34;&gt;blacklist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from HTTP request test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;input: http://betguardian.me/
requests:
- request:
    body: null
    headers:
    - - User-Agent
      - [&#39;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 6.1; en-US; rv:1.9.2)
        Gecko/20100115
          Firefox/3.6&#39;]
    method: GET
    tor: {is_tor: false}
    url: http://betguardian.me/
  response:
    body: &#39;&#39;
    code: 301
    headers:
    - - Date
      - [&#39;Sun, 24 Aug 2014 17:33:56 GMT&#39;]
    - - Connection
      - [close]
    - - Content-Length
      - [&#39;0&#39;]
    - - Location
      - [&#39;http://1.2.3.50/ups/no_access_gambling.htm&#39;]
    - - Server
      - [WebProxy/6.0]
- request:
    body: null
    headers:
    - - User-Agent
      - [&#39;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 6.1; en-US; rv:1.9.1.7)
        Gecko/20091221
          Firefox/3.5.7&#39;]

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A screenshot from the blocked website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/eeep-greek-censorship/eeep_vodafone_gr.png&#34; alt=&#34;Vodafone mobile EEEP Blocked website screenshot&#34; title=&#34;Vodafone mobile EEEP Blocked website screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ISP uses DNS hijacking for 58 entries that EEEP has published either using
HTTPS URLs on the blacklist or entries that not prefixed with &amp;lsquo;http://&amp;rsquo; For the
rest of them it uses some kind of DPI/proxy, using Bluecoat&amp;rsquo;s WebProxy/6.0. If
an HTTP URL does not exactly match the one published at the blacklist it is
passed on to the original server, if it matches then the request gets
redirected to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://1.2.3.50/ups/no_access_gambling.htm
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another interesting case with this ISP is that for domains that it has filtered
using DNS hijacking, subdomains of those do not even have an A record
(dns_lookup_error). That means that some URLs on the blacklist that
contain subdomains are not getting redirected to
&amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.2.3.50/ups/no_access_gambling.htm&#39;&#34;&gt;http://1.2.3.50/ups/no_access_gambling.htm&#39;&lt;/a&gt;. They cannot be resolved
and they are not accessible at all from clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -I rivernilecasino.net
HTTP/1.1 302 Moved Temporarily
Date: Sun, 31 Aug 2014 12:38:01 GMT
Server: Microsoft-IIS/6.0
X-Powered-By: ASP.NET
X-AspNet-Version: 4.0.30319
Location: http://www.vegaspartnerlounge.com/generic/informer.asp?Subgid=987228&amp;amp;Country=Greece&amp;amp;btag=rivernilecasino.net&amp;amp;btag2=16&amp;amp;btag3=&amp;amp;btag4=&amp;amp;btag5=
Set-Cookie: RiverNileCasino=btag=rivernilecasino.net&amp;amp;btag2=16&amp;amp;btag3=&amp;amp;btag4=&amp;amp;btag5=; domain=rivernilecasino.net; expires=Mon, 01-Sep-2014 12:38:00 GMT; path=/; HttpOnly
Cache-Control: private
Content-Type: text/html; charset=utf-8
Content-Length: 279
Connection: keep-alive
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By changing the URL to www.rivernilecasino.net (adding the www subdomain), the
request also passes through to the legitimate server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -I www.rivernilecasino.net
HTTP/1.1 302 Moved Temporarily
Date: Sun, 31 Aug 2014 12:38:28 GMT
Server: Microsoft-IIS/6.0
X-Powered-By: ASP.NET
X-AspNet-Version: 4.0.30319
Location: http://www.vegaspartnerlounge.com/generic/informer.asp?Subgid=785274&amp;amp;Country=Greece&amp;amp;btag=www.rivernilecasino.net&amp;amp;btag2=16&amp;amp;btag3=&amp;amp;btag4=&amp;amp;btag5=
Set-Cookie: RiverNileCasino=btag=www.rivernilecasino.net&amp;amp;btag2=16&amp;amp;btag3=&amp;amp;btag4=&amp;amp;btag5=; domain=rivernilecasino.net; expires=Mon, 01-Sep-2014 12:38:28 GMT; path=/; HttpOnly
Cache-Control: private
Content-Type: text/html; charset=utf-8
Content-Length: 283
Connection: keep-alive
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally using the same URL as the one published in the blacklist
(www.rivernilecasino.net/index.asp), the request gets proxied via
Vodafone ISP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -I www.rivernilecasino.net/index.asp
HTTP/1.1 301 Moved Permanently
Server: WebProxy/6.0
Date: Sun, 31 Aug 2014 12:39:01 GMT
Content-Length: 0
Location: http://1.2.3.50/ups/no_access_gambling.htm
Connection: keep-alive
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;wind-mobile:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Wind mobile&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from HTTP request test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;input: http://betguardian.me/
requests:
- request:
    body: null
    headers:
    - - User-Agent
      - [&#39;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 6.1; en-US; rv:1.9.1.7)
        Gecko/20091221
          Firefox/3.5.7&#39;]
    method: GET
    tor: {is_tor: false}
    url: http://betguardian.me/
  response:
    body: &amp;quot;\uFEFF&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC \&amp;quot;-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.01
Transitional//EN\&amp;quot;\r\
      \n\&amp;quot;http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/loose.dtd\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;.:\
      \ \u0391\u03C0\u03B1\u03B3\u03CC\u03C1\u03B5\u03C5\u03C3\u03B7
\u03A0\u03C1\u03CC\
      \u03C3\u03B2\u03B1\u03C3\u03B7\u03C2 :.&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;meta
http-equiv=\&amp;quot;Content-Type\&amp;quot;\
      \ content=\&amp;quot;text/html; charset=UTF-8\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;style
type=\&amp;quot;text/css\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;!--\r\
      \nbody
{\r\n\tpadding:0px;\r\n\tmargin:0px;\r\n\tfont-family:Tahoma;\r\n\tfont-size:11pt;\r\
      \n\tbackground-image:
url(/img/wind_new_bg.jpg);\r\n\tbackground-repeat:repeat-x;\r\
      \n\tbackground-position: center top; \r\n}\r\n\r\na
{\r\n\tcolor:#02578E;\r\n\
      \tcursor: pointer; cursor: hand;\r\n}\r\n\r\nTop
{\r\n\tmargin:0;\r\n\theight:125px;\r\
      \n\twidth:970px;\r\n\tmargin-bottom:20px;\r\n}\r\n\r\nLogo{\r\n\tfloat:left;\r\
      \n\twidth:188px;\r\n}\r\n\r\n.style1 {\r\n\tfont-size:
11pt;\r\n\tfont-weight:\
      \ bold;\r\n}\r\n\r\n.style2 {color: #02578E}\r\n\r\n.main {\r\n\tmargin:
30px\
      \ 10px 10px 20px;\r\n\tpadding:10pt auto;\r\n\tline-spacing:
110%;\r\n\tfont-size:\
      \ 11pt;\r\n\ttext-align:
justify;\r\n}\r\n\r\n.uline{\r\n\ttext-decoration:underline;\r\
      \n\tfont-weight: bold;\r\n}\r\n--&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/style&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;body
class=\&amp;quot;\
      body\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n\t&amp;lt;div class=\&amp;quot;Top\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t&amp;lt;div class=\&amp;quot;Logo\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img
src=\&amp;quot;/img/wind_logo.jpg\&amp;quot;\
      &amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;\r\n\t&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;\r\n\t&amp;lt;div class=\&amp;quot;main\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span
      &amp;gt;class=\&amp;quot;style1\&amp;quot;\
      &amp;gt;\u03A3\u03B7\u03BC\u03B1\u03BD\u03C4\u03B9\u03BA\u03AE
      &amp;gt;\u03B5\u03BD\u03B7\u03BC\
      \u03AD\u03C1\u03C9\u03C3\u03B7:&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;\u039C\u03B5
\u03B2\u03AC\
      \u03C3\u03B7 \u03C4\u03B7\u03BD 65/8/24.7.2013
\u03B1\u03C0\u03CC\u03C6\u03B1\
      \u03C3\u03B7 \u03C4\u03B7\u03C2
&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;\u0395\u03C0\u03B9\u03C4\u03C1\u03BF\
      \u03C0\u03AE\u03C2 \u0395\u03C0\u03BF\u03C0\u03C4\u03B5\u03AF\u03B1\u03C2
\u03BA\
      \u03B1\u03B9 \u0395\u03BB\u03AD\u03B3\u03C7\u03BF\u03C5
\u03A0\u03B1\u03B9\u03B3\
      \u03BD\u03AF\u03C9\u03BD (\u0395.\u0395.\u0395.\u03A0.)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;, \u03BF
\u03B9\
      \u03C3\u03C4\u03CC\u03C4\u03BF\u03C0\u03BF\u03C2 \u03C0\u03BF\u03C5
\u03B5\u03C0\
      \u03B9\u03C7\u03B5\u03B9\u03C1\u03B5\u03AF\u03C4\u03B5 \u03BD\u03B1
\u03B5\u03C0\
      \u03B9\u03C3\u03BA\u03B5\u03C6\u03B8\u03B5\u03AF\u03C4\u03B5
&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;\u03C0\u03C1\
      \u03BF\u03C3\u03C6\u03AD\u03C1\u03B5\u03B9
\u03C5\u03C0\u03B7\u03C1\u03B5\u03C3\
      \u03AF\u03B5\u03C2 \u03C4\u03C5\u03C7\u03B5\u03C1\u03CE\u03BD
\u03C0\u03B1\u03B9\
      \u03B3\u03BD\u03AF\u03C9\u03BD \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9
\u03C3\u03C4\u03BF\u03B9\u03C7\
      \u03B7\u03BC\u03AC\u03C4\u03C9\u03BD &amp;lt;span
class=&#39;uline&#39;&amp;gt;\u03C7\u03C9\u03C1\u03AF\
      \u03C2 \u03AC\u03B4\u03B5\u03B9\u03B1&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;
\u03C3\u03C4\u03B7\u03BD\
      \
\u0395\u03BB\u03BB\u03AC\u03B4\u03B1.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;\u039A\u03B1\u03C4\u03AC\
      \ \u03C3\u03C5\u03BD\u03AD\u03C0\u03B5\u03B9\u03B1, &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;\u03B7
\u03C0\u03C1\
      \u03CC\u03C3\u03B2\u03B1\u03C3\u03B7 \u03C3\u03C4\u03BF\u03BD
\u03B9\u03C3\u03C4\
      \u03CC\u03C4\u03BF\u03C0\u03BF \u03B1\u03C5\u03C4\u03CC
\u03B4\u03B5\u03BD \u03B5\
      \u03AF\u03BD\u03B1\u03B9
\u03B5\u03C0\u03B9\u03C4\u03C1\u03B5\u03C0\u03C4\u03AE\
      &amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;, \u03CC\u03C0\u03C9\u03C2 \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9 \u03C3\u03B5
\u03BA\u03AC\
      \u03B8\u03B5 \u03B9\u03C3\u03C4\u03CC\u03C4\u03BF\u03C0\u03BF
\u03C0\u03BF\u03C5\
      \
\u03C0\u03B5\u03C1\u03B9\u03BB\u03B1\u03BC\u03B2\u03AC\u03BD\u03B5\u03C4\u03B1\
      \u03B9 \u03C3\u03C4\u03BF\u03BD
\u03C3\u03C7\u03B5\u03C4\u03B9\u03BA\u03CC \u03BA\
      \u03B1\u03C4\u03AC\u03BB\u03BF\u03B3\u03BF \u03C4\u03B7\u03C2
\u0395.\u0395\
      .\u0395.\u03A0.
\u03A0\u03B5\u03C1\u03B9\u03C3\u03C3\u03CC\u03C4\u03B5\u03C1\
      \u03B5\u03C2
\u03BB\u03B5\u03C0\u03C4\u03BF\u03BC\u03AD\u03C1\u03B5\u03B9\u03B5\
      \u03C2 \u03C3\u03C7\u03B5\u03C4\u03B9\u03BA\u03AC \u03BC\u03B5
\u03C4\u03B1\
      \ \u03C0\u03B1\u03C1\u03B1\u03C0\u03AC\u03BD\u03C9
\u03BA\u03B1\u03B8\u03CE\u03C2\
      \ \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9 \u03C4\u03BF\u03BD \u03C0\u03BB\u03AE\u03C1\u03B7
\u03BA\
      \u03B1\u03C4\u03AC\u03BB\u03BF\u03B3\u03BF \u03C4\u03C9\u03BD
\u03B1\u03C0\u03B1\
      \u03B3\u03BF\u03C1\u03B5\u03C5\u03BC\u03AD\u03BD\u03C9\u03BD
\u03B1\u03C0\u03CC\
      \ \u03C4\u03B7\u03BD \u0395.\u0395.\u0395.\u03A0.
\u03B9\u03C3\u03C4\u03BF\u03C4\
      \u03CC\u03C0\u03C9\u03BD \u03BC\u03C0\u03BF\u03C1\u03B5\u03AF\u03C4\u03B5
\u03BD\
      \u03B1 \u03B2\u03C1\u03B5\u03AF\u03C4\u03B5 \u03B5\u03B4\u03CE:  &amp;lt;a
href=&#39;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/index.php/el&#39;\
      \
target=&#39;_new&#39;&amp;gt;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/index.php/el/&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;\r\n\
      \t\t\t&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;\u039C\u03B5
\u03B5\u03BA\u03C4\u03AF\u03BC\u03B7\u03C3\u03B7,&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;\r\
      \n\t\t\tWIND
\u0395\u03BB\u03BB\u03AC\u03C2\r\n\t\t\t&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;\r\n\t&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;\r\
      \n&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;quot;
    code: 200
    headers:
    - - Content-Length
      - [&#39;2395&#39;]
    - - Accept-Ranges
      - [bytes]
    - - Server
      - [Tellas HTTP Server]
    - - Last-Modified
      - [&#39;Wed, 04 Sep 2013 06:55:41 GMT&#39;]
    - - Connection
      - [close]
    - - ETag
      - [&#39;&amp;quot;1cf689-95b-4b277540&amp;quot;&#39;]
    - - Date
      - [&#39;Fri, 04 Jul 2014 00:00:08 GMT&#39;]
    - - Content-Type
      - [text/html]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ISP has blocked 325 entries (74.2%) of the published &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamingcommission.gov.gr/images/Anakoinoseis/BlackList_EEEP_%2021022014.pdf&#34;&gt;blacklist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A screenshot from the blocked website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/eeep-greek-censorship/eeep_wind_gr.png&#34; alt=&#34;Wind mobile EEEP Blocked website screenshot&#34; title=&#34;Wind mobile EEEP Blocked website screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least 65 entries falsely responded with a 404 HTTP error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;- request:
    body: null
    headers:
    - - User-Agent
      - [&#39;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; de; rv:1.9.2) Gecko/20100115
        Firefox/3.6&#39;]
    method: GET
    tor: {is_tor: false}
    url: http://tatts.com/nswlotteries
  response:
    body: &#39;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC &amp;quot;-//IETF//DTD HTML 2.0//EN&amp;quot;&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;404 Not Found&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Not Found&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The requested URL /nswlotteries was not found on this server.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Additionally, a 404 Not Found

      error was encountered while trying to use an ErrorDocument to handle the
request.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;

      &#39;
    code: 404
    headers:
    - - Date
      - [&#39;Fri, 04 Jul 2014 00:01:30 GMT&#39;]
    - - Content-Length
      - [&#39;329&#39;]
    - - Content-Type
      - [text/html; charset=iso-8859-1]
    - - Connection
      - [close]
    - - Server
      - [Tellas HTTP Server]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 entries landing to the Wind support page: &amp;ldquo;landline services provided by Wind have been suspended&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;agent: agent
body_length_match: false
body_proportion: 0.0
control_failure: null
experiment_failure: null
factor: 0.8
headers_diff: !!set {Accept-Ranges: null, Content-Type: null, ETag: null,
Last-Modified: null,
  Location: null, Server: null}
headers_match: false
input: http://www.betoto.com
requests:
- request:
    body: null
    headers:
    - - User-Agent
      - [&#39;Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; en-US; rv:1.9.1.7)
        Gecko/20091221
          Firefox/3.5.7&#39;]
    method: GET
    tor: {is_tor: false}
    url: http://www.betoto.com
  response:
    body: &amp;quot;\uFEFF&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC \&amp;quot;-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.01
Transitional//EN\&amp;quot;\r\
      \n\&amp;quot;http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/loose.dtd\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;.:\
      \ \u03A0\u03C1\u03BF\u03C3\u03C9\u03C1\u03B9\u03BD\u03AE
\u03C6\u03C1\u03B1\u03B3\
      \u03AE \u03C4\u03C9\u03BD
\u03C5\u03C0\u03B7\u03C1\u03B5\u03C3\u03B9\u03CE\u03BD\
      \ \u03C0\u03C1\u03CC\u03C3\u03B2\u03B1\u03C3\u03B7\u03C2
\u03C3\u03C4\u03BF\
      \ Internet \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9
\u03C3\u03C4\u03B1\u03B8\u03B5\u03C1\u03AE\u03C2\
      \ \u03C4\u03B7\u03BB\u03B5\u03C6\u03C9\u03BD\u03AF\u03B1\u03C2
:.&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;\r\n\
      &amp;lt;!-- &amp;lt;meta http-equiv=\&amp;quot;Content-Type\&amp;quot; content=\&amp;quot;text/html;
charset=iso-8859-7\&amp;quot;\
      &amp;gt; --&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;meta http-equiv=\&amp;quot;Content-Type\&amp;quot; content=\&amp;quot;text/html;
      &amp;gt; charset=UTF-8\&amp;quot;\
      &amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;style type=\&amp;quot;text/css\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;!--\r\n\r\n\r\nbody
      &amp;gt;{\r\n\tpadding:0px;\r\
      \n\tmargin:0px;\r\n\tfont-family:Tahoma;\r\n\tfont-size:11px;\r\n\tbackground-image:\
      \
url(/img/wind_new_bg.jpg);\r\n\tbackground-repeat:repeat-x;\r\n\tbackground-position:\
      \ center top; \r\n\t\r\n}\r\na {\r\n\tcolor:#02578E;\r\n\tcursor:
pointer; cursor:\
      \ hand;\r\n\t}\r\n\t\r\n\r\nTop\r\n{\r\n\tmargin:0
auto;\r\n\theight:125px;\r\
      \n\twidth:970px;\r\n\tmargin-bottom:20px;\r\n}\r\nLogo{\r\n\tfloat:left;\r\n\
      \twidth:188px;\r\n}\r\n.style1 {\r\n\tfont-size: 14px;\r\n\tfont-weight:
bold;\r\
      \n}\r\n.style2 {color: #02578E}\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n--&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/style&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;script
type=\&amp;quot;\
      text/javascript\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;  \r\ndocument.write(&#39;&amp;lt;style
type=\&amp;quot;text\\/css\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;#toggle {\
      \ display: none; }&amp;lt;\\/style&amp;gt;&#39;);  \r\n&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;  \r\n&amp;lt;script
type=\&amp;quot;text/javascript\&amp;quot;\
      &amp;gt;  \r\nfunction switchMenu(obj) {  \r\n  var el =
      &amp;gt;  document.getElementById(obj);\
      \  \r\n  if ( el.style.display != \&amp;quot;none\&amp;quot; ) {  \r\n    el.style.display
= &#39;none&#39;;\
      \  \r\n  }  \r\n  else {  \r\n    el.style.display = &#39;block&#39;;  \r\n  }
\r\n\
      }  \r\nfunction hide() {  \r\n
document.getElementById(\&amp;quot;toggle\&amp;quot;).style.display=&#39;none&#39;;\
      \  \r\n  document.getElementById(\&amp;quot;toggle1\&amp;quot;).style.display=&#39;none&#39;; \r\n
document.getElementById(\&amp;quot;\
      toggle2\&amp;quot;).style.display=&#39;none&#39;; \r\n}
\r\n&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;\r\n\r\n&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;\r\n\r\n\
      &amp;lt;body class=\&amp;quot;body\&amp;quot; onload=\&amp;quot;hide();\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t&amp;lt;div
class=\&amp;quot;Top\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t\
      &amp;lt;div
class=\&amp;quot;Logo\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;\r\
      \n\t\t\t&amp;lt;img
src=\&amp;quot;/img/wind_logo.jpg\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;\r\n\
      \t\t&amp;lt;table width=\&amp;quot;100%\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t\t&amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t\t\t&amp;lt;td
width=\&amp;quot;15%\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;\r\
      \n\t\t\t\t\t&amp;lt;td width=\&amp;quot;76%\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span
class=\&amp;quot;style1\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\u03A3\u03B7\
      \u03BC\u03B1\u03BD\u03C4\u03B9\u03BA\u03AE
\u03B5\u03BD\u03B7\u03BC\u03AD\u03C1\
      \u03C9\u03C3\u03B7:&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t\t     &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;\r\n\u03A3\u03B1\u03C2
\u03B5\
      \u03BD\u03B7\u03BC\u03B5\u03C1\u03CE\u03BD\u03BF\u03C5\u03BC\u03B5
\u03C0\u03C9\
      \u03C2 &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;\u03AD\u03C7\u03B5\u03B9
\u03B5\u03BD\u03B5\u03C1\u03B3\u03BF\
      \u03C0\u03BF\u03B9\u03B7\u03B8\u03B5\u03AF \u03B7
\u03C0\u03C1\u03BF\u03C3\u03C9\
      \u03C1\u03B9\u03BD\u03AE \u03C6\u03C1\u03B1\u03B3\u03AE
\u03C4\u03C9\u03BD \u03C5\
      \u03C0\u03B7\u03C1\u03B5\u03C3\u03B9\u03CE\u03BD
\u03C0\u03C1\u03CC\u03C3\u03B2\
      \u03B1\u03C3\u03B7\u03C2 \u03C3\u03C4\u03BF Internet \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9
\u03C3\
      \u03C4\u03B1\u03B8\u03B5\u03C1\u03AE\u03C2
\u03C4\u03B7\u03BB\u03B5\u03C6\u03C9\
      \u03BD\u03AF\u03B1\u03C2&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; \u03C0\u03BF\u03C5
\u03BB\u03B1\u03BC\u03B2\
      \u03AC\u03BD\u03B5\u03C4\u03B5 \u03B1\u03C0\u03CC \u03C4\u03B7 Wind.
\u039F\
      \ \u03BB\u03CC\u03B3\u03BF\u03C2 \u03C4\u03B7\u03C2
\u03C6\u03C1\u03B1\u03B3\
      \u03AE\u03C2 \u03BC\u03C0\u03BF\u03C1\u03B5\u03AF \u03BD\u03B1
\u03B5\u03AF\u03BD\
      \u03B1\u03B9:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t\t\t  &amp;lt;ol&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t\t\t
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;\u039B\u03B7\
      \u03BE\u03B9\u03C0\u03C1\u03CC\u03B8\u03B5\u03C3\u03BC\u03B5\u03C2
\u03BF\u03C6\
      \u03B5\u03B9\u03BB\u03AD\u03C2&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; \u03AE\r\n\t\t\t\t\t
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\
      \t            &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;\u03A7\u03C1\u03AE\u03C3\u03B7
\u03C4\u03B7\u03C2\
      \ \u03C5\u03C0\u03B7\u03C1\u03B5\u03C3\u03AF\u03B1\u03C2
\u03C0\u03BF\u03C5\
      \
\u03B5\u03BD\u03B1\u03BD\u03C4\u03B9\u03CE\u03BD\u03B5\u03C4\u03B1\u03B9
\u03BC\
      \u03B5 \u03C4\u03BF\u03C5\u03C2 \u03CC\u03C1\u03BF\u03C5\u03C2
\u03C7\u03C1\u03AE\
      \u03C3\u03B7\u03C2&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;
(\u03B1\u03C0\u03BF\u03C3\u03C4\u03BF\u03BB\u03AE\
      \ \u03BC\u03B1\u03B6\u03B9\u03BA\u03CE\u03BD mail -spam-,
\u03B5\u03C0\u03B9\
      \u03B8\u03AD\u03C3\u03B5\u03B9\u03C2 \u03C3\u03B5
\u03C3\u03C5\u03BD\u03B4\u03B5\
      \u03B4\u03B5\u03BC\u03AD\u03BD\u03BF\u03C5\u03C2
\u03C7\u03C1\u03AE\u03C3\u03C4\
      \u03B5\u03C2 -attacks- \u03BA\u03BB\u03C0)\r\n
\r\n\
      \t\t\t            &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t\t\t  &amp;lt;/ol&amp;gt;\r\n
\u03A3\
      \u03C4\u03B7\u03BD \u03C0\u03B5\u03C1\u03AF\u03C0\u03C4\u03C9\u03C3\u03B7
\u03C4\
      \u03C9\u03BD
\u03BB\u03B7\u03BE\u03B9\u03C0\u03C1\u03CC\u03B8\u03B5\u03C3\u03BC\
      \u03C9\u03BD \u03BF\u03C6\u03B5\u03B9\u03BB\u03CE\u03BD,
\u03C0\u03B1\u03C1\u03B1\
      \u03BA\u03B1\u03BB\u03BF\u03CD\u03BC\u03B5 \u03BD\u03B1
\u03C0\u03C1\u03BF\u03C7\
      \u03C9\u03C1\u03AE\u03C3\u03B5\u03C4\u03B5 \u03AC\u03BC\u03B5\u03C3\u03B1
\u03C3\
      \u03C4\u03B7\u03BD \u03B5\u03BE\u03CC\u03C6\u03BB\u03B7\u03C3\u03AE
\u03C4\u03BF\
      \u03C5\u03C2 \u03BC\u03B5 \u03AD\u03BD\u03B1\u03BD \u03B1\u03C0\u03CC
\u03C4\
      \u03BF\u03C5\u03C2
\u03B4\u03B9\u03B1\u03B8\u03AD\u03C3\u03B9\u03BC\u03BF\u03C5\
      \u03C2 \u03C4\u03C1\u03CC\u03C0\u03BF\u03C5\u03C2
\u03C0\u03BB\u03B7\u03C1\u03C9\
      \u03BC\u03AE\u03C2:\r\n                   \r\n&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a
onclick=\&amp;quot;switchMenu(&#39;toggle&#39;);\&amp;quot;\
      \ title=\&amp;quot;\u0394\u03B5\u03AF\u03C4\u03B5 \u03C4\u03BF\u03C5\u03C2
\u03B4\u03B9\
      \u03B1\u03B8\u03AD\u03C3\u03B9\u03BC\u03BF\u03C5\u03C2
\u03C4\u03C1\u03CC\u03C0\
      \u03BF\u03C5\u03C2 \u03C0\u03BB\u03B7\u03C1\u03C9\u03BC\u03AE\u03C2\&amp;quot;
onMouseOver=\&amp;quot;\
      this.style.color = &#39;#C71B37&#39;\&amp;quot; onMouseOut=\&amp;quot;this.style.color =
&#39;#02578E&#39;\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\
      \n&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;u&amp;gt;[+]
\xAB\u0394\u03B9\u03B1\u03B8\u03AD\u03C3\u03B9\u03BC\u03BF\u03B9\
      \ \u03C4\u03C1\u03CC\u03C0\u03BF\u03B9
\u03C0\u03BB\u03B7\u03C1\u03C9\u03BC\u03AE\
      \u03C2\xBB&amp;lt;/u&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;DIV id=\&amp;quot;toggle\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;ol&amp;gt;
\
      \      \r\n\t&amp;lt;li
class=\&amp;quot;style2\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;\u0395\u03BE\u03CC\u03C6\u03BB\u03B7\
      \u03C3\u03B7 \u03C3\u03B5
\u03BA\u03B1\u03C4\u03AC\u03C3\u03C4\u03B7\u03BC\u03B1\
      \ Wind &amp;lt;u&amp;gt;(\u03C3\u03C5\u03C3\u03C4\u03AE\u03BD\u03B5\u03C4\u03B1\u03B9
\u03B3\
      \u03B9\u03B1 \u03B3\u03C1\u03AE\u03B3\u03BF\u03C1\u03B7
\u03B5\u03BE\u03C5\u03C0\
      \u03B7\u03C1\u03AD\u03C4\u03B7\u03C3\u03B7)&amp;lt;/u&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;li
class=\&amp;quot;\
      style2\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;\u039C\u03AD\u03C3\u03C9
\u03C0\u03B9\u03C3\u03C4\u03C9\u03C4\
      \u03B9\u03BA\u03CE\u03BD \u03BA\u03B1\u03C1\u03C4\u03CE\u03BD
\u03BC\u03B5 \u03B5\
      \u03C0\u03B9\u03C4\u03CC\u03C0\u03BF\u03C5
\u03C7\u03C1\u03AD\u03C9\u03C3\u03B7\
      \ \u03C3\u03B5 \u03BA\u03B1\u03C4\u03AC\u03C3\u03C4\u03B7\u03BC\u03B1
Wind&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;\
      \ (Visa, Mastercard,
\u0395\u03B8\u03BD\u03BF\u03BA\u03AC\u03C1\u03C4\u03B1\
      , American Express, Eurocard \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9 Diners) \u03AE
\u03BC\u03B5\
      \ &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;\u03AC\u03BC\u03B5\u03C3\u03B7
\u03C7\u03C1\u03AD\u03C9\u03C3\u03B7\
      &amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; \u03C4\u03B7\u03C2
\u03C0\u03B9\u03C3\u03C4\u03C9\u03C4\u03B9\u03BA\
      \u03AE\u03C2 \u03C3\u03B1\u03C2 \u03BA\u03AC\u03C1\u03C4\u03B1\u03C2
(Visa,\
      \ Mastercard \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9 Diners),
\u03BA\u03B1\u03BB\u03CE\u03BD\u03C4\
      \u03B1\u03C2 \u03BC\u03B1\u03C2 \u03C3\u03C4\u03BF 1215
\u03B1\u03C0\u03CC \u03BA\
      \u03B9\u03BD\u03B7\u03C4\u03CC WIND \u03C7\u03C9\u03C1\u03AF\u03C2
\u03C7\u03C1\
      \u03AD\u03C9\u03C3\u03B7 \u03AE \u03C3\u03C4\u03BF 210-5100600
(\u0394\u03B5\
      \u03C5\u03C4\u03AD\u03C1\u03B1-\u03A0\u03B1\u03C1\u03B1\u03C3\u03BA\u03B5\u03C5\
      \u03AE 08:00-17:00)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;li
class=\&amp;quot;style2\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\u03A3\u03C4\u03B1&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;\
      \
\u03C5\u03C0\u03BF\u03BA\u03B1\u03C4\u03B1\u03C3\u03C4\u03AE\u03BC\u03B1\u03C4\
      \u03B1 \u03C4\u03C9\u03BD
\u03C4\u03C1\u03B1\u03C0\u03B5\u03B6\u03CE\u03BD&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;:\
      \ \u0395\u03B8\u03BD\u03B9\u03BA\u03AE, EFG Eurobank-Ergasias, Alpha
Bank, T\
      \ Bank, Marfin-\u0395\u03B3\u03BD\u03B1\u03C4\u03AF\u03B1,
\u039A\u03CD\u03C0\
      \u03C1\u03BF\u03C5, \u0391\u03B3\u03C1\u03BF\u03C4\u03B9\u03BA\u03AE,
\u0395\
      \u03BC\u03C0\u03BF\u03C1\u03B9\u03BA\u03AE, Probank \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9
\u03A4\
      \u03B1\u03C7\u03C5\u03B4\u03C1\u03BF\u03BC\u03B9\u03BA\u03CC
\u03A4\u03B1\u03BC\
      \u03B9\u03B5\u03C5\u03C4\u03AE\u03C1\u03B9\u03BF
\u03C0\u03C1\u03BF\u03C3\u03BA\
      \u03BF\u03BC\u03AF\u03B6\u03BF\u03BD\u03C4\u03B1\u03C2 \u03C4\u03BF
\u03BB\u03BF\
      \u03B3\u03B1\u03C1\u03B9\u03B1\u03C3\u03BC\u03CC
\u03C3\u03B1\u03C2\r\n\t&amp;lt;li\
      \ class=\&amp;quot;style2\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\u03A3\u03C4\u03B1&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;
\u03C5\u03C0\u03BF\u03BA\u03B1\
      \u03C4\u03B1\u03C3\u03C4\u03AE\u03BC\u03B1\u03C4\u03B1
\u0395\u039B\u03A4\u0391\
      &amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;,
\u03C0\u03C1\u03BF\u03C3\u03BA\u03BF\u03BC\u03AF\u03B6\u03BF\u03BD\
      \u03C4\u03B1\u03C2 \u03C4\u03BF
\u03BB\u03BF\u03B3\u03B1\u03C1\u03B9\u03B1\u03C3\
      \u03BC\u03CC \u03C3\u03B1\u03C2&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;li
class=\&amp;quot;style2\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\u039C\u03AD\
      \u03C3\u03C9 &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;web-banking&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; \u03C4\u03C9\u03BD
\u03C4\u03C1\u03B1\
      \u03C0\u03B5\u03B6\u03CE\u03BD \u0395\u03B8\u03BD\u03B9\u03BA\u03AE, EFG
Eurobank-Ergasias,\
      \ Alpha Bank, Marfin-\u0395\u03B3\u03BD\u03B1\u03C4\u03AF\u03B1,
\u039A\u03CD\
      \u03C0\u03C1\u03BF\u03C5,
\u03A0\u03B5\u03B9\u03C1\u03B1\u03B9\u03CE\u03C2,\
      \ \u0391\u03B3\u03C1\u03BF\u03C4\u03B9\u03BA\u03AE,
\u0395\u03BC\u03C0\u03BF\
      \u03C1\u03B9\u03BA\u03AE, HSBC \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9
\u03A4\u03B1\u03C7\u03C5\u03B4\
      \u03C1\u03BF\u03BC\u03B9\u03BA\u03CC
\u03A4\u03B1\u03BC\u03B9\u03B5\u03C5\u03C4\
      \u03AE\u03C1\u03B9\u03BF&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;li
class=\&amp;quot;style2\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\u039C\u03AD\u03C3\
      \u03C9&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt; phone-banking&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; \u03C4\u03C9\u03BD
\u03C4\u03C1\u03B1\u03C0\
      \u03B5\u03B6\u03CE\u03BD EFG Eurobank-Ergasias, Alpha Bank,
Marfin-\u0395\u03B3\
      \u03BD\u03B1\u03C4\u03AF\u03B1, \u039A\u03CD\u03C0\u03C1\u03BF\u03C5,
\u03A0\
      \u03B5\u03B9\u03C1\u03B1\u03B9\u03CE\u03C2 \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9
HSBC&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n\
      \    &amp;lt;li class=\&amp;quot;style2\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\u039C\u03AD\u03C3\u03C9 \u03C4\u03C9\u03BD
\u03B1\
      \u03C5\u03C4\u03CC\u03BC\u03B1\u03C4\u03C9\u03BD
\u03BC\u03B7\u03C7\u03B1\u03BD\
      \u03B7\u03BC\u03AC\u03C4\u03C9\u03BD&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt; Easy Pay&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;
\u03C4\u03B7\u03C2\
      \ \u03A4\u03C1\u03AC\u03C0\u03B5\u03B6\u03B1\u03C2
\u03A0\u03B5\u03B9\u03C1\u03B1\
      \u03B9\u03CE\u03C2&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;li
class=\&amp;quot;style2\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\u039C\u03AD\u03C3\u03C9\
      \ &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;winbank&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; easypay \u03C4\u03B7\u03C2
\u03A0\u03B5\u03B9\u03C1\
      \u03B1\u03B9\u03CE\u03C2&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;li
class=\&amp;quot;style2\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\u039C\u03AD\u03C3\
      \u03C9 \u03C4\u03BF\u03C5&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;
\u03B4\u03B9\u03BA\u03C4\u03CD\u03BF\u03C5\
      \ \u0391\u03A4\u039C&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; \u03C4\u03C9\u03BD
\u03C4\u03C1\u03B1\u03C0\u03B5\
      \u03B6\u03CE\u03BD \u0395\u03B8\u03BD\u03B9\u03BA\u03AE, Alpha Bank,
\u0391\u03B3\
      \u03C1\u03BF\u03C4\u03B9\u03BA\u03AE, Probank \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9
\u03A4\u03B1\
      \u03C7\u03C5\u03B4\u03C1\u03BF\u03BC\u03B9\u03BA\u03CC
\u03A4\u03B1\u03BC\u03B9\
      \u03B5\u03C5\u03C4\u03AE\u03C1\u03B9\u03BF, \u03BC\u03B5
\u03C7\u03C1\u03AE\u03C3\
      \u03B7 \u03C4\u03BF\u03C5 \u039A\u03C9\u03B4\u03B9\u03BA\u03BF\u03CD
\u03A0\u03BB\
      \u03B7\u03C1\u03C9\u03BC\u03AE\u03C2 \u0391\u03A4\u039C
\u03C0\u03BF\u03C5 \u03B1\
      \u03BD\u03B1\u03B3\u03C1\u03AC\u03C6\u03B5\u03C4\u03B1\u03B9
\u03C3\u03C4\u03B7\
      \u03BD \u03C0\u03C1\u03CE\u03C4\u03B7
\u03C3\u03B5\u03BB\u03AF\u03B4\u03B1 \u03C4\
      \u03BF\u03C5
\u03BB\u03BF\u03B3\u03B1\u03C1\u03B9\u03B1\u03C3\u03BC\u03BF\u03CD\
      &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;li class=\&amp;quot;style2\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\u039C\u03AD\u03C3\u03C9
\u03C4\u03BF\u03C5\
      &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt; \u0394\u03B9\u03BA\u03C4\u03CD\u03BF\u03C5
\u0391\u03C5\u03C4\u03CC\
      \u03BC\u03B1\u03C4\u03C9\u03BD \u039A\u03AD\u03BD\u03C4\u03C1\u03C9\u03BD
\u03A0\
      \u03BB\u03B7\u03C1\u03C9\u03BC\u03CE\u03BD&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; (APS)
\u03C4\u03BF\u03C5\
      \
\u03A4\u03B1\u03C7\u03C5\u03B4\u03C1\u03BF\u03BC\u03B9\u03BA\u03BF\u03CD
\u03A4\
      \u03B1\u03BC\u03B9\u03B5\u03C5\u03C4\u03B7\u03C1\u03AF\u03BF\u03C5&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n\
      &amp;lt;/ol&amp;gt;\r\n\r\n&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;\r\n\r\n  \r\n  \r\n&amp;lt;span
class=\&amp;quot;style2\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;u&amp;gt;\u03A0\
      \u03C1\u03BF\u03C3\u03BF\u03C7\u03AE:&amp;lt;/u&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; \u03A3\u03B5
\u03C0\u03B5\
      \u03C1\u03AF\u03C0\u03C4\u03C9\u03C3\u03B7 \u03C0\u03BF\u03C5
&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;\u03B4\
      \u03B5\u03BD&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;
\u03C0\u03C1\u03BF\u03C7\u03C9\u03C1\u03AE\u03C3\u03B5\
      \u03C4\u03B5 \u03C3\u03B5
\u03B5\u03BE\u03CC\u03C6\u03BB\u03B7\u03C3\u03B7 \u03C3\
      \u03B5 \u03BA\u03B1\u03C4\u03AC\u03C3\u03C4\u03B7\u03BC\u03B1 Wind,
\u03C3\u03C5\
      \u03C3\u03C4\u03AE\u03BD\u03B5\u03C4\u03B1\u03B9
-\u03CE\u03C3\u03C4\u03B5 \u03BD\
      \u03B1
\u03B5\u03BE\u03C5\u03C0\u03B7\u03C1\u03B5\u03C4\u03B7\u03B8\u03B5\u03AF\
      \u03C4\u03B5 \u03C4\u03B1\u03C7\u03CD\u03C4\u03B5\u03C1\u03B1- \u03B7
\u03B1\
      \u03C0\u03BF\u03C3\u03C4\u03BF\u03BB\u03AE \u03BC\u03B5 FAX
\u03C3\u03C4\u03BF\
      \ 211 120 1100 \u03AE \u03BC\u03B5 e-mail \u03C3\u03C4\u03BF
CustomerCareFixed@wind.gr,\
      \ \u03C4\u03B7\u03C2
\u03B1\u03C0\u03CC\u03B4\u03B5\u03B9\u03BE\u03B7\u03C2\
      \ \u03C0\u03BB\u03B7\u03C1\u03C9\u03BC\u03AE\u03C2, \u03BC\u03B5
\u03C4\u03B7\
      \u03BD \u03AD\u03BD\u03B4\u03B5\u03B9\u03BE\u03B7
\xAB\u0386\u03C1\u03C3\u03B7\
      \ \u03A0\u03C1\u03BF\u03C3\u03C9\u03C1\u03B9\u03BD\u03AE\u03C2
\u03A6\u03C1\u03B1\
      \u03B3\u03AE\u03C2\xBB \u03BA\u03B1\u03B9
\u03B1\u03BD\u03B1\u03B3\u03C1\u03AC\
      \u03C6\u03BF\u03BD\u03C4\u03B1\u03C2 \u03C4\u03BF\u03BD
\u03B1\u03C1\u03B9\u03B8\
      \u03BC\u03CC \u03C4\u03B7\u03C2
\u03C3\u03CD\u03BD\u03B4\u03B5\u03C3\u03AE\u03C2\
      \ \u03C3\u03B1\u03C2 \u03AE \u03C4\u03BF\u03BD
\u03BA\u03C9\u03B4\u03B9\u03BA\
      \u03CC
\u03C0\u03B5\u03BB\u03AC\u03C4\u03B7&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;\r\n\
      &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;\u039C\u03B5 \u03C4\u03B7\u03BD
\u03B5\u03BE\u03CC\u03C6\u03BB\u03B7\u03C3\
      \u03B7 \u03C4\u03C9\u03BD \u03BF\u03C6\u03B5\u03B9\u03BB\u03CE\u03BD,
\u03B7\
      \ Wind \u03B8\u03B1
\u03C0\u03C1\u03BF\u03C7\u03C9\u03C1\u03AE\u03C3\u03B5\u03B9\
      \ \u03C3\u03C4\u03B9\u03C2&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;
\u03B1\u03C0\u03B1\u03C1\u03B1\u03AF\u03C4\
      \u03B7\u03C4\u03B5\u03C2
\u03B5\u03BD\u03AD\u03C1\u03B3\u03B5\u03B9\u03B5\u03C2\
      \ \u03B3\u03B9\u03B1 \u03C4\u03B7\u03BD \u03AC\u03C1\u03C3\u03B7
\u03C4\u03B7\
      \u03C2 \u03C6\u03C1\u03B1\u03B3\u03AE\u03C2&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;, \u03B5\u03BD\u03CE
\u03B1\
      \u03C0\u03CC \u03C4\u03B7\u03BD \u03C0\u03BB\u03B5\u03C5\u03C1\u03AC
\u03C3\u03B1\
      \u03C2 \u03B5\u03AF\u03BD\u03B1\u03B9
\u03C0\u03B9\u03B8\u03B1\u03BD\u03CC \u03BD\
      \u03B1 \u03C7\u03C1\u03B5\u03B9\u03AC\u03B6\u03B5\u03C4\u03B1\u03B9
&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;\u03B5\
      \u03C0\u03B1\u03BD\u03B5\u03BA\u03BA\u03AF\u03BD\u03B7\u03C3\u03B7
\u03C4\u03BF\
      \u03C5 \u03B5\u03BE\u03BF\u03C0\u03BB\u03B9\u03C3\u03BC\u03BF\u03CD
(router).&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;\r\
      \n&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;\u0393\u03B9\u03B1 \u03AC\u03BC\u03B5\u03C3\u03B7
\u03AC\u03C1\u03C3\u03B7\
      \ \u03C4\u03B7\u03C2 \u03C6\u03C1\u03B1\u03B3\u03AE\u03C2&amp;amp;nbsp;
&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;\u03C3\
      \u03C5\u03C3\u03C4\u03AE\u03BD\u03B5\u03C4\u03B1\u03B9 \u03B7
\u03B5\u03BE\u03CC\
      \u03C6\u03BB\u03B7\u03C3\u03B7 \u03C3\u03B5
\u03BA\u03B1\u03C4\u03AC\u03C3\u03C4\
      \u03B7\u03BC\u03B1 Wind &amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;.  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;\u039C\u03B5
\u03B5\u03BA\u03C4\
      \u03AF\u03BC\u03B7\u03C3\u03B7,\r\n&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Wind
\u0395\u03BB\u03BB\u03AC\u03C2\r\n\
      \      &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n\t&amp;lt;/ol&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;td
width=\&amp;quot;9%\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;\r\n\
      \t\t\t\t\r\n\t\t\t\t&amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t\t\t&amp;lt;td
width=\&amp;quot;15%\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t\
      \t\t&amp;lt;td width=\&amp;quot;76%\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t\t\t&amp;lt;a onclick=\&amp;quot;switchMenu(&#39;toggle2&#39;);\&amp;quot;
title=\&amp;quot;\
      English Version\&amp;quot; onMouseOver=\&amp;quot;this.style.color = &#39;#C71B37&#39;\&amp;quot;
onMouseOut=\&amp;quot;\
      this.style.color = &#39;#02578E&#39;\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt; &amp;lt;u&amp;gt;[+] English
Version&amp;lt;/u&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;img\
      \ src=\&amp;quot;/img/flag_en.jpg\&amp;quot; width=\&amp;quot;18\&amp;quot; height=\&amp;quot;13\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t\t\t\
      \ &amp;lt;div id=\&amp;quot;toggle2\&amp;quot;&amp;gt; \r\n\t\t\t\t\t &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class=\&amp;quot;style1\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Important
notice:&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;\r\
      \n  \r\nYou are kindly informed that your &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;landline services
provided\
      \ by Wind have been suspended &amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; due to: &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t\t\t
&amp;lt;ol&amp;gt;\r\n\
      \t\t\t\t\t    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Non-payment&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; or&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t
\
      \ &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Violation of terms of use&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;\r\n
\
      \    \r\n\t\t\t            &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t\t\t\t  &amp;lt;/ol&amp;gt;\r\n           In
case\
      \ of suspension due to non-payment please proceed as soon as possible to
settlement\
      \ with one of the available ways listed below:\r\n
\r\n&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a\
      \ onclick=\&amp;quot;switchMenu(&#39;toggle1&#39;);\&amp;quot; title=\&amp;quot;Make Click to view the Ways
of\
      \ Payment\&amp;quot; onMouseOver=\&amp;quot;this.style.color = &#39;#C71B37&#39;\&amp;quot;
onMouseOut=\&amp;quot;this.style.color\
      \ = &#39;#02578E&#39;\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt; &amp;lt;u&amp;gt;[+] &amp;amp;quot;Ways of
Payment&amp;amp;quot;&amp;lt;/u&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;DIV id=\&amp;quot;\
      toggle1\&amp;quot; class=\&amp;quot;style2\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;ol&amp;gt;
\r\n\t&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Directly\
      \ in any Wind Store &amp;lt;u&amp;gt;(recommended for quick service
re-activation)&amp;lt;/u&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\
      \n    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Using your credit card &amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;, with &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;direct
charge\
      \ in any Wind Store &amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; (Visa, Mastercard, Ethnokarta, American
Express,\
      \ Eurocard and Diners) or &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;In any branch of the
following\
      \ banks: &amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;National bank of Greece, EFG Eurobank-Ergasias,
Alpha\
      \ Bank, T Bank, Marfin-Egnatia, Bank of Cyprus, ATEbank, Emporiki Bank,
Probank\
      \ and Hellenic Postbank bringing your bill &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;any
Hellenic\
      \ Post branch (ELTA) &amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;, bringing your bill &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Through&amp;amp;nbsp;\
      \ &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;web banking &amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;services of the following banks:
National\
      \ bank of Greece, EFG Eurobank-Ergasias, Alpha Bank, Marfin-Egnatia, Bank
of\
      \ Cyprus, Piraeus Bank, ATEbank, Emporiki Bank, HSBC and Hellenic
Postbank &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\
      \n    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; Through&amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;phone-banking &amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;services of
the\
      \ following banks: EFG Eurobank-Ergasias, Alpha Bank, Marfin-Egnatia,
Bank of\
      \ Cyprus, Piraeus Bank and HSBC &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; Through&amp;amp;nbsp;
&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Easy\
      \ Pay &amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;bill payment spots provided by Piraeus Bank
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n \
      \   &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Through&amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Winbank Easy Pay &amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;service
provided\
      \ by Piraeus Bank&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Through
&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;\u0391\u03A4\u039C machines&amp;amp;nbsp;of\
      \ &amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;the following banks: National bank of Gre ece, Alpha B ank,
ATEbank,\
      \ Probank and Hellenic Postbank,using the ATM payment code mentioned on
the\
      \ first page of the bill &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n    \r\n&amp;lt;/ol&amp;gt;\r\n  \r\n
\r\n&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;u&amp;gt;Important\
      \ notice:&amp;lt;/u&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; In case you do &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;u&amp;gt;not&amp;lt;/u&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; proceed
to\
      \ settlement through a Wind Store, it is highly recommended to submit
through\
      \ FAX to 211 120 1100 or e-mail to CustomerCareFixed@wind.gr, a copy of
the\
      \ receipt \u03C4\u03B7\u03C2
\u03B1\u03C0\u03CC\u03B4\u03B5\u03B9\u03BE\u03B7\
      \u03C2 \u03C0\u03BB\u03B7\u03C1\u03C9\u03BC\u03AE\u03C2, with the
indication\
      \ \&amp;quot;Service re-activation\&amp;quot;, referring your telephone number or the
customer\
      \ code&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;\r\n\r\nUpon settlement, Wind will proceed to service
re-activation,\
      \ while &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;restarting your router may be
needed.&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;\r\nFor\
      \ quick service re-activation it is &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;u&amp;gt;recommended to pay through
any\
      \ Wind Store&amp;lt;/u&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;.\r\n                            \r\n&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Best
regards,\r\
      \n&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Wind S.A\r\n      &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;\r\n\t&amp;lt;/ol&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;td
width=\&amp;quot;9%\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;\r\
      \n&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;\r\n\t\t&amp;lt;/table&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;quot;
    code: 200
    headers:
    - - Content-Length
      - [&#39;10873&#39;]
    - - Accept-Ranges
      - [bytes]
    - - Server
      - [Tellas HTTP Server]
    - - Last-Modified
      - [&#39;Fri, 05 Jul 2013 12:56:04 GMT&#39;]
    - - Connection
      - [close]
    - - ETag
      - [&#39;&amp;quot;1ce8b8-2a79-37aa6100&amp;quot;&#39;]
    - - Date
      - [&#39;Fri, 04 Jul 2014 00:02:07 GMT&#39;]
    - - Content-Type
      - [text/html]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ISP uses Etag for tracking users which try to visit the blocked content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;failure-on-mail-delivery:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Failure on mail delivery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most ISPs have hijacked the DNS mail
exchanger record(s) of the domain name of the EEEP blacklist. A MX record
points to the appropriate mail server and specifies how email delivery
should be routed for a domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our test cases the ISPs have not returned any answer when queried for MX
record(s), deliberately or by mis-configuration for the domain entries included
in the EEEP blacklist. During email delivery an SMTP client first would query
the domain for a MX record and if that is not found it falls back to looking up
for an A record (or AAAA record if IPV6 is available) and attempt to deliver
email based on these records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our case the A records points to a spoofed A record pointing to a local
server or proxy of the ISP (show A records from ISPs) any email delivery would
fail and the user would realize this after hours or even days (according to the
email SMTP configuration).This implies tremendous negative impacts as well as
restricting fair markets and business regulations, i.e a user trying to
communicate with any business (all of the censored websites are businesses)
would find himself not being able to perform an email delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dns-mx-records-responses:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;DNS MX records responses:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The correct MX records of the censored domain names in example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;; &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; DiG 9.8.4-rpz2+rl005.12-P1 &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; MX 770.com @8.8.8.8
;; global options: +cmd
;; Got answer:
;; -&amp;gt;&amp;gt;HEADER&amp;lt;&amp;lt;- opcode: QUERY, status: NOERROR, id: 764
;; flags: qr rd ra; QUERY: 1, ANSWER: 5, AUTHORITY: 0, ADDITIONAL: 0

;; QUESTION SECTION:
;770.com.           IN  MX

;; ANSWER SECTION:
770.com.        2473    IN  MX  20 alt1.aspmx.l.google.com.
770.com.        2473    IN  MX  30 aspmx2.googlemail.com.
770.com.        2473    IN  MX  20 alt2.aspmx.l.google.com.
770.com.        2473    IN  MX  30 aspmx3.googlemail.com.
770.com.        2473    IN  MX  10 aspmx.l.google.com.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;; &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; DiG 9.8.4-rpz2+rl005.12-P1 &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; MX 880.com @8.8.8.8
;; global options: +cmd
;; Got answer:
;; -&amp;gt;&amp;gt;HEADER&amp;lt;&amp;lt;- opcode: QUERY, status: NOERROR, id: 17952
;; flags: qr rd ra; QUERY: 1, ANSWER: 2, AUTHORITY: 0, ADDITIONAL: 0

;; QUESTION SECTION:
;880.com.           IN  MX

;; ANSWER SECTION:
880.com.        2753    IN  MX  0 smtp.secureserver.net.
880.com.        2753    IN  MX  10 mailstore1.secureserver.net.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spoofed MX record responses of the ISPs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;forthnet-1:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Forthnet&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;; &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; DiG 9.8.4-rpz2+rl005.12-P1 &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 770.com
;; Got answer:
;; -&amp;gt;&amp;gt;HEADER&amp;lt;&amp;lt;- opcode: QUERY, status: NOERROR, id: 19146
;; flags: qr aa rd ra; QUERY: 1, ANSWER: 0, AUTHORITY: 0, ADDITIONAL: 0

;; QUESTION SECTION:
;770.com.                       IN      MX
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;ote-1:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Ote&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;; &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; DiG 9.8.4-rpz2+rl005.12-P1 &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 770.com
;; Got answer:
;; -&amp;gt;&amp;gt;HEADER&amp;lt;&amp;lt;- opcode: QUERY, status: NOERROR, id: 25114
;; flags: qr aa rd ra; QUERY: 1, ANSWER: 0, AUTHORITY: 1, ADDITIONAL: 0

;; QUESTION SECTION:
;770.com.                       IN      MX

;; AUTHORITY SECTION:
770.com.                86400   IN      SOA     localhost.
hostmaster.localhost. 2014030701 10800 3600 1814400 86400
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;vodafone-1:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Vodafone&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;; &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; DiG 9.9.5-4-Debian &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 888.com
;; Got answer:
;; -&amp;gt;&amp;gt;HEADER&amp;lt;&amp;lt;- opcode: QUERY, status: NOERROR, id: 50372
;; flags: qr aa rd ra; QUERY: 1, ANSWER: 0, AUTHORITY: 1, ADDITIONAL: 1

;; OPT PSEUDOSECTION:
; EDNS: version: 0, flags:; udp: 4096
;; QUESTION SECTION:
;888.com.                       IN      MX

;; AUTHORITY SECTION:
888.com.                600     IN      SOA     ns0.panafonet.gr.
root.iapetos.panafonet.gr. 2014180301 28800 7200 1209600 600
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;cosmote-1:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Cosmote&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;; &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; DiG 9.9.5-4-Debian &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 770.com
;; Got answer:
;; -&amp;gt;&amp;gt;HEADER&amp;lt;&amp;lt;- opcode: QUERY, status: NOERROR, id: 64761
;; flags: qr aa rd ra; QUERY: 1, ANSWER: 0, AUTHORITY: 1, ADDITIONAL: 1

;; OPT PSEUDOSECTION:
; EDNS: version: 0, flags:; udp: 4096
;; QUESTION SECTION:
;770.com.                       IN      MX

;; AUTHORITY SECTION:
770.com.                900     IN      SOA     nyma_grid_dns1.dcn.cosmote.gr.
please_set_email.absolutely.nowhere. 4 10800 3600 2419200 900
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;cyta-1:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Cyta&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;; &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; DiG 9.9.5-4-Debian &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 770.com
;; Got answer:
;; -&amp;gt;&amp;gt;HEADER&amp;lt;&amp;lt;- opcode: QUERY, status: NOERROR, id: 26529
;; flags: qr aa rd ra; QUERY: 1, ANSWER: 0, AUTHORITY: 1, ADDITIONAL: 1

;; OPT PSEUDOSECTION:
; EDNS: version: 0, flags:; udp: 4096
;; QUESTION SECTION:
;770.com.                       IN      MX

;; AUTHORITY SECTION:
770.com.                86400   IN      SOA     770.com. root.770.com. 42 10800
900 604800 86400
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;wind-mobile-1:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Wind mobile&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;; &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; DiG 9.8.4-rpz2+rl005.12-P1 &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 770.com
;; Got answer:
;; -&amp;gt;&amp;gt;HEADER&amp;lt;&amp;lt;- opcode: QUERY, status: NOERROR, id: 8803
;; flags: qr aa rd ra; QUERY: 1, ANSWER: 0, AUTHORITY: 1, ADDITIONAL: 0

;; QUESTION SECTION:
;770.com.                       IN      MX

;; AUTHORITY SECTION:
770.com.                86400   IN      SOA     localhost. root.localhost.
2013091901 14400 7200 604800 86400
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dns-a-records-resposnes:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;DNS A records resposnes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The correct A records of the censored domain names in example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;; &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; DiG 9.8.4-rpz2+rl005.12-P1 &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; A 770.com @8.8.8.8
;; global options: +cmd
;; Got answer:
;; -&amp;gt;&amp;gt;HEADER&amp;lt;&amp;lt;- opcode: QUERY, status: NOERROR, id: 47376
;; flags: qr rd ra; QUERY: 1, ANSWER: 1, AUTHORITY: 0, ADDITIONAL: 0

;; QUESTION SECTION:
;770.com.           IN  A

;; ANSWER SECTION:
770.com.        285 IN  A   69.93.79.125
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;; &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; DiG 9.8.4-rpz2+rl005.12-P1 &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; A box24casino.com @8.8.8.8
;; global options: +cmd
;; Got answer:
;; -&amp;gt;&amp;gt;HEADER&amp;lt;&amp;lt;- opcode: QUERY, status: NOERROR, id: 61390
;; flags: qr rd ra; QUERY: 1, ANSWER: 1, AUTHORITY: 0, ADDITIONAL: 0

;; QUESTION SECTION:
;box24casino.com.       IN  A

;; ANSWER SECTION:
box24casino.com.    899 IN  A   46.28.204.122
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;; &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; DiG 9.8.4-rpz2+rl005.12-P1 &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; A acelivecasino.com @8.8.8.8
;; global options: +cmd
;; Got answer:
;; -&amp;gt;&amp;gt;HEADER&amp;lt;&amp;lt;- opcode: QUERY, status: NOERROR, id: 64017
;; flags: qr rd ra; QUERY: 1, ANSWER: 1, AUTHORITY: 0, ADDITIONAL: 0

;; QUESTION SECTION:
;acelivecasino.com.     IN  A

;; ANSWER SECTION:
acelivecasino.com.  1799    IN  A   198.135.249.123
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spoofed A records entries of the ISPs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;forthnet-2:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Forthnet&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;; &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; DiG 9.8.4-rpz2+rl005.12-P1 &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; A 770.com
;; global options: +cmd
;; Got answer:
;; -&amp;gt;&amp;gt;HEADER&amp;lt;&amp;lt;- opcode: QUERY, status: NOERROR, id: 2445
;; flags: qr aa rd ra; QUERY: 1, ANSWER: 1, AUTHORITY: 0, ADDITIONAL: 0

;; QUESTION SECTION:
;770.com.                       IN      A

;; ANSWER SECTION:
770.com.                3600    IN      A       62.1.46.55
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;ote-2:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Ote&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;; &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; DiG 9.8.4-rpz2+rl005.12-P1 &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; A box24casino.com
;; global options: +cmd
;; Got answer:
;; -&amp;gt;&amp;gt;HEADER&amp;lt;&amp;lt;- opcode: QUERY, status: NOERROR, id: 60841
;; flags: qr rd ra; QUERY: 1, ANSWER: 1, AUTHORITY: 0, ADDITIONAL: 0

;; QUESTION SECTION:
;box24casino.com.               IN      A

;; ANSWER SECTION:
box24casino.com.        86191   IN      A       83.235.64.20
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;cyta-2:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Cyta&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;; &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; DiG 9.9.5-4-Debian &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 770.com
;; global options: +cmd
;; Got answer:
;; -&amp;gt;&amp;gt;HEADER&amp;lt;&amp;lt;- opcode: QUERY, status: NOERROR, id: 59438
;; flags: qr aa rd ad; QUERY: 1, ANSWER: 1, AUTHORITY: 0, ADDITIONAL: 1
;; WARNING: recursion requested but not available

;; OPT PSEUDOSECTION:
; EDNS: version: 0, flags:; udp: 4096
;; QUESTION SECTION:
;770.com.                       IN      A

;; ADDITIONAL SECTION:
770.com.                86400   IN      A       78.87.2.91
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;wind-1:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Wind&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;; &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; DiG 9.8.4-rpz2+rl005.12-P1 &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; A acelivecasino.com
;; global options: +cmd
;; Got answer:
;; -&amp;gt;&amp;gt;HEADER&amp;lt;&amp;lt;- opcode: QUERY, status: NOERROR, id: 21679
;; flags: qr rd ra; QUERY: 1, ANSWER: 1, AUTHORITY: 0, ADDITIONAL: 0

;; QUESTION SECTION:
;acelivecasino.com.             IN      A

;; ANSWER SECTION:
acelivecasino.com.      85963   IN      A       62.169.194.8
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;corollary:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Corollary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout our technical report we highlighted flaws in the implementation of
betting websites&amp;rsquo; censorship. Nevertheless, we do not seek for a properly
implemented censorship of any kind. Instead, our intention is to make visible
all those problematics that arise when censorship is invoked as method to
approach a social or public issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with poorly implemented censorship, is censorship per se.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ISPs in Greece haven&amp;rsquo;t provided any kind of notification to their customers to
inform them how the blocking took place, why this happened and if they can
opt-out from the service. After all, they are paying for the full service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lack of transparency on behalf of the providers, permits them to block and
censor arbitrary internet destinations according to their needs, thus following
a blocking-at-will strategy. Internet destinations may be accessible or not,
while users have no reasoning about it. That would lead to deliberate abuse of
citizens&amp;rsquo; accessibility and view of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;censorship-as-a-social-control-method:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Censorship as a social control method.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Censorship is introduced as a top-down method to solve pathogenic social
behaviours or phenomena. For example a state that censors a blog containing
caricatures of god with the pretense of confronting blasphemy. Or a state
that tries to protect public income by censoring betting companies&amp;rsquo; websites
that do not intend to pay taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with a top-down method is that frequently the ideas, the needs,
the culture of those on top -who actually take the decisions of what needs
to be censored- present deviations from the ideas and needs of the social
groups affected by the censorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally pathogenic social behaviours appear to majorly differ between
societies in different places of our planet or in different time points of
human evolution. For example, in some epoch owning other human beings as slaves
was socially acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, as a case study, we assume there is a commonly acknowledged social pathology.
Even then, censorship consists of imposition rather than education. Imposition
will result in fearful humans who do not understand why some specific behaviour
is banned, leading to more complex and problematic phenomena. On the other side,
educating individuals and social groups based on consensus and reasoning results
in free and healthy social relations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should also notice that censorship is bound to economic interests. Censorship
of betting websites by EEEP should not treated independently of the monopoly of
&amp;ldquo;ΟΠΑΠ&amp;rdquo; betting company that prevails in Greek territory. Spread of the internet led to
a conflict of interest between &amp;ldquo;ΟΠΑΠ&amp;rdquo; which holds physical betting kiosks and the
globalized market of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Censorship serving certain economic interests rises as a tool of manipulation of
users&amp;rsquo; choices, manipulation of the market and suggests corruption is part of the
public governance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;censorship-as-status-quo:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Censorship as status quo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If online censorship is widespread and accepted with little opposition as a way
to implement a broad range of public policy issues, it becomes far harder to
argue for Internet freedom and net neutrality elsewhere. Governments and
companies around the world use the same technologies to restrict access to
online content and offer the same arguments about taste, decency and citizens
safety &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openrightsgroup.org/ourwork/reports/mobile-internet-censorship:-whats-happening-and-what-we-can-do-about-it&#34;&gt;ORG&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In most cases, as long as censorship is introduced -with some legitimate or not
excuse- societies tend to accept the fact that censorship can exist and is justified.
Any debate will be probably help over what is just to censor and what is not, and
rarely censorship per se will be questioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This strategy is encountered in other politics sectors too, such as fees in public
transport or health insurance, issues that are of tremendous importance for our
societies and are a point of conflict in many countries worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as censorship is established, the set of entities that are being subjected
to censorship tends to grow. More and more censorship will be used as a method to
resolve problems or rather to enforce a certain type of approach to the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;censorship-s-side-effects:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Censorship&amp;rsquo;s side-effects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Censorship of some betting sites in Greece was implemented as a way to forbid
residents of Greece to bet on websites that do not intend to pay taxes i.e. the
goal of the censors appears to be to prevent players from betting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Censorship implementations includes some
side-effects: users are not only forbidden to play on these websites, but they
are also not being able to communicate (via email) with these companies. Censorship
is thus not limited to a specific problem (tax evasion) but it&amp;rsquo;s totally destroying
user&amp;rsquo;s experience and communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disrupting users&amp;rsquo; communication with a certain entity can have various social implications
or economic impact. Suppose a Greek resident would like to work as web developer to one
of the blocked websites. Communicating with the owner company would be impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ooni-data-per-isp:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;OONI data per ISP&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;raw-measurement-data-per-isp:d0c495f4479395eff703b25df5d2e963&#34;&gt;Raw measurement data per ISP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forthnet:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/2014-07-30/20140730T221712Z-GR-AS0-http_requests-no_report_id-0.1.0-probe.json&#34;&gt;HTTP Requests test report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/2014-06-23/20140623T125708Z-GR-AS1241-http_requests-no_report_id-0.1.0-probe.json&#34;&gt;HTTP Requests test report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/2014-06-25/20140625T222008Z-GR-AS1241-dns_consistency-no_report_id-0.1.0-probe.json&#34;&gt;DNS Consistency test report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ote:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/2014-06-26/20140626T105437Z-GR-AS6799-dns_consistency-no_report_id-0.1.0-probe.json&#34;&gt;DNS Consistency test report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/2014-06-26/20140626T130619Z-GR-AS6799-dns_consistency-no_report_id-0.1.0-probe.json&#34;&gt;DNS Consistency test report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/2014-06-25/20140625T210158Z-GR-AS0-http_requests-no_report_id-0.1.0-probe.json&#34;&gt;HTTP Requests test report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/2014-06-25/20140625T211147Z-GR-AS0-http_requests-no_report_id-0.1.0-probe.json&#34;&gt;HTTP Requests test report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyta:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/2014-06-23/20140623T165118Z-GR-AS0-http_requests-no_report_id-0.1.0-probe.json&#34;&gt;HTTP Requests test report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/2014-07-30/20140730T224459Z-GR-AS0-http_requests-no_report_id-0.1.0-probe.json&#34;&gt;HTTP Requests test report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hol:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/2014-07-24/20140724T164440Z-GR-AS3329-http_requests-no_report_id-0.1.0-probe.json&#34;&gt;HTTP Requests test report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/2014-07-24/20140724T160923Z-GR-AS3329-http_requests-no_report_id-0.1.0-probe.json&#34;&gt;HTTP Requests test report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/2014-07-24/20140724T161705Z-GR-AS3329-dns_consistency-no_report_id-0.1.0-probe.json&#34;&gt;DNS Consistency test report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cosmote:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/2014-07-03/20140703T161600Z-GR-AS0-http_requests-no_report_id-0.1.0-probe.json&#34;&gt;HTTP Requests test report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vodafone:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/2014-07-03/20140703T083044Z-ZZ-AS0-http_requests-no_report_id-0.1.0-probe.json&#34;&gt;HTTP Requests test report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wind mobile:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/2014-07-04/20140704T025958Z-GR-AS0-http_requests-no_report_id-0.1.0-probe.json&#34;&gt;HTTP Requests test report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/2014-07-30/20140730T200818Z-GR-AS15617-http_requests-no_report_id-0.1.0-probe.json&#34;&gt;HTTP Requests test report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- # References --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>