<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title>
    <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/categories/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ooni.torproject.org/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OONI at the CryptoRave 2017</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ooni-cryptorave-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ooni-cryptorave-2017/</guid>
      <description>CryptoRave is a free, non-commercial and collectively funded 48 hour event featuring talks, workshops and activities related to security, privacy, anonymity, hacking and freedom of expression that attracts more that 2,500 people mainly from South America. The event took place in São Paulo, Brazil on 5th and 6th May 2017.
A number of people attended the OONI presentation and workshop (&amp;ldquo;Listatona&amp;rdquo;) that was co-organized with Coding Rights. During the workshop participants were able to better understand OONI&amp;rsquo;s testing methodology, and how ooniprobe performs network measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OONI at the Internet Freedom Festival &amp; RightsCon 2017</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ooni-iff-rightscon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ooni-iff-rightscon/</guid>
      <description>Over the last month the OONI team joined the internet freedom community at the following events:
 Vietnam Cyber Dialogue (VCD)
 Internet Freedom Festival (IFF)
 Iran Cyber Dialogue (ICD)
 RightsCon 2017
 International Journalism Festival (IJF)
  These events provided us with the opportunity to engage with community members, create new friendships, learn about new projects, and to share skills and knowledge. We also had the opportunity to facilitate sessions that allowed us to collect feedback for the improvement of our software and research methodologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urandom.pcap: Belarus (finally) bans Tor</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/belarus-fries-onion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/belarus-fries-onion/</guid>
      <description>Country: Belarus
Probed ISPs: Beltelecom (AS 6697)
Censorship method: TCP injections
We have recently heard of network anomalies in Belarus. Tor has been finally blocked in December 2016, although it had been explicitly declared that Tor should be blocked since February 2015.
An anonymous cypherpunk has helped to gather some evidence regarding Tor being blocked in Belarus. It&amp;rsquo;s neither a complete study nor an in-depth research and it&amp;rsquo;s unclear if any other further evidence will be gathered, so we decided to share current knowledge as-is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OONI releases Lepidopter Raspberry Pi distribution</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/lepidopter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/lepidopter/</guid>
      <description>The Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) team is happy to announce the beta release of ooniprobe&amp;rsquo;s distribution for Raspberry Pis, caĺled Lepidopter.
What is Lepidopter Lepidopter is a Raspberry Pi distribution image with all the required dependencies and software packages in place, configured to run network measurement tests via the ooniprobe software. It is developed and designed to require no physical attendance upon first bootstrap but also allows experienced users to further configure it as they wish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OONI releases new Web Connectivity test for detecting online censorship</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/web-connectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/web-connectivity/</guid>
      <description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) is excited to be releasing a brand new test, called Web Connectivity, which is designed to detect three different types of censorship: DNS tampering, TCP/IP blocking and HTTP blocking.
Advantages of running Web Connectivity This test allows us to see which websites are blocked and how, more accurately than ever before!
Previously we relied on running separate (http_request, dns_consistency and tcp_connect) tests with the aim of identifying various forms of censorship.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>