<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title>
    <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 15:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ooni.torproject.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#EgyptCensors: Evidence of recent censorship events in Egypt</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/egypt-censors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/egypt-censors/</guid>
      <description>Country: Egypt
OONI tests: Web Connectivity, HTTP Header Field Manipulation, HTTP Invalid Request Line, HTTP Host, Vanilla Tor.
Probed ISPs: Link Egypt (AS24863), Vodafone Egypt (AS36935), Telecom Egypt (AS8452).
Analysis period: 23rd May 2017 to 17th June 2017.
Censorship method: Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) used to RESET connections.
Starting on May 24th, the Egyptian government ordered ISPs to block at least 21 news websites on the grounds of “supporting terrorism and spreading lies”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Internet Censorship in Indonesia</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/indonesia-internet-censorship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/indonesia-internet-censorship/</guid>
      <description>Image: Block page in Indonesia
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Sinar Project.
Table of contents
 Key Findings
 Introduction
 Background
 Network landscape and internet penetration
 Legal environment
 Freedom of expression
 Press freedom
 Access to information
 Privacy
 Censorship and surveillance
  Reported cases of internet censorship and surveillance
 Examining internet censorship in Indonesia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OONI at the CryptoRave 2017</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ooni-cryptorave-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ooni-cryptorave-2017/</guid>
      <description>CryptoRave is a free, non-commercial and collectively funded 48 hour event featuring talks, workshops and activities related to security, privacy, anonymity, hacking and freedom of expression that attracts more that 2,500 people mainly from South America. The event took place in São Paulo, Brazil on 5th and 6th May 2017.
A number of people attended the OONI presentation and workshop (&amp;ldquo;Listatona&amp;rdquo;) that was co-organized with Coding Rights. During the workshop participants were able to better understand OONI&amp;rsquo;s testing methodology, and how ooniprobe performs network measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OONI at the Internet Freedom Festival &amp; RightsCon 2017</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ooni-iff-rightscon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ooni-iff-rightscon/</guid>
      <description>Over the last month the OONI team joined the internet freedom community at the following events:
 Vietnam Cyber Dialogue (VCD)
 Internet Freedom Festival (IFF)
 Iran Cyber Dialogue (ICD)
 RightsCon 2017
 International Journalism Festival (IJF)
  These events provided us with the opportunity to engage with community members, create new friendships, learn about new projects, and to share skills and knowledge. We also had the opportunity to facilitate sessions that allowed us to collect feedback for the improvement of our software and research methodologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Internet Censorship in Myanmar</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/myanmar-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 13:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/myanmar-report/</guid>
      <description>A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI), Sinar Project, and the Myanmar ICT for Development Organization (MIDO).
Table of contents
 Key Findings
 Introduction
 Background
 Network landscape and internet penetration
 Legal environment
 Freedom of expression
 Press freedom
 Access to information
 Privacy
 Censorship and surveillance
  Reported cases of internet censorship and surveillance
 Examining internet censorship in Myanmar</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examining internet blackouts through public data sources</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/examining-internet-blackouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 16:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/examining-internet-blackouts/</guid>
      <description>Pulling the plug on the internet is one of the ways that governments around the world attempt to exert control over the flow of information.
While the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project has developed numerous software tests for examining different forms of internet censorship (such as the blocking of websites, instant messaging apps, and censorship circumvention tools), we currently do not have tests that are designed to examine internet blackouts, when the internet as a whole is rendered inaccessible within a location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Internet Censorship in Thailand</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/thailand-internet-censorship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/thailand-internet-censorship/</guid>
      <description>Image: Block page in Thailand
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI), Sinar Project, and the Thai Netizen Network.
Table of contents
 Key Findings
 Introduction
 Background
 Network landscape and internet penetration
 Legal environment
 Freedom of expression
 Press freedom
 Access to information
 Privacy
 Censorship and surveillance
  Reported cases of internet censorship and surveillance
 Examining internet censorship in Thailand</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New ooniprobe Mobile App: Measure Internet Censorship &amp; Performance</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ooni-mobile-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ooni-mobile-app/</guid>
      <description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project is thrilled to announce the release of a new mobile app (“ooniprobe - Measure Internet Censorship &amp;amp; Performance”) that can now be installed on Android and iOS for testing Internet censorship and network performance.
     By running the tests included in OONI’s mobile app, you can monitor:
 Blocking of websites; Presence of systems that could be responsible for censorship or surveillance; Speed and performance of your network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kenya: Censorship-free internet?</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/kenya-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/kenya-study/</guid>
      <description>Over the last five months we ran OONI tests in Kenya almost every day to examine whether internet censorship events were occurring in the country. Hundreds of thousands of network measurements were collected and analyzed. 1,357 URLs were tested for censorship, including both international websites and sites that are more relevant to Kenya (e.g. local news outlets). Yet, after five months of intensive testing from four local vantage points in Kenya, we found almost no signs of internet censorship in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Internet Censorship in Malaysia</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/malaysia-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/malaysia-report/</guid>
      <description>Block page in Malaysia
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Sinar Project.
Table of contents
 Key Findings
 Introduction
 Background
 Network landscape and internet penetration
 Legal environment
 Freedom of expression
 Press freedom
 Access to information
 Privacy
 Censorship and surveillance
  Previous cases of internet censorship and surveillance
 Examining internet censorship in Malaysia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New OONI tests examine the blocking of WhatsApp and Facebook Messenger</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/whatsapp-and-facebook-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/whatsapp-and-facebook-tests/</guid>
      <description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project is excited to announce the release of two new software tests which are designed to examine the blocking of WhatsApp and Facebook Messenger. You can now run these tests to monitor the accessibility of these apps across time, and to collect data that can serve as evidence when/if they are blocked.
WhatsApp test Many of our users have asked us to develop a test to examine the accessibility of WhatsApp, especially in light of it being blocked by various governments around the world during elections, protests, and other political events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethiopia: Evidence of social media blocking and internet censorship</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ethiopia-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ethiopia-report/</guid>
      <description>Youth in Addis trying to get Wi-Fi Connection. Credit Addis Fortune Newspaper
Recently we published a post about what appeared to be a possible internet shutdown in Ethiopia during a wave of ongoing protests by ethnic groups. Today, in collaboration with Amnesty International we are releasing a report that includes evidence of recent censorship events during Ethiopia’s political upheaval.
View the pdf version of the report here.
Country: Ethiopia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OONI releases new web UI: Run censorship tests from your web browser!</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/web-ui-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/web-ui-post/</guid>
      <description>Today we are excited to announce the beta release of our new web-based user interface (WUI) that enables ooniprobe users to run censorship tests from a web browser!
Whether you’re running ooniprobe from your desktop or a Raspberry Pi, you can now easily choose which tests you want to run through OONI’s web UI and run them with the click of a button. These tests are designed to examine the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gambia: Internet Shutdown during 2016 Presidential Election</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/gambia-internet-shutdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/gambia-internet-shutdown/</guid>
      <description>Last week we attempted to perform OONI network measurement tests in the Gambia to examine whether websites were blocked during its 2016 presidential election. But merely a few hours after we connected our probe to perform tests, it stopped working completely.
We suspected that this was due to an internet shutdown. To confirm this, we referred to third-party data to examine whether a country-wide internet blackout was taking place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urandom.pcap: Belarus (finally) bans Tor</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/belarus-fries-onion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/belarus-fries-onion/</guid>
      <description>Country: Belarus
Probed ISPs: Beltelecom (AS 6697)
Censorship method: TCP injections
We have recently heard of network anomalies in Belarus. Tor has been finally blocked in December 2016, although it had been explicitly declared that Tor should be blocked since February 2015.
An anonymous cypherpunk has helped to gather some evidence regarding Tor being blocked in Belarus. It&amp;rsquo;s neither a complete study nor an in-depth research and it&amp;rsquo;s unclear if any other further evidence will be gathered, so we decided to share current knowledge as-is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OONI releases Lepidopter Raspberry Pi distribution</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/lepidopter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/lepidopter/</guid>
      <description>The Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) team is happy to announce the beta release of ooniprobe&amp;rsquo;s distribution for Raspberry Pis, caĺled Lepidopter.
What is Lepidopter Lepidopter is a Raspberry Pi distribution image with all the required dependencies and software packages in place, configured to run network measurement tests via the ooniprobe software. It is developed and designed to require no physical attendance upon first bootstrap but also allows experienced users to further configure it as they wish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OONI-dev meeting and hackathon 2016</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ooni-dev-and-hackathon-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ooni-dev-and-hackathon-2016/</guid>
      <description>Oonitarians are spread out across the globe, and OONI’s core team is no exception. We recently met in Berlin to hack on OONI’s software, work on our roadmap, and to have all those discussions that are more fruitful to have in person than on IRC. We also held a hackathon to engage new individuals with our project!
Below we document some of the things that we worked on as part of our OONI-dev meeting and hackathon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Egypt: Media censorship, Tor interference, HTTPS throttling and ads injections?</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/egypt-network-interference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/egypt-network-interference/</guid>
      <description>Country: Egypt
Probed ISPs: Noor (AS 20928), TE Data (AS 8452), Vodafone (AS 24835)
Censorship method: DPI, network throttling, TCP injections
OONI tests: HTTP Requests, Web Connectivity, Vanilla Tor
Measurement period: 2016-08-27 - 2016-10-26
We recently noticed network anomalies in Egypt and performed a study in an attempt to understand the situation.
Our findings indicate that the Tor anonymity network appeared to be interfered with in Egypt, while HTTPS connections to DigitalOcean&amp;rsquo;s Frankfurt data centre were throttled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OONI Hackathon: Join us to explore internet censorship!</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/berlin-hackathon-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/berlin-hackathon-2016/</guid>
      <description>Interested in exploring (and exposing) internet censorship? Join the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) hackathon in Berlin!
 When? Friday, 11th November &amp;amp; Saturday, 12th November 2016
 Where? The OnionSpace (Gottschedstraße 4, 13357 Berlin, Germany)
 What time? 10am onwards
 Who? Software developers, data analysts, academics, journalists, bloggers, lawyers, activists, and all those who don’t go by any particular label, but are curious enough to join! We only have one rule: Be excellent to each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zambia: Internet censorship during the 2016 general elections?</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/zambia-election-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 10:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/zambia-election-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Strathmore University’s Centre for Intellectual Property and Information Technology Law (CIPIT).
Table of contents
 Key Findings
 Introduction
 Background
 Network landscape and internet penetration
 Legal environment
 Freedom of expression
 Press freedom
 Access to information
 Privacy
 Censorship and surveillance
  Previous cases of internet censorship and surveillance
 Zambia’s 2016 general elections and constitutional referendum</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethiopia: Internet Shutdown Amidst Recent Protests?</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ethiopia-internet-shutdown-amidst-recent-protests/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/ethiopia-internet-shutdown-amidst-recent-protests/</guid>
      <description>Nearly 100 deaths and thousands of arrests have been reported in Ethiopia over the last days, as part of protests against the marginalization and persecution of the Oromos and Amharas, Ethiopia’s two largest ethnic groups. But the attacks and arrests may not have been the only forms of retribution carried out by the Ethiopian government in its crackdown against protesters.
Last weekend, the internet was reportedly shut down in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Access Disruption in Turkey - July 2016</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/turkey-internet-access-disruption/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/turkey-internet-access-disruption/</guid>
      <description>With the attempted coup in Turkey, reports went out about social media being throttled and/or blocked. We analysed data about this that we collected with RIPE Atlas and the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI).
On 15 July, a coup was attempted in Turkey. We heard about social media being throttled and/or blocked, but much was unclear about what was actually going on. Here we present measurement data from various platforms that shared their data publicly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OONI releases new Web Connectivity test for detecting online censorship</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/web-connectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/web-connectivity/</guid>
      <description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) is excited to be releasing a brand new test, called Web Connectivity, which is designed to detect three different types of censorship: DNS tampering, TCP/IP blocking and HTTP blocking.
Advantages of running Web Connectivity This test allows us to see which websites are blocked and how, more accurately than ever before!
Previously we relied on running separate (http_request, dns_consistency and tcp_connect) tests with the aim of identifying various forms of censorship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Uganda blocked social media, again</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/uganda-social-media-blocked/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/uganda-social-media-blocked/</guid>
      <description>Country: Uganda
Probed ISPs: Orange (AS36991), SMILE (AS37122)
Censorship method: IP blocking
OONI tests: HTTP Requests
Measurement period: 2016-05-12
Last Wednesday, the Ugandan Communications Commission (UCC) ordered ISPs to block access to social media leading up to the (fifth) inauguration of President Yoweri Museveni, who has governed the country since 1986. Authorities argued that the blocking was ordered for “security purposes”, but the move directly harms political opposition, which has relied on social media to organize a “defiance campaign” of protests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OONI Data Reveals How WhatsApp Was Blocked (Again) in Brazil</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/brazil-whatsapp-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/brazil-whatsapp-block/</guid>
      <description>Country: Brazil
Probed ISPs: Tim mobile (AS 26615), Oi landline (AS 7738)
Censorship method: DNS Hijacking
OONI tests: HTTP Requests, DNS Consistency
Measurement period: 2016-05-02 - 2016-05-03
Portoguese Translation
19:10 UTC Saturday, 7 May 2016 Update: Add OONI Explorer measurements links
Ever since WhatsApp implemented end-to-end encryption to protect the privacy and security of its 1 billion users worldwide, several cases of censorship have been ordered by governments who are frustrated with the fact that they can no longer access users&amp;rsquo; private communications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WhatsApp bloqueado (outra vez) no Brasil</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/brazil-whatsapp-block-pt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/brazil-whatsapp-block-pt/</guid>
      <description>Pais: Brasil
ISPs investigados: Tim mobile (AS 26615), Oi landline (AS 7738)
Método de censura: DNS Hijacking
OONI testes: HTTP Requests, DNS Consistency
Periodo da medição: 2016-05-02 - 2016-05-03
Translation by: Kornelia Friesch
Post in original language
Desde que o WhatsApp implantou a codificação end-to-end (end-to-end encryption) para proteger a privacidade e segurança dos, em nível mundial, um bilhão de usuários, manifestaram-se, alguns casos de censura ordenados por governos irritando-se pelo fato de não terem mais acesso à comunicação privada dos cidadãos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EEEP and Greek Internet censorship</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/eeep-greek-censorship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/eeep-greek-censorship/</guid>
      <description>Country: Greece
Probed ISPs: Forthnet, Ote, Cyta, Wind, Vodafone, Cosmote, Wind mobile
Blocking methods: DPI, DNS Hijacking, HTTP proxy
Measurement period: June - July 2014
19:40 UTC Saturday, 17 June 2016 Update: Add AS numbers of the ISPs, update raw measurement data URLs.
The newly formed Independent Administrative Authority&amp;rsquo;s Hellenic Gaming Commission acts as the public body responsible for the control and supervision of gambling services in Greece and published a blacklist of websites that are offering unlicensed gambling and betting services to Greek internet users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zambia, a country under Deep Packet Inspection</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/zambia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/zambia/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I do not have the details of the blocking of Zambianwatchdog.com, but I would celebrate.&amp;rdquo; Guy Scott Zambian Vicepresident, Friday 28th June 2013
The following article is a guest blog post by Mr T. an independent researcher and provider of hosting to various grass roots organizations.
This article summarizes how we discovered that the grass roots online newspaper Zambianwatchdog.com was being blocked inside Zambia. This report provides technical evidence of the unlawful presence of Deep Packet Inspection in the country to monitor the Internet communications and stop users from browsing the website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tab-Tab, Come in! Bypassing Internet blocking to categorize DPI devices</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/tab-tab-come-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/tab-tab-come-in/</guid>
      <description>Motivation During the past two years, we have been following the technical developments in Internet filtering in Uzbekistan and Turkmenistan. Internet users were reporting that some websites were blocked, connections were reseted and in some cases users were redirected to another website.
Apart from our technical curiosity of how Internet filtering is implemented at large scale and how it can be circumvented, we are interested in providing technical facts of how blocking is taking place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hadara Palestine</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/hadara-palestine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/hadara-palestine/</guid>
      <description>ooni_test: HTTP Host
country: Palestine
provider: Hadara, Paltel
product: Squid
product_website: http://www.squid-cache.org/
censorship method: Transparent HTTP proxy
downloads:
 Full scan result List of censored sites  This is the technical report on the politically motivated censorship going on in Bethlehem, West Bank.
These are the networks in question:
inetnum: 82.205.96.0 - 82.205.103.255 netname: GZ-HOME-BR1 descr: GAZA BSA HOME country: PS admin-c: WK4085-RIPE tech-c: HT1472-RIPE status: ASSIGNED PA mnt-by: Palnet-mnt source: RIPE # Filtered inetnum: 212.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T-Mobile USA Web Guard</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/t-mobile-usa-web-guard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/t-mobile-usa-web-guard/</guid>
      <description>ooni_test: HTTP Host
country: United States
provider: T-Mobile USA
product: Web Guard
product_website: http://support.t-mobile.com/docs/DOC-2144
censorship_method: Transparent HTTP proxy
downloads:
 Full scan result List of censored sites Categories of censored sites  T-Mobile USA offers a &amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; to restrict access to certain kinds of content. This is called Web Guard. Supposedly Web Guard is supposed to inhibit access to content that falls under the following categories: Alcohol, Mature Content, Violence, Drugs, Pornography, Weapons, Gambling, Suicide, Guns, Hate, Tobacco, Ammunition.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>