<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Event on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title>
    <link>http://ooni.io/tags/event/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Event on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://ooni.io/tags/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>ADINA15: A Dive Into Network Anomalies</title>
      <link>http://ooni.io/event/adina15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ooni.io/event/adina15/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ooni-hackathon:550281d282d64ceb2dd86438c13e2d48&#34;&gt;OONI Hackathon&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;adina15:550281d282d64ceb2dd86438c13e2d48&#34;&gt;#ADINA15&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you like playing with open data and producing some good looking graphics
about them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you fancy spending some time in the Italian Parliament in Rome hacking on
internet censorship data and &lt;a href=&#34;http://api.ooni.io/&#34;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; gathered by
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;OONI&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then submit an application to join us from the 1st of October
to the 2nd of October 2015 at the OONI Open Data Hackfest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All humans welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ooni:550281d282d64ceb2dd86438c13e2d48&#34;&gt;OONI?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI is a platform for conducting and publishing measurements useful to study
censorship and surveillance on the Internet. It consists of an open data
format, an open source software implementation for several platforms, and a
public archive of over 15000 measurements collected from about 70 countries
worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what:550281d282d64ceb2dd86438c13e2d48&#34;&gt;WHAT&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two days of collaborative hacking on visualizations and tools that utilize the
OONI dataset to study censorship hosted at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.camera.it&#34;&gt;Italian Chamber of Deputies&lt;/a&gt; and
organized by the OONI project in collaboration with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://nexa.polito.it/&#34;&gt;Nexa Center for
Internet &amp;amp; Society&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be in the format of a code-a-thon, where people work in groups on a
specific project and at the end of the event the results produced by every team
will be evaluated by a jury. It will kick off with a short presentation that
sets the stage for the context of the event. Participants should have chosen
beforehand the specific type of project they would like to work on during the
event. We will provide a list of sample projects that people can pick from
to give an idea of what are the sort of things that are possible, but it is
encouraged for participants to submit their own idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A symbolic prize will be given to the first three teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;why:550281d282d64ceb2dd86438c13e2d48&#34;&gt;WHY&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OONI project builds tools to study internet censorship. Now your
contribution is needed to understand OONI data and make them more accessible to
society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got an idea? Want to build it? We want to hack with you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making internet censorship data (and, more generally, network measurements)
easier to understand and study is crucial to foster an informed democratic
debate on the governance of the internet. Democratic societies sometimes need
to restrict access to certain content to safeguard the public interest; this
leads to interesting research and policy questions such as how to transparently
implement such means and how to openly verify that only what should be blocked
is blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;who:550281d282d64ceb2dd86438c13e2d48&#34;&gt;WHO&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We invite all people that have a background in design and, in particular, in
information design or in data visualization. A strong technical background is not
needed though it is useful to have. Members of the core OONI development team
will also be part of the event and will be iterating over the various
participating teams to provide technical insight and help out with the needed
coding tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;when:550281d282d64ceb2dd86438c13e2d48&#34;&gt;WHEN&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hackathon will run from October 1st to October 2nd 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;october-1st:550281d282d64ceb2dd86438c13e2d48&#34;&gt;October 1st&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;09:00 Start of event (Organizers should be there at 8 AM)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:00 Introduction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:00 The hackathon begins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13:00 Buffet lunch[a]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20:00 Wrap up for the day, you can hack more, but not here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;october-2nd:550281d282d64ceb2dd86438c13e2d48&#34;&gt;October 2nd&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;09:00 Venue opens&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:00 The hackathon begins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13:00 Buffet lunch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;16:00 Deadline for submissions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19:00 Award ceremony&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;where:550281d282d64ceb2dd86438c13e2d48&#34;&gt;WHERE&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hackathon will be at the Chamber of Deputies of the Italian Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the address of the room:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nuova Sala dei Gruppi Camera dei Deputati
Via Campo Marzio 78
Rome, Italy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for each event organized at the Italian Parliament, the following rules apply:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participants and their belongings will be subject to security check;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smoking inside is forbidden;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participants must be at least fourteen years old;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Smart casual attire is required (i.e. male bodied humans must &lt;strong&gt;wear a suit
jacket at all times&lt;/strong&gt;).
Note: this rule is actually enforced very strictly and if you show up without
a jacket you may not be able to attend the hackathon;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Food or beverages may not be consumed inside the room;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is forbidden to request and/or to pay for participation fee within the venue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;travel-information:550281d282d64ceb2dd86438c13e2d48&#34;&gt;Travel information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rome is served by two airports FCO (Rome Fiumicino) and CIA (Rome Ciampino).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From FCO it is possible to take the train to either Termini central station or
to various stations spread around the city (Trastevere, Ostiense, Tiburtina,
Tuscolana).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From CIA there are busses that run regularly and connect you to the Termini
central station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The venue itself is close to the Metro A stops called Spagna and Barberini.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;prizes:550281d282d64ceb2dd86438c13e2d48&#34;&gt;PRIZES&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-be-announced:550281d282d64ceb2dd86438c13e2d48&#34;&gt;To be announced!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rules:550281d282d64ceb2dd86438c13e2d48&#34;&gt;RULES&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the following rules must be followed when working on your project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;projects must use OONI data as the main theme of the visualisation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;all data used in the project should either already be public or should be
published before judging takes place using an open license&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;collaboration is encouraged and you are expected to work as part of a team&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;submissions must be free and open source software and may be featured on the
OONI website&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hackfest is an environment in which to hack, meet new people, get creative,
and have a good time. in order to make sure this event is enjoyable for
everyone involved we ask that you be excellent to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting something meaningful done within such a short amount of time can be
stressful, but we&amp;rsquo;d like to encourage everyone to take a break every now and
then to relax and enjoy the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attendees violating these rules may be asked to leave the hackfest at the sole
discretion of the organizers. thank you for helping make this a welcoming,
friendly event for all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>