<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About-rsses on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title>
    <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in About-rsses on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://ooni.torproject.org/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/data-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/data-policy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ooni-data-policy&#34;&gt;OONI Data Policy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Effective:&lt;/strong&gt; 2016-05-05&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.0.0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Data Policy explains what data is collected, processed, stored and
published by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Open Observatory of Network Interference
(OONI)&lt;/a&gt; project, as well as how users can opt-out
from sending OONI their network measurements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of OONI&amp;rsquo;s software and website constitutes an acceptance of the policies
outlined in this Data Policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;website-visitors&#34;&gt;Website Visitors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; use tracking cookies, analytics or any other tracking
technologies through its &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; and does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;
collect any information about its website visitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Access logs, which only include the date of the requested page, can be stored
for up to 2 weeks and do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; include the IP addresses of website visitors nor
the time of access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this changes in the future, users will be notified through this Data Policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-users&#34;&gt;Software Users&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI&amp;rsquo;s software is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; designed to protect user privacy, but is developed by
people who &lt;em&gt;care&lt;/em&gt; about user privacy. While OONI developers take measures to
protect users&amp;rsquo; privacy by &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; deliberately collecting their IP addresses,
users might still potentially face risks as a result of OONI&amp;rsquo;s data collection,
processing, storing and publishing methods, as explained below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To mitigate such potential risks, users can choose to &lt;em&gt;opt-out&lt;/em&gt; from certain or
all types of data collection by OONI, though this would limit OONI&amp;rsquo;s research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-ooni-collects&#34;&gt;Data OONI Collects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a user runs &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-spec&#34;&gt;OONI software
tests&lt;/a&gt;, the OONI project can
collect the following types of data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Country code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI &lt;em&gt;by default&lt;/em&gt; collects the code which corresponds to the country from which
the user is running OONI tests from, by automatically searching for it based on
the user&amp;rsquo;s IP address through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.maxmind.com/en/home&#34;&gt;MaxMind GeoIP
database&lt;/a&gt;. The collection of country codes is
an important part of OONI&amp;rsquo;s research, as it enables OONI to map out global
network measurements and to identify where network interferences take place.
This information could potentially be useful to local researchers, journalists
and advocates who aim to discover network interferences (such as censorship and
traffic manipulation) in a country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI software users can choose to &lt;em&gt;opt-out&lt;/em&gt; from the collection of country codes
by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-probe#configuring-ooniprobe&#34;&gt;editing the ooniprobe
 configuration&lt;/a&gt;
file inside of &lt;code&gt;~/.ooni/ooniprobe.conf&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autonomous System Number (ASN)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI &lt;em&gt;by default&lt;/em&gt; collects the Autonomous System Number (ASN) which corresponds
to the network that a user is running OONI tests from. The collection of the ASN
is useful to OONI&amp;rsquo;s research because it reveals the specific network provider
(such as Vodafone) of a user. Such information can increase transparency in
regards to which network providers are implementing censorship or other forms of
network interference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI software users can choose to &lt;em&gt;opt-out&lt;/em&gt; from the collection of their
network&amp;rsquo;s ASN by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-probe#configuring-ooniprobe&#34;&gt;editing the ooniprobe
configuration&lt;/a&gt;
file inside of  &lt;code&gt;~/.ooni/ooniprobe.conf&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date and time of measurements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI &lt;em&gt;by default&lt;/em&gt; collects the time and date of when tests were run. This
information helps OONI evaluate when network interferences occur and to compare
them across time. Users &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; opt-out from this type of data collection, as
it is a core component of OONI&amp;rsquo;s research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IP addresses and other information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; deliberately collect or store users&amp;rsquo; IP addresses. In fact, OONI
takes measures to remove users&amp;rsquo; IP addresses from the collected measurements, to
protect its users from potential risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, OONI might &lt;em&gt;unintentionally&lt;/em&gt; collect users&amp;rsquo; IP addresses and other
potentially personally-identifiable information, if such information is included
in the HTTP headers or other metadata of measurements. This, for example, can
occur if the tested websites include tracking technologies or custom content
based on a user&amp;rsquo;s network location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, OONI does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; collect users&amp;rsquo; IP addresses, but they can choose to
&lt;em&gt;opt-in&lt;/em&gt; (to provide more accurate information) by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-probe#configuring-ooniprobe&#34;&gt;editing the ooniprobe
 configuration&lt;/a&gt;
file inside of &lt;code&gt;~/.ooni/ooniprobe.conf&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network measurements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The types of network measurements that OONI collects depend on the types of
tests that are run. Specifications about each OONI test can be viewed
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-spec/tree/master/test-specs&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and
details about what collected network measurements entail can be viewed through
&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/world/&#34;&gt;OONI Explorer&lt;/a&gt; or through OONI&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;public list of measurements&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI software users can choose to &lt;em&gt;opt-out&lt;/em&gt; from sending OONI their measurements
by running ooniprobe with the &lt;code&gt;-n&lt;/code&gt; command line option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-ooni-processes&#34;&gt;Data OONI Processes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through its &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-pipeline&#34;&gt;data pipeline&lt;/a&gt;,
OONI processes all of the network measurements that it collects, which include
the aforementioned types of data. OONI processes data with the aim of deriving
meaning from the collected measurements and, specifically, in an attempt to
answer the following types of questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which types of OONI tests were run?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In which countries were those tests run?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In which networks were those tests run?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When were tests run?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What types of network interferences occurred?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In which countries did network interferences occur?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In which networks did network interferences occur?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When did network interferences occur?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did network interferences occur?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer such questions, OONI&amp;rsquo;s pipeline is designed to process data which is
automatically sent to OONI&amp;rsquo;s measurement collector by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users can choose to &lt;em&gt;opt-out&lt;/em&gt; from sending OONI their measurements by running
ooniprobe with the &lt;code&gt;-n&lt;/code&gt; command line option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-ooni-stores&#34;&gt;Data OONI Stores&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI stores all of the aforementioned data that it collects and processes,
including users&amp;rsquo; IP addresses and other potentially personally-identifiable
information which &lt;em&gt;might unintentionally&lt;/em&gt; be collected and therefore stored,
despite OONI&amp;rsquo;s efforts to prevent this from happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users can &lt;em&gt;opt-out&lt;/em&gt; from sending specific types of data to OONI&amp;rsquo;s measurement
collector as described in previous sections of this Data Policy, or they can
&lt;em&gt;opt-out&lt;/em&gt; from sending OONI any of their measurements by running ooniprobe with
the &lt;code&gt;-n&lt;/code&gt; command line option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-ooni-publishes&#34;&gt;Data OONI Publishes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI publishes all of the network measurement data that it collects and
processes because open data allows third parties to conduct independent studies,
to verify OONI findings and/or to answer other research questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, OONI publishes all collected measurements on its website
through:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/world/&#34;&gt;OONI Explorer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;OONI&amp;rsquo;s list of measurements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both resources include the same measurements; the only difference is that OONI
Explorer is an interactive visualization of the measurements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If users&amp;rsquo; IP addresses and/or other potentially personally-identifiable
information are included in the HTTP headers or other metadata of collected
measurements, then such information &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; be publicly available through the
above resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that the publication of network measurements might raise
various types of &lt;em&gt;risks&lt;/em&gt; for OONI users. Information about such risks can be
found &lt;a href=&#34;INCLUDE LINK&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Users can also consider opting-out from submitting
some or all of their measurements to OONI through the following opt-out section
of this Data Policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;opt-out&#34;&gt;Opt-out&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI software users can &lt;em&gt;opt-out&lt;/em&gt; from sending OONI&amp;rsquo;s measurement collector
specific types of data by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-probe#configuring-ooniprobe&#34;&gt;editing the ooniprobe
 configuration&lt;/a&gt;
 file inside of &lt;code&gt;~/.ooni/ooniprobe.conf&lt;/code&gt;. Through this file, users can opt-out
from sending OONI the following types of information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Country code&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autonomous System Number (ASN)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, OONI does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; collect users&amp;rsquo; IP addresses, but users can choose to
&lt;em&gt;opt-in&lt;/em&gt; (to provide more accurate information) through the above configuration
file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users can also choose to &lt;em&gt;opt-out&lt;/em&gt; from sending OONI&amp;rsquo;s measurement collector any
data at all, by running ooniprobe with the &lt;code&gt;-n&lt;/code&gt; command line option. This option
is quite often chosen by users who prefer to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have their measurements
published, due to potential risks that could emerge as a result of such
publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-policy-changes&#34;&gt;Data Policy Changes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although most changes are likely to be minor, OONI may change its Data Policy
from time to time, and in OONI&amp;rsquo;s sole discretion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI encourages its website visitors and software users to frequently check this
page for any changes to its Data Policy. The continued use of OONI&amp;rsquo;s website and
software after any change in this Data Policy will constitute acceptance of such
change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoughts or questions about this Data Policy? Please send an email to
&lt;strong&gt;contact@openobservatory.org&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Key ID:
    0CB177B7
Fingerprint:
4C15 DDA9 96C6 C0CF 48BD 3309 6B29 43F0 0CB1 77B7
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/risks/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;risks-things-you-should-know-before-using-ooniprobe&#34;&gt;Risks: Things you should know before using ooniprobe&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI&amp;rsquo;s software tests (called ooniprobe) are designed to test networks for
symptoms of censorship, surveillance and traffic manipulation and, in some
countries around the world, &lt;strong&gt;legal&lt;/strong&gt; and/or &lt;strong&gt;extra-legal risks&lt;/strong&gt; could emerge.
We therefore strongly urge you to consult with lawyers &lt;em&gt;prior&lt;/em&gt; to downloading,
installing and running ooniprobe, and to carefully read the documentation below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#legal-and-extra-legal-risks&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Legal and extra-legal risks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#detection-of-ooniprobe-usage&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Detection of ooniprobe usage&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#surveillance&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Surveillance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tested-services&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tested services&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#physical-or-remote-access-to-a-users-device&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physical or remote access to a user&amp;rsquo;s device&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#publication-of-measurements&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Publication of measurements&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ooniprobe-software-tests&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ooniprobe software tests&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#legality-of-tested-websites&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Legality of tested websites&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#legality-of-ooniprobe-tests&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Legality of ooniprobe tests&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#legality-of-anonymity-software&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Legality of anonymity software&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#legal-advice&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Legal advice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The risks described below are quite speculative. To our
knowledge, no ooniprobe user has ever faced consequences from the risks
described below. Nonetheless, we strongly encourage you to read the following
information regarding potential risks associated with the use of ooniprobe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;legal-and-extra-legal-risks&#34;&gt;Legal and extra-legal risks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The legal risks of downloading, installing and running ooniprobe can vary from
country to country, which is why we advise you to consult with local lawyers. In
extreme cases, any form of active network measurement could be illegal, or even
considered a form of espionage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many countries have a lengthy history of subjecting digital rights activists to
various forms of abuse that could make it dangerous for individuals in these
countries to run ooniprobe. The use of ooniprobe might therefore subject users
to severe civil, criminal, or extra-judicial penalties, and such sanctions can
potentially include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imprisonment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Physical assaults&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Large fines&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Receiving threats&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being placed on government watchlists&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Targeted for surveillance&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While most countries don&amp;rsquo;t have laws which specifically prohibit the use of
network measurement software, it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that the use of ooniprobe
can &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; potentially be criminalized in certain countries under other,
broader laws if, for example, its use is viewed as an illegal or anti-government
activity. ooniprobe users might also face the risk of being criminalized on the
grounds of &lt;em&gt;national security&lt;/em&gt; if the data obtained and published by running
ooniprobe is viewed as jeopardizing the country&amp;rsquo;s external or internal security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We strongly encourage you to consult with lawyers and understand legal risks
&lt;em&gt;prior&lt;/em&gt; to running ooniprobe. Some questions you can ask lawyers related to the
use of ooniprobe can include the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does country X have laws in force that restrict or prohibit the use of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;network measurement software&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;censorship detection software&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;censorship circumvention software&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does country X have laws in force that restrict or prohibit certain types
of &lt;strong&gt;internet access&lt;/strong&gt;? (for example, is it illegal to access certain
websites?)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does country X have laws in force or ISP License Agreements that require
Internet Service Providers (ISPs) to track users&amp;rsquo; online activities and to
retain such records?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have laws or rules in country X ever been used to criminalize groups or
individuals based on their internet activity? (this does not necessarily need
to be specific to network measurements)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;detection-of-ooniprobe-usage&#34;&gt;Detection of ooniprobe usage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Various legal and extra-legal risks (as explained in the previous section) might
potentially emerge if third parties (such as governments and ISPs) who view the
use of ooniprobe as an illegal or generally &amp;ldquo;suspicious&amp;rdquo; activity detect an
ooniprobe user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of ooniprobe can potentially be detected by third parties through the
following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;surveillance&#34;&gt;Surveillance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third parties (such as your government, ISP and/or employer) monitoring your
internet activity will be able to see all web traffic generated by ooniprobe,
including your IP address, and might be able to link it to you personally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many countries employ sophisticated surveillance measures that allow governments
to track individuals&amp;rsquo; online activities – even if they are using a VPN or a
proxy server to protect their privacy. In such countries, governments might be
able to identify you as an ooniprobe user regardless of what measures you take to
protect your online privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tested-services&#34;&gt;Tested services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Services connected to by ooniprobe will be able to see your IP address and might be
able to detect that you are using ooniprobe. You can view which services ooniprobe tests
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/tree/master/lists&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;physical-or-remote-access-to-a-user-s-device&#34;&gt;Physical or remote access to a user&amp;rsquo;s device&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any other software, the usage of ooniprobe can leave traces. As such,
anyone with physical or remote access to your computer might be able to see
that you have downloaded, installed or run ooniprobe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remove traces of ooniprobe usage, you can re-install your operating system or
wipe your computer and remove everything (operating system, programs and files)
from your hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;publication-of-measurements&#34;&gt;Publication of measurements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The public (including third parties who view the usage of ooniprobe as illegal or
&amp;ldquo;suspicious&amp;rdquo;) will be able to see the information collected by ooniprobe once it&amp;rsquo;s
published through:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/world/&#34;&gt;OONI Explorer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;OONI&amp;rsquo;s list of measurements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless users &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/about/data-policy/&#34;&gt;opt-out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, all
measurements that are generated through ooniprobe tests are by default sent to
OONI&amp;rsquo;s measurement collector and automatically published through the above
resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Published data will include your approximate location, the network (ASN) you are
connecting from, and when you ran ooniprobe. Other identifying information, such
as your IP address, is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; deliberately collected, but might be included in
HTTP headers or other metadata. The full page content downloaded by ooniprobe
could potentially include further information if, for example, a website
includes tracking codes or custom content based on your network location. Such
information could potentially aid third parties in detecting you as an ooniprobe
user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ooniprobe-software-tests&#34;&gt;ooniprobe software tests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI has developed multiple free software tests, each one of which is designed
to perform a different function and can therefore potentially entail different
types of legal and/or extra-legal risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, OONI&amp;rsquo;s tests are designed to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Examine whether websites are blocked&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Examine whether instant messaging (IM) apps (such as WhatsApp or Facebook Messenger) are blocked&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detect the presence of systems which might be responsible for censorship,
surveillance and traffic manipulation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Examine whether censorship circumvention tools, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://bridges.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor
bridges&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://psiphon.ca/&#34;&gt;Psiphon&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://getlantern.org/&#34;&gt;Lantern&lt;/a&gt;, are blocked&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We urge you to review the
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-spec/tree/master/test-specs&#34;&gt;specifications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
for each ooniprobe test carefully, prior to running them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;legality-of-tested-websites&#34;&gt;Legality of tested websites&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When running OONI&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/web-connectivity/&#34;&gt;web connectivity test&lt;/a&gt; you will connect to and download data from various websites
which are included in the following two lists:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/tree/master/lists&#34;&gt;Country-specific test list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
(search for your country&amp;rsquo;s test list based on its country code)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/blob/master/lists/global.csv&#34;&gt;Global test list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
(including a list of globally accessed websites)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many websites included in the above lists will likely be controversial and can
include pornography or hate speech, which might be illegal to access in your
country. We therefore recommend that you examine carefully whether you are
willing to take the risk of accessing and downloading data from such websites
through ooniprobe tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are uncertain of the potential implications of connecting to and
downloading data from the websites listed in the above lists, you can pass your
&lt;em&gt;own&lt;/em&gt; test list with the ooniprobe &lt;code&gt;-f&lt;/code&gt; command line option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;legality-of-ooniprobe-tests&#34;&gt;Legality of ooniprobe tests&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While network measurements or the use of censorship detection software might not
be illegal per se, some network tests that ooniprobe does might be against the &lt;em&gt;terms
of service of your Internet Service Provider (ISP)&lt;/em&gt; or legally questionable in
your country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/http-invalid-request-line/&#34;&gt;HTTP-invalid-request-line&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; test, for example, &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; trigger the suspicion of
your ISP when sending out-of-spec messages to an echo service. Some ooniprobe
tests are designed to connect to and download data from potentially legally
questionable websites (as mentioned in the previous section), while others
examine the reachability of instant messaging apps and circumvention tools (such
as &lt;a href=&#34;https://psiphon.ca/&#34;&gt;Psiphon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://getlantern.org/&#34;&gt;Lantern&lt;/a&gt;) which
might be illegal or viewed as controversial in some countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;legality-of-anonymity-software&#34;&gt;Legality of anonymity software&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The installation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt; software, which is
designed for online anonymity, is a &lt;em&gt;prerequisite&lt;/em&gt; for using ooniprobe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, OONI&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/vanilla-tor/&#34;&gt;Vanilla Tor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; test is designed to examine the
reachability of the Tor network, while OONI&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/tor-bridge-reachability/&#34;&gt;bridge-reachability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
test is designed to check whether &lt;a href=&#34;https://bridges.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor bridges&lt;/a&gt;
are blocked or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the following OONI tests require the installation of circumvention
software:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/psiphon/&#34;&gt;Psiphon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/lantern/&#34;&gt;Lantern&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We therefore encourage you to consult with a lawyer on the legality of anonymity
software (such as Tor, a VPN or a proxy) &lt;em&gt;prior&lt;/em&gt; to using ooniprobe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;legal-advice&#34;&gt;Legal advice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to consulting with laywers, you can also reach out to us with
specific inquiries at &lt;strong&gt;contact@openobservatory.org&lt;/strong&gt;. Please note though that we
are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; lawyers, but we might be able to seek legal advice for you or to put
you in touch with lawyers who could address your questions and/or concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some relevant resources include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/torchallenge/faq.html&#34;&gt;Tor Legal FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/issues/know-your-rights&#34;&gt;EFF Know Your Rights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The use of ooniprobe is at your &lt;em&gt;own risk&lt;/em&gt; in accordance to OONI&amp;rsquo;s software
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni- probe/blob/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;license&lt;/a&gt; and
neither the OONI project nor its parent organization, the Tor Project, can be
held liable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>