<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abouts on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title>
    <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abouts on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://ooni.torproject.org/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/data-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/data-policy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ooni-data-policy&#34;&gt;OONI Data Policy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last modified:&lt;/strong&gt; February 09, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.0.1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Data Policy discloses and explains what data the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project&lt;/a&gt; (&amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;us&amp;rdquo;,
or &amp;ldquo;our&amp;rdquo;) collects, processes, stores and publishes relating to users of its
website and its ooniprobe software (&amp;ldquo;you&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;your&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our ooniprobe software is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; designed to protect your privacy. You may face
various &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/about/risks/&#34;&gt;risks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; such as fines,
imprisonment, or other penalties for running ooniprobe. You can avoid some of
these risks by opting not to send us certain types of data when running
ooniprobe. You can find instructions on how to do so in section 2 below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reserve all rights to make future changes to this Data Policy at our sole
discretion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-website-visitors&#34;&gt;1. Website Visitors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; collect any information about visitors to our
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. We do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; use analytics, tracking
cookies, or any other tracking technologies on our website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our website access logs store only the date (up to 2 weeks), but not the time,
when you requested access to our webpages. Our website does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; log your IP
addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will notify you of any future changes to our website visitor policy through
this Data Policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-software-users&#34;&gt;2. Software Users&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-1-data-we-collect&#34;&gt;2.1. Data We Collect&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We collect different types of network measurements when you run different types
of tests. You can view the specifications about each ooniprobe test
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-spec&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and the details about the
collected network measurements on &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/world/&#34;&gt;OONI Explorer&lt;/a&gt; or through our
&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;measurements interface&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can opt out of sending us your measurements by running ooniprobe with the &lt;code&gt;-n&lt;/code&gt;
command line option. Alternatively, you can choose &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to have your
measurements uploaded through the setup settings of OONI&amp;rsquo;s web user interface or
OONI&amp;rsquo;s mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; opt out of sending us your measurements, we will collect the
following types of data when you run ooniprobe:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.1. Date and time of measurements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt; collect the time and date of measurements when you run ooniprobe.
This data helps us evaluate when network interference has occurred and to
compare such occurrences over time. &lt;strong&gt;You cannot opt-out of sending us this type
of data.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.2. Country code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, we automatically transmit your IP address to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.maxmind.com/en/home&#34;&gt;MaxMind GeoIP database&lt;/a&gt;, which identifies the country in
which you are located. We then obtain a two-letter country code from this
database and store it along with the rest of your test results. Knowing the
country from which our users are running ooniprobe allows us to locate any
network interference the software identifies to a specific country. Such
information may be useful to researchers, journalists, and advocates who aim to
discover network interference (such as censorship and traffic manipulation).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can opt out of sending us your country code by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-probe#configuring-ooniprobe&#34;&gt;editing the ooniprobe configuration&lt;/a&gt; file inside of &lt;code&gt;~/.ooni/ooniprobe.conf&lt;/code&gt;. Alternatively, you can opt
out of sending us this information through the setup settings of OONI&amp;rsquo;s web user
interface or OONI&amp;rsquo;s mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.3. Network measurements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We collect different types of network measurements when you run different types
of tests. You can view the specifications about each ooniprobe test
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-spec&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and the details about the
collected network measurements on &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/world/&#34;&gt;OONI Explorer&lt;/a&gt; or through our
&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;measurements interface&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can opt out of sending us your measurements by running ooniprobe with the &lt;code&gt;-n&lt;/code&gt;
command line option. Alternatively, you can choose &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to have your
measurements uploaded via OONI&amp;rsquo;s web user interface or OONI&amp;rsquo;s mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.4. Autonomous System Number (ASN)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, we collect your corresponding network Autonomous System Number (ASN)
when you run ooniprobe. Collecting ASNs helps our work by revealing the identity
of network providers that engage in censorship or other forms of network
interference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can opt out of sending us your network&amp;rsquo;s ASN by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-probe#configuring-ooniprobe&#34;&gt;editing the ooniprobe configuration&lt;/a&gt; file inside of  &lt;code&gt;~/.ooni/ooniprobe.conf&lt;/code&gt;. Alternatively, you can opt
out of sending us this information through the setup settings of OONI&amp;rsquo;s web user
interface or OONI&amp;rsquo;s mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.5. IP addresses and other information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; aim to collect or store your IP addresses. In face, we take measures
to remove them from our database of collected measurements to reduce the risk to
you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we &lt;strong&gt;might unintentionally&lt;/strong&gt; collect your IP addresses and other
personally-identifiable information if this data is included in the HTTP headers
or other metadata of measurements. This data might be collected if the websites
ooniprobe is testing employ tracking technologies or contain custom content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, we do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; collect your IP addresses. You can, however, opt-in to
provide your individual IP address (to enhance the accuracy of information) by
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-probe#configuring-ooniprobe&#34;&gt;editing the ooniprobe  configuration&lt;/a&gt; file inside of &lt;code&gt;~/.ooni/ooniprobe.conf&lt;/code&gt;.
Alternatively, you can opt-in to send us this information through the setup
settings of OONI&amp;rsquo;s web user interface or OONI&amp;rsquo;s mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-2-data-we-process&#34;&gt;2.2. Data We Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We process all the collected network measurements mentioned in 2.1. through our
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-pipeline&#34;&gt;data processing pipeline&lt;/a&gt;. We
try to make sense of the data and to find answers to the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which types of ooniprobe tests were run?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In which countries were those tests run?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In which networks were those tests run?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When were those tests run?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What types of network interference occurred?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In which countries did network interference occur?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In which networks did network interference occur?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When did network interference occur?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did network interference occur?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can opt out of sending us your measurements by running ooniprobe with the &lt;code&gt;-n&lt;/code&gt;
command line option. Alternatively, you can choose &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to have your
measurements uploaded through the setup settings of OONI&amp;rsquo;s web user interface or
OONI&amp;rsquo;s mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-3-data-we-store&#34;&gt;2.3. Data We Store&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, we store ALL of the data that your copy of ooniprobe sends us when
you run a test. This includes information that &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; be personally-identifying,
such as your IP address or other information contained in the HTTP headers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can opt out of sending specific types of data to our measurement collector
as described in Section 2.1. You can opt out of sending us any measurements by
running ooniprobe with the &lt;code&gt;-n&lt;/code&gt; command line option, or by choosing &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to have
your measurements uploaded through the setup settings of OONI&amp;rsquo;s web user
interface or OONI&amp;rsquo;s mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-4-data-we-publish&#34;&gt;2.4. Data We Publish&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We publish ALL of the network measurement data that we have collected and stored
to allow third parties to conduct independent studies, verify our findings, and
answer other research questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, we publish all measurement data both through our &lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;measurements interface&lt;/a&gt; and through an interactive
visualization called &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/world/&#34;&gt;OONI Explorer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-5-third-party-services&#34;&gt;2.5. Third-party services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/ndt/&#34;&gt;Network Diagnostic Test (NDT)&lt;/a&gt; is designed to measure the speed and performance of networks by connecting to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.measurementlab.net/&#34;&gt;M-Lab&lt;/a&gt; servers close to the user, and by collecting TCP/IP low level information that is useful to examining and characterizing the quality of the network path between the user and the M-Lab server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As NDT is based on third-party servers, we cannot guarantee that your IP address will not be collected, processed, and published by third-parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For questions and comments on this Data Policy, please contact:
&lt;strong&gt;contact@openobservatory.org&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Key ID:
    0CB177B7
Fingerprint:
4C15 DDA9 96C6 C0CF 48BD 3309 6B29 43F0 0CB1 77B7
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/inform-users-long/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/inform-users-long/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;goal&#34;&gt;GOAL&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI is a project aimed at mapping network anomalies by performing measurements
from the vantage point of a users.
You may find details on what exactly it is that we measure by reading through
our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-spec/tree/master/test-specs&#34;&gt;test specifications&lt;/a&gt;.
The data we collect is then made available to the public for further analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this study is to have a better understanding on how the internet
works around the world and what is stopping it from working as it should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please take a minute to go through what can be the possible implications for
running ooniprobe and make sure you properly understand them before proceeding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;legality&#34;&gt;LEGALITY&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before running OONI inside of a country with controversial internet access
related laws you should consult a lawyer. You may also reach out to us with
specific inquiries at legal@ooni.nu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some network tests that OONI does may be against the terms of service of your
ISP or legally questionable by your country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI&amp;rsquo;s http test will download data from controversial websites,
specifically targeting those which may be censored in your country.
These may include, for example, sites containing pornography or hate
speech. You can find a list of sites checked at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists&#34;&gt;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even where these sites are not blocked, it may be illegal to access
them. It may also be illegal to bypass censorship, as OONI attempts by
using Tor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the most extreme case, any form of active network measurement could be
illegal or banned, or even considered a form of espionage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some useful resources may be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/torchallenge/faq.html&#34;&gt;Tor Legal FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/issues/know-your-rights&#34;&gt;EFF Know Your Rights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;privacy&#34;&gt;PRIVACY&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI IS NOT DESIGNED TO PROTECT YOUR PRIVACY. It will reveal information
about your internet connection to the whole world. Particular groups,
such as your ISP and web services used by the ooni tests, will be able
to discover even more detailed information about you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE PUBLIC will be able to see the information collected by ooniprobe.
This will definitely include your approximate location, the network
(ASN) you are connecting from, and when you ran ooniprobe. Other
identifying information, such as your IP address, is not deliberately
collected, but may be included in HTTP headers or other metadata. The
full page content downloaded by OONI could potentially include further
information, for example if a website includes tracking codes or custom
content based on your network location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see what information OONI releases to the public at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/data/&#34;&gt;https://ooni.torproject.org/data/&lt;/a&gt;. You should expect this information
to remain online PERMANENTLY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE OONI PROJECT when running some tests against our backends will be able to
see your IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ORGANIZATIONS MONITORING YOUR INTERNET CONNECTION will be able to see
all web traffic generated by OONI, including your IP address, and will
likely be able to link it to you personally. These organizations might
include your government, your ISP, and your employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ANYBODY WITH ACCESS TO YOUR COMPUTER, now or in the future, may be able
to detect that you have installed or run ooni.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SERVICES CONNECTED TO BY OONI will be able to see your IP address, and
may be able to detect that you are using OONI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/inform-users-short/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/inform-users-short/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WARNING: Running OONI may be against the terms of service of your ISP
or legally questionable in your country.
By running OONI you will connect to web services which may be banned, and use
web censorship circumvention methods such as Tor. The OONI project will publish
data submitted by probes, possibly including your IP address or other
identifying information. In addition, your use of OONI will be clear to anybody
who has access to your computer, and to anybody who can monitor your internet
connection (such as your employer, ISP or government).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/risks/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;risks-things-you-should-know-before-using-ooniprobe&#34;&gt;Risks: Things you should know before using ooniprobe&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-probe&#34;&gt;software tests&lt;/a&gt; (called
ooniprobe) are designed to test networks for signs of censorship, surveillance
and traffic manipulation. In some countries around the world using ooniprobe may
result in criminal prosecution, fines, or even imprisonment. We therefore
strongly urge you to consult with a lawyer licensed to practice in your country
&lt;em&gt;prior&lt;/em&gt; to downloading, installing and running ooniprobe, and to carefully read
the documentation below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users run ooniprobe at their own risk. By installing ooniprobe, users agree to
comply with OONI&amp;rsquo;s software
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-%20probe/blob/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;license&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/about/data-policy&#34;&gt;Data Policy&lt;/a&gt;. Neither the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;OONI project&lt;/a&gt; nor its parent organization, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;The Tor Project&lt;/a&gt;, can be held liable, jointly or
severally, at law or at equity, to ooniprobe users and other third parties, for
any risks or damages resulting from the use of ooniprobe under any tort,
contract, or other causes of action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#potential-penalties-and-sanctions&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Potential Penalties and Sanctions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#risks-detection-of-ooniprobe&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Risks: Detection of ooniprobe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#surveillance&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Surveillance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tested-services&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tested services&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#physical-or-remote-access-to-a-users-device&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physical or remote access to a user&amp;rsquo;s device&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#publication-of-measurements&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Publication of measurements&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#risks-ooniprobe-tests&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Risks: ooniprobe tests&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#legality-of-tested-websites&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Legality of tested websites&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#legality-of-ooniprobe-tests&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Legality of ooniprobe tests&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#legality-of-anonymity-software&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Legality of anonymity software&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#third-party-services&#34;&gt;Third-party services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#seeking-legal-advice&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seeking Legal advice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The risks described below are quite speculative. To our
knowledge, no ooniprobe user has ever faced consequences from the risks
described below. Nonetheless, we strongly encourage you to read the following
information regarding potential risks associated with the use of ooniprobe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;potential-penalties-and-sanctions&#34;&gt;Potential Penalties and Sanctions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some countries, any form of active network measurement may be illegal, or
even considered a form of espionage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many governments have a lengthy history of subjecting digital rights activists to
various forms of abuse that may make it dangerous for individuals in these
countries to run ooniprobe. The use of ooniprobe may therefore subject users
to severe civil, criminal, or extra-judicial penalties. Such sanctions can
potentially include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imprisonment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Physical assaults&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Large fines&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Threats&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Placement on government watch lists&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Targeting for surveillance&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In view of these threats, we strongly encourage you to consult with a lawyer and
to understand the legal risks prior to using ooniprobe. Potential risks of using
ooniprobe are detailed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;risks-detection-of-ooniprobe&#34;&gt;Risks: Detection of ooniprobe&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certain users may face severe penalties if these users are detected by third
parties (such as governments) who view ooniprobe as a threat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of ooniprobe may be detected by third parties through the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;surveillance&#34;&gt;Surveillance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third parties (such as your government, your internet service provider, or your
employer) may be monitoring some or all of your internet activity. This may
allow them to detect the web traffic generated by your use of ooniprobe and to
link it back to you personally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many countries employ sophisticated surveillance measures that allow governments
to track individuals&amp;rsquo; online activities – even if they are using privacy-
preserving services such as Tor, Psiphon, virtual private networks (VPNs), or
proxy servers. In such countries, governments or third parties may be able to
identify you as an ooniprobe user regardless of what measures you take to
protect your online privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tested-services&#34;&gt;Tested services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The services ooniprobe connects to will be able to see your IP address and may be
able to detect that you are using ooniprobe. You can view which services ooniprobe tests
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/tree/master/lists&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;physical-or-remote-access-to-a-user-s-device&#34;&gt;Physical or remote access to a user&amp;rsquo;s device&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any other software, the usage of ooniprobe can leave traces. As such,
anyone with physical or remote access to your computer may be able to see
that you have downloaded, installed or run ooniprobe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;publication-of-measurements&#34;&gt;Publication of measurements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, all measurements generated through ooniprobe are sent to OONI&amp;rsquo;s
measurement collector and automatically published through:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/world/&#34;&gt;OONI Explorer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;OONI&amp;rsquo;s measurements interface&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, the public - including third parties who view the usage of
ooniprobe as a threat - will be able to see all user measurements, unless users
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/about/data-policy/&#34;&gt;opt out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Published data will include your approximate location, the network (ASN) you are
connecting from, and the time when you ran ooniprobe. Other identifying
information, such as your IP address, is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; deliberately collected, but may
be included in HTTP headers or other metadata. The full page content downloaded
by ooniprobe may include such information if, for example, a website includes
tracking codes or custom content based on your network location. Identifying
information could potentially aid third parties in detecting you as an ooniprobe
user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;risks-ooniprobe-tests&#34;&gt;Risks: ooniprobe tests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI has developed multiple free software tests, each one of which is designed
to perform a different function. Therefore these tests potentially entail different
types of risks to the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, ooniprobe is designed to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Examine whether websites are blocked;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Examine whether instant messaging (IM) apps (such as WhatsApp or Facebook Messenger) are blocked;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detect the presence of systems which may be responsible for censorship,
surveillance and traffic manipulation;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Examine whether censorship circumvention tools, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://bridges.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor
bridges&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://psiphon.ca/&#34;&gt;Psiphon&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://getlantern.org/&#34;&gt;Lantern&lt;/a&gt;, are blocked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We urge you to review the
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-spec/tree/master/test-specs&#34;&gt;specifications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
for each ooniprobe test carefully, prior to running them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;legality-of-tested-websites&#34;&gt;Legality of tested websites&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When running OONI&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/web-connectivity/&#34;&gt;web connectivity test&lt;/a&gt; you will connect to and download data from various websites
which are included in the following two lists:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/tree/master/lists&#34;&gt;Country-specific test list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
(search for your country&amp;rsquo;s test list based on its country code)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/blob/master/lists/global.csv&#34;&gt;Global test list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
(including a list of globally accessed websites)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many websites included in the above lists are controversial and may include
pornography or hate speech. This content may be illegal to access in your
country. In some countries, accessing illegal content has severe consequences,
such as imprisonment. We therefore recommend that you carefully examine whether
you are willing to take the risk of accessing and downloading data from such
websites through ooniprobe tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are uncertain of the potential implications of connecting to and
downloading data from the websites listed in the above lists, you can choose
which websites to test by running &lt;code&gt;ooniprobe web_connectivity -u &amp;lt;url&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;legality-of-ooniprobe-tests&#34;&gt;Legality of ooniprobe tests&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some network tests performed by ooniprobe may violate your country&amp;rsquo;s computer
misuse laws or terms of service of your internet provider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, the operators of network components affected by ooniprobe tests
may view these tests as attacks. OONI&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/http-invalid-request-line/&#34;&gt;HTTP-invalid-request-line&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; test,
for example, &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; trigger suspicion when sending out-of-spec messages to an
echo service and could be viewed as a form of &amp;ldquo;hacking&amp;rdquo;. If network components
affected by this test view these out-of-spec messages as attacks, you may face
severe consequences, such as prosecution under computer misuse laws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;legality-of-anonymity-software&#34;&gt;Legality of anonymity software&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, ooniprobe network measurements are sent to OONI&amp;rsquo;s measurement
collector through the use of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/docs/hidden-services&#34;&gt;Tor hidden services&lt;/a&gt; which are designed
for online anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, OONI&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/vanilla-tor/&#34;&gt;Vanilla Tor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; test is designed to examine the reachability of the Tor network, while
OONI&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/tor-bridge-reachability/&#34;&gt;bridge-reachability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; test is designed to check whether &lt;a href=&#34;https://bridges.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor bridges&lt;/a&gt; are blocked or not. Both tests require
the installation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Tor software&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the following OONI tests require the installation of circumvention
software:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/psiphon/&#34;&gt;Psiphon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/lantern/&#34;&gt;Lantern&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We therefore encourage you to consult with a lawyer on the legality of anonymity
software (such as Tor, a VPN or a proxy) in your country &lt;em&gt;prior&lt;/em&gt; to running the
above tests and to consider uploading your measurements via HTTPS collectors or
cloud-fronting (instead of Tor hidden services).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;third-party-services&#34;&gt;Third-party services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/nettest/ndt/&#34;&gt;Network Diagnostic Test (NDT)&lt;/a&gt; is designed to measure the speed and performance of networks by connecting to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.measurementlab.net/&#34;&gt;M-Lab&lt;/a&gt; servers close to the user, and by collecting TCP/IP low level information that is useful to examining and characterizing the quality of the network path between the user and the M-Lab server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As NDT is a third-party performance test based on third-party servers, we cannot guarantee that your IP address will not be collected, processed, and published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;seeking-legal-advice&#34;&gt;Seeking legal advice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The legal risks of downloading, installing and running ooniprobe can vary from
country to country, which is why we advise you to consult with lawyers who are
licensed to practice in your country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some questions you may want to ask your lawyers relating to the use of ooniprobe
include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does my country prohibit me from using:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;network measurement software&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;censorship detection software&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;censorship circumvention software&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;anonymity software&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is it illegal for me to access certain websites?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are there laws in my country that require Internet Service Providers (ISPs) to
track my online activity?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Has anyone in my country ever been criminalized based on their internet
activity? (This does not necessarily need to be specific to network
measurements)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note, this is not an exhaustive list of questions to ask your lawyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, while many countries do not have laws specifically prohibiting the
use of network measurement software, the use of ooniprobe may still be
criminalized in certain countries under other, broader laws. For example, using
ooniprobe may be viewed as illegal or anti-government activity. ooniprobe users
may also face the risk of being criminalized on the grounds of &lt;strong&gt;national security&lt;/strong&gt;
if the data obtained and published by running ooniprobe is viewed as
&amp;ldquo;jeopardizing&amp;rdquo; the country&amp;rsquo;s external or internal security. You may want to
consult with a lawyer about these matters as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to consulting with a lawyer, you can also reach out to us with
specific inquiries at &lt;strong&gt;contact@openobservatory.org&lt;/strong&gt;. Please note that we are
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; lawyers, and any information we give you does not constitute legal advice.
Additionally, your communication with us is not protected by any legal privilege
so law enforcement may subpoena and obtain any information you give us. However,
we may be able to put you in touch with lawyers who are capable of addressing
your questions and/or concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some relevant resources include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/torchallenge/faq.html&#34;&gt;Tor Legal FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/issues/know-your-rights&#34;&gt;EFF Know Your Rights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; These resources do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; constitute legal advice and may be out of date.
Please confirm you are reading the latest version before relying on any advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, users run ooniprobe at their own risk. By installing ooniprobe, users agree to
comply with OONI&amp;rsquo;s software
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-%20probe/blob/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;license&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/about/data-policy&#34;&gt;Data Policy&lt;/a&gt;. Neither the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;OONI project&lt;/a&gt; nor its parent organization, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;The Tor Project&lt;/a&gt;, can be held liable, jointly or
severally, at law or at equity, to ooniprobe users and other third parties, for
any risks or damages resulting from the use of ooniprobe under any tort,
contract, or other causes of action.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>