<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abouts on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title>
    <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abouts on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ooni.torproject.org/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/data-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/data-policy/</guid>
      <description>OONI Data Policy Last modified: July 17, 2017
Version: 1.1.0
This Data Policy discloses and explains what data the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project (&amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;us&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;our&amp;rdquo;) collects, processes, stores and publishes relating to users of its website and its ooniprobe software (&amp;ldquo;you&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;your&amp;rdquo;).
WARNING:
Our ooniprobe software is not designed to protect your privacy. You may face various risks such as fines, imprisonment, or other penalties for running ooniprobe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/inform-users-long/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/inform-users-long/</guid>
      <description>GOAL OONI is a project aimed at mapping network anomalies by performing measurements from the vantage point of a users. You may find details on what exactly it is that we measure by reading through our test specifications. The data we collect is then made available to the public for further analysis.
The goal of this study is to have a better understanding on how the internet works around the world and what is stopping it from working as it should.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/inform-users-short/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/inform-users-short/</guid>
      <description>WARNING: Running OONI may be against the terms of service of your ISP or legally questionable in your country. By running OONI you will connect to web services which may be banned, and use web censorship circumvention methods such as Tor. The OONI project will publish data submitted by probes, possibly including your IP address or other identifying information. In addition, your use of OONI will be clear to anybody who has access to your computer, and to anybody who can monitor your internet connection (such as your employer, ISP or government).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/about/risks/</guid>
      <description>Risks: Things you should know before using ooniprobe OONI&amp;rsquo;s software tests (called ooniprobe) are designed to test networks for signs of censorship, surveillance and traffic manipulation. In some countries around the world using ooniprobe may result in criminal prosecution, fines, or even imprisonment. We therefore strongly urge you to consult with a lawyer licensed to practice in your country prior to downloading, installing and running ooniprobe, and to carefully read the documentation below.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>