<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Get-involveds on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title>
    <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/get-involved/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Get-involveds on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ooni.torproject.org/get-involved/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/get-involved/contribute-test-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/get-involved/contribute-test-lists/</guid>
      <description>OONI tests specific websites to see if they are blocked, and such websites are included in what we call &amp;ldquo;test lists&amp;rdquo;. Each test list contains multiple categorized URLs which are tested for online censorship and they include the following:
 Global test list
 Country-specific test lists
  The global list includes a wide range of internationally relevant websites (most of which are in English), while each country-specific test list includes websites that are relevant and commonly accessed within that country (many of which are in local languages).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OONI Partnership Program</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/get-involved/partnership-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/get-involved/partnership-program/</guid>
      <description>Uncovering Evidence of Online Censorship Around the World
Hundreds of volunteers around the world have made the OONI project possible over the last years by contributing to the collection of millions of network measurements across more than 95 countries. These measurements have discovered online censorship and traffic manipulation around the world, and have brought transparency to covert surveillance through proxies and traffic monitoring.
Now we aim to take OONI a step further by studying network anomalies more systematically and within local context, through OONI&amp;rsquo;s Partnership Program.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>