<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Installs on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title>
    <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/install/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Installs on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ooni.torproject.org/install/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lepidopter Installation: Help Guides and Resources</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/install/lepidopter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/install/lepidopter/</guid>
      <description>Lepidopter guide This guide explains step-by-step how to run OONI tests from a Raspberry Pi.
The code of the image as well as the build script can be found in the git repository.
Some compact documentation on how to install, build, copy to an SD card and run Lepidopter in QEMU is described here.
About Lepidopter Lepidopter is an ooniprobe distribution for Raspberry Pis.
This enables users to contribute to the collection of network measurements consistently across time, without having to manually run ooniprobe from their computers and regardless of their technical skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ooniprobe: Installation guide</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/install/ooniprobe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/install/ooniprobe/</guid>
      <description>The Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) is a free software project under the Tor Project which aims to detect internet censorship, traffic manipulation and signs of surveillance around the world through the collection and processing of network measurements. Since late 2012, OONI has collected millions of network measurements across more than 100 countries around the world, shedding light on multiple cases of network interference.
ooniprobe is a program that users can run to probe their network and to collect data for the OONI project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>