<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hackathon on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title>
    <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/tags/hackathon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hackathon on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ooni.torproject.org/tags/hackathon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>OONI Hackathon: Join us to explore internet censorship!</title>
      <link>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/berlin-hackathon-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ooni.torproject.org/post/berlin-hackathon-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/berlin-hackathon/ooni-berlin-hackathon.png&#34; alt=&#34;HACKOONI16&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in exploring (and exposing) internet censorship? Join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI)&lt;/a&gt; hackathon in Berlin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When?&lt;/strong&gt; Friday, &lt;strong&gt;11th November&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; Saturday, &lt;strong&gt;12th November&lt;/strong&gt; 2016&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where?&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;strong&gt;OnionSpace&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openstreetmap.org/?mlat=52.54965&amp;amp;mlon=13.3700#map=19/52.54974/13.37001&#34;&gt;Gottschedstraße 4, 13357 Berlin, Germany&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What time?&lt;/strong&gt; 10am onwards&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who?&lt;/strong&gt; Software developers, data analysts, academics, journalists,
bloggers, lawyers, activists, and all those who don’t go by any
particular label, but are curious enough to join! We only have one rule:
&lt;strong&gt;Be excellent to each other&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI is a &lt;em&gt;free software&lt;/em&gt; project under The Tor Project which aims to uncover
internet censorship around the world. Since 2012, OONI has &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/world/&#34;&gt;collected&lt;/a&gt; millions of
network measurements across more than 100 countries, shedding light on multiple
cases of censorship and network interference around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But our work is far from done and we need your help! Below you can learn about
&lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of the ways that you can contribute to the fight against internet
censorship through this hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;hack-on-censorship-tests&#34;&gt;Hack on censorship tests&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OONI has multiple &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-probe/tree/master/ooni/nettests&#34;&gt;free software tests&lt;/a&gt; that you can hack on! These tests are designed to examine the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blocking of websites&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blocking of instant messaging (IM) apps&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blocking of Tor, Psiphon, Lantern, and OpenVPN&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Presence of systems that could be used for censorship or surveillance (such as BlueCoat)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us to improve OONI’s tests and/or write new ones!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;learn-how-to-run-censorship-tests&#34;&gt;Learn how to run censorship tests&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of your technical skills or background, you can &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; contribute to
transparency around internet censorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would be happy to teach you how to run tests from your terminal, your web
browser, or how to set-up a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raspberry_Pi&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; to automatically run tests for
you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-lists-of-urls-to-test-for-censorship&#34;&gt;Create lists of URLs to test for censorship&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you familiar with any blocked sites? Again, regardless of your technical
skills or background, you can play an important role!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our findings are probably only as interesting as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citizenlab/test-lists/tree/master/lists&#34;&gt;websites that we test for censorship&lt;/a&gt;. Join us
to learn about our methodology and to suggest websites that we should be
testing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;data-analysis&#34;&gt;Data analysis&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collecting all those network measurements is great, but we need to improve our
data analysis capabilities to better detect and confirm censorship events.
That’s where data analysts can play an important role! Join us to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Improve &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-pipeline&#34;&gt;OONI’s data processing pipeline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Analyze &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/world/&#34;&gt;existing measurements&lt;/a&gt;
to potentially find hidden cases of censorship&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Share data analysis methodologies and techniques&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can dig into OONI’s data through &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/world/&#34;&gt;OONI Explorer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://measurements.ooni.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;OONI’s list of measurements&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;research&#34;&gt;Research&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studying internet controls? We are sitting on millions of network measurements
that might be useful to your existing research, or which might help develop new
research questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us to learn all about OONI and how you can use its data as part of your
research!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;story-telling&#34;&gt;Story-telling&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journalists and bloggers, this is a place for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By collecting network measurements, OONI can provide you with &lt;em&gt;evidence&lt;/em&gt; of
internet censorship. This can include the blocking of various websites and
instant messaging (IM) apps (such as WhatsApp and Facebook Messenger), as well
as the blocking of circumvention tools, such as Tor. Furthermore, OONI’s data
can help uncover the covert presence of censorship and surveillance equipment (which we &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorer.ooni.torproject.org/highlights/&#34;&gt;detected&lt;/a&gt; in various countries around the world in the
past).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us to learn how to dig into OONI’s data and find evidence that you
might need for your next story!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you all soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fordfound.org/&#34;&gt;Ford Foundation&lt;/a&gt; for supporting the OONI team&amp;rsquo;s travel costs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>